<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://sixsq.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://sixsq.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-05-20T06:36:45+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">SixSq Website</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Bouquet Of Apps At The Edge</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/blog/marketplace/2024/05/15/bouquet-of-apps-at-the-edge.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bouquet Of Apps At The Edge" /><published>2024-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/blog/marketplace/2024/05/15/bouquet-of-apps-at-the-edge</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/blog/marketplace/2024/05/15/bouquet-of-apps-at-the-edge.html"><![CDATA[<p>Why settle for something less than exquisite when you’re running <a href="/blog/discover/2024/03/22/running-ai-at-the-edge.html">artificial intelligence (AI) at the edge</a>? We think you deserve a beautiful bouquet of hand-picked machine-learning (ML) apps.</p>

<h3 id="everythings-coming-up-roses">Everything’s coming up roses</h3>

<p>If a single vendor says they can provide a complete scope of ML apps, be very sceptical. Both AI in general and the ML sector specifically are moving at an incredible pace – beautiful apps are appearing every day but never just in one place.</p>

<h3 id="fastening-it-all-together">Fastening it all together</h3>

<p>What’s required is a way to bring it all together. At SixSq, we believe an ecosystem is the best way to do this, presenting you with a complete and future-proof solution.</p>

<h3 id="arranging-everything-attractively">Arranging everything attractively</h3>

<p>Our edge-to-cloud management platform, <a href="/platform">Nuvla.io</a> is designed to support app bouquets. You are free to arrange your selection in an attractive bundle, picking ML apps from our <a href="/marketplace">Nuvla.io Marketplace</a> and from third party vendors, as well as using your own.</p>

<h3 id="putting-a-smile-on-your-face">Putting a smile on your face</h3>

<p>And we’ve thought of all those little details in advance. It’s our way of making sure your IT team can minimise ML ops costs while maintaining clear <a href="https://sixsq.com/legal/legal-general-terms-and-conditions-v2.html">T&amp;Cs</a>, SLAs, support services, <a href="https://sixsq.com/pricing">pricing</a> and more.</p>

<h3 id="lets-talk-today">Let’s talk today</h3>

<p>Don’t be a stranger. We’ve got a mountain of experience to share. Let’s run AI at the edge together!</p>

<p>Get in touch.</p>]]></content><author><name>Marc-Elian Bégin</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="edge" /><category term="cloud" /><category term="marketplace" /><category term="ai" /><category term="ml" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why settle for something less than exquisite when you’re running artificial intelligence (AI) at the edge? We think you deserve a beautiful bouquet of hand-picked machine-learning (ML) apps. Everything’s coming up roses If a single vendor says they can provide a complete scope of ML apps, be very sceptical. Both AI in general and the ML sector specifically are moving at an incredible pace – beautiful apps are appearing every day but never just in one place. Fastening it all together What’s required is a way to bring it all together. At SixSq, we believe an ecosystem is the best way to do this, presenting you with a complete and future-proof solution. Arranging everything attractively Our edge-to-cloud management platform, Nuvla.io is designed to support app bouquets. You are free to arrange your selection in an attractive bundle, picking ML apps from our Nuvla.io Marketplace and from third party vendors, as well as using your own. Putting a smile on your face And we’ve thought of all those little details in advance. It’s our way of making sure your IT team can minimise ML ops costs while maintaining clear T&amp;Cs, SLAs, support services, pricing and more. Let’s talk today Don’t be a stranger. We’ve got a mountain of experience to share. Let’s run AI at the edge together! Get in touch.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/bouquet.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/bouquet.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Running AI at the edge? It’s not rocket science!</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2024/05/13/running-ai-at-the-edge.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Running AI at the edge? It’s not rocket science!" /><published>2024-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2024/05/13/running-ai-at-the-edge</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2024/05/13/running-ai-at-the-edge.html"><![CDATA[<p>Running <strong>artificial intelligence (AI)</strong> and <strong>machine learning (ML)</strong> at the edge to turn your data into actionable insights isn’t rocket science. I should know; I’ve had a hand in building rockets! But nor is it a walk in the park.</p>

<p>In this blog, I’ll share my experiences of building, deploying, and operating intelligent apps (let’s call them <strong>ML apps</strong>) at the edge – in other words, in the physical world that’s outside the data centre.</p>

<p>Just before take-off, a couple of basics. Your ML apps need a stable and secure infrastructure incorporating the near-edge or far-edge or both. They also need high-quality data which must be pre-processed to retain its rich context. And they must be easy to deploy, redeploy and operate.</p>

<h3 id="whos-on-board">Who’s on board?</h3>

<p>So, who should be on board to run your ML apps (let’s call this activity <strong>ML ops</strong>)? It’s helpful to think of three groups of people – some of whom belong to your organisation and others who are partners or provide consulting services to your organisation. They are the <strong>IT team</strong>, <strong>the data scientists</strong> and <strong>the business folk</strong>.</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p><strong>The IT team</strong>: What are these people up to? They’re working hard to provide a <strong>stable and secure edge-to-cloud infrastructure</strong>, needing full visibility of the edge especially if there are physical and/or cyber risks. If something goes wrong, these people need to know immediately.</p>

    <p>These techies like to select ML apps according to their intended purpose. If a new ML app will be critical to local business processes, the IT team picks one capable of functioning locally at the edge (it delivers business continuity). If the new ML app will be used for overall management, monitoring or trending analysis, the team picks one that can communicate with the wider world to provide an overview (it delivers business availability).</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>The data scientists</strong>: What do these people want? A <strong>massive, central warehouse of well-organised, high-quality data</strong> that’s easily queryable and downloadable. This is the liquid hydrogen essential to every rocket launch!</p>

    <p>Over the years, I’ve talked to many data scientists working in transportation (and many other industries) here on Planet Earth. They all say very similar things  <em>“90% of failing AI projects fail because of data-related issues,”</em> <em>“Data is the hardest part of machine learning and the most important to get right”</em> (Uber), and  <em>“No other activity in the machine learning lifecycle has a higher return on investment than improving the data a model has access to”</em> (Gojek).</p>

    <p>What else could knock your ML ops off-course? Data scientists insist high-quality data includes context – the “where, when and how” of its collection, also known as its metadata – information that must be packaged and stored alongside data wherever it travels.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>The business folk</strong>: These people make significant demands: they want <strong>fluid deployment and operation of ML apps</strong>. They want everything immediately and want to make changes almost daily – whatever it takes to solve business problems and remain agile in a competitive market.</p>

    <p>Needing to deploy new ML apps all the time can bring business folk into conflict with the  IT team. In most business cases, there’s not a single app vendor or creator capable of fulfilling all requirements, so the business team wants the freedom to compose its own bouquet of apps, from different sources – a risk for the IT team who are tasked with minimising ML ops costs and maintaining clear T&amp;Cs, SLAs, support services, pricing and more. This also introduces more work. Training and deploying each new ML app is not one-shot task because the physical world changes and evolves, so ML app models require regular re-training, from regularly updated data, and regular re-deployment.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<h3 id="which-launch-pad">Which launch pad?</h3>

<p>Whoever takes the decision about how to run AI at the edge, it’s important to keep in mind the varying needs of the IT team, data scientists and business folk.</p>

<p>Hyperscalers such as Amazon Web Services (AWS), Microsoft Azure and Google Cloud Platform (GCP) are attracting attention right now, so one of these might seem the right choice. But hyperscale providers have a cloud-first business model. This means they focus on selling cloud storage and compute resources and giving access to tools for data exploration as well as AI and ML model training.</p>

<p>The triumvirate rocket crew would do better with an edge-first solution. Only this puts them all in full control of their data processing chain – from data capture, crunching and training, right back to inference (aka running the model on fresh data). And only an edge-first solution can deliver the required level of maturity, control and flexibility.</p>

<h3 id="why-edge-first">Why edge-first?</h3>

<p>Thinking about the infrastructure level, edge-first allows you to adopt container technology at the edge. Your IT team will be able to re-use, re-purpose and modernise many existing infrastructures, knowledge and processes. Edge-first also allows you to operate different types and generations of assets and devices at the edge in a coherent way. You can manage them with secure and intelligent edge computing software like our hardware-agnostic, container-native NuvlaEdge software.</p>

<p>Thinking about your data needs, edge-first allows you to use an edge-to-cloud management platform, such as our B2B SaaS <a href="/platform">Nuvla.io,</a> to accelerate app deployment at the edge, reducing risk, removing management complexity and delivering full control over data. For companies operating in a regulated industry, there’s an on-premises version of Nuvla.io.</p>

<p>Once curated, the data can be pushed to your favourite backend service. For example, Nuvla.io will deliver the data to your own servers, Amazon’s, Azure’s or Google’s. We also provide this service from Switzerland. What’s important here is your data scientists get easy and safe access to their rocket fuel!</p>

<p>Thinking about ML app deployment and operation, an edge-first management platform is likely to support apps from multiple vendors and third parties. Our Nuvla.io platform certainly does, while also providing an excellent selection of ML apps and app bundles in the <a href="/marketplace">Nuvla.io Marketplace</a>. This allows your organisation to move fast while controlling risks.</p>

<h3 id="find-out-more">Find out more</h3>

<p>By reading this far, I hope you now agree running AI at the edge isn’t rocket science! There’s a lot to consider but there’s no need to journey alone. Before lift-off, please <a href="/contact">get in touch</a> to discuss your specific needs.</p>]]></content><author><name>Marc-Elian Bégin</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="edge" /><category term="ai" /><category term="machine-learning" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Running artificial intelligence (AI) and machine learning (ML) at the edge to turn your data into actionable insights isn’t rocket science. I should know; I’ve had a hand in building rockets! But nor is it a walk in the park. In this blog, I’ll share my experiences of building, deploying, and operating intelligent apps (let’s call them ML apps) at the edge – in other words, in the physical world that’s outside the data centre. Just before take-off, a couple of basics. Your ML apps need a stable and secure infrastructure incorporating the near-edge or far-edge or both. They also need high-quality data which must be pre-processed to retain its rich context. And they must be easy to deploy, redeploy and operate. Who’s on board? So, who should be on board to run your ML apps (let’s call this activity ML ops)? It’s helpful to think of three groups of people – some of whom belong to your organisation and others who are partners or provide consulting services to your organisation. They are the IT team, the data scientists and the business folk. The IT team: What are these people up to? They’re working hard to provide a stable and secure edge-to-cloud infrastructure, needing full visibility of the edge especially if there are physical and/or cyber risks. If something goes wrong, these people need to know immediately. These techies like to select ML apps according to their intended purpose. If a new ML app will be critical to local business processes, the IT team picks one capable of functioning locally at the edge (it delivers business continuity). If the new ML app will be used for overall management, monitoring or trending analysis, the team picks one that can communicate with the wider world to provide an overview (it delivers business availability). The data scientists: What do these people want? A massive, central warehouse of well-organised, high-quality data that’s easily queryable and downloadable. This is the liquid hydrogen essential to every rocket launch! Over the years, I’ve talked to many data scientists working in transportation (and many other industries) here on Planet Earth. They all say very similar things “90% of failing AI projects fail because of data-related issues,” “Data is the hardest part of machine learning and the most important to get right” (Uber), and “No other activity in the machine learning lifecycle has a higher return on investment than improving the data a model has access to” (Gojek). What else could knock your ML ops off-course? Data scientists insist high-quality data includes context – the “where, when and how” of its collection, also known as its metadata – information that must be packaged and stored alongside data wherever it travels. The business folk: These people make significant demands: they want fluid deployment and operation of ML apps. They want everything immediately and want to make changes almost daily – whatever it takes to solve business problems and remain agile in a competitive market. Needing to deploy new ML apps all the time can bring business folk into conflict with the IT team. In most business cases, there’s not a single app vendor or creator capable of fulfilling all requirements, so the business team wants the freedom to compose its own bouquet of apps, from different sources – a risk for the IT team who are tasked with minimising ML ops costs and maintaining clear T&amp;Cs, SLAs, support services, pricing and more. This also introduces more work. Training and deploying each new ML app is not one-shot task because the physical world changes and evolves, so ML app models require regular re-training, from regularly updated data, and regular re-deployment. Which launch pad? Whoever takes the decision about how to run AI at the edge, it’s important to keep in mind the varying needs of the IT team, data scientists and business folk. Hyperscalers such as Amazon Web Services (AWS), Microsoft Azure and Google Cloud Platform (GCP) are attracting attention right now, so one of these might seem the right choice. But hyperscale providers have a cloud-first business model. This means they focus on selling cloud storage and compute resources and giving access to tools for data exploration as well as AI and ML model training. The triumvirate rocket crew would do better with an edge-first solution. Only this puts them all in full control of their data processing chain – from data capture, crunching and training, right back to inference (aka running the model on fresh data). And only an edge-first solution can deliver the required level of maturity, control and flexibility. Why edge-first? Thinking about the infrastructure level, edge-first allows you to adopt container technology at the edge. Your IT team will be able to re-use, re-purpose and modernise many existing infrastructures, knowledge and processes. Edge-first also allows you to operate different types and generations of assets and devices at the edge in a coherent way. You can manage them with secure and intelligent edge computing software like our hardware-agnostic, container-native NuvlaEdge software. Thinking about your data needs, edge-first allows you to use an edge-to-cloud management platform, such as our B2B SaaS Nuvla.io, to accelerate app deployment at the edge, reducing risk, removing management complexity and delivering full control over data. For companies operating in a regulated industry, there’s an on-premises version of Nuvla.io. Once curated, the data can be pushed to your favourite backend service. For example, Nuvla.io will deliver the data to your own servers, Amazon’s, Azure’s or Google’s. We also provide this service from Switzerland. What’s important here is your data scientists get easy and safe access to their rocket fuel! Thinking about ML app deployment and operation, an edge-first management platform is likely to support apps from multiple vendors and third parties. Our Nuvla.io platform certainly does, while also providing an excellent selection of ML apps and app bundles in the Nuvla.io Marketplace. This allows your organisation to move fast while controlling risks. Find out more By reading this far, I hope you now agree running AI at the edge isn’t rocket science! There’s a lot to consider but there’s no need to journey alone. Before lift-off, please get in touch to discuss your specific needs.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/ai.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/ai.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Keysight Hawkeye Active Network Monitoring now available on SixSq’s Nuvla.io Marketplace</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/news/2024/04/18/news-keysight-hawkeye.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Keysight Hawkeye Active Network Monitoring now available on SixSq’s Nuvla.io Marketplace" /><published>2024-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/news/2024/04/18/news-keysight-hawkeye</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/news/2024/04/18/news-keysight-hawkeye.html"><![CDATA[<h4 id="sixsqs-nuvlaio-ecosystem-facilitates-the-deployment-management-and-update-of-keysights-hawkeye-active-monitoring-solution">SixSq’s Nuvla.io ecosystem facilitates the deployment, management, and update of Keysight’s Hawkeye Active Monitoring Solution</h4>

<p><strong>Geneva, April 18 2024</strong>, SixSq, an Ekinops Company, and <a href="https://www.keysight.com/us/en/home.html">Keysight Technologies</a> today announced a partnership to deliver <a href="https://www.keysight.com/us/en/products/network-visibility/hawkeye-software-suite.html">Keysight Hawkeye Active Network Monitoring Solution</a> via the Nuvla.io Marketplace. This collaboration significantly simplifies the procurement, deployment, and management of Keysight’s solution.</p>

<p>In today’s digital age, networks must operate at peak performance. If service providers wait for their network monitoring tools to detect a problem, performance issues could impact their customers and potentially damage their reputation. Telecommunications companies and enterprise businesses need tools that can simulate real-world application traffic in order to anticipate potential issues and optimize network performance.</p>

<p>The <strong>Keysight Hawkeye Active Network Monitoring Solution</strong> meets this challenge by quickly and effectively validating network performance, isolating problems, and proactively detecting issues. It does this by running scheduled verification tests on any site using wireline or wireless connections. Using a combination of hardware and software agents, Hawkeye simulates application traffic and sends key performance metrics to a central console for fast action. Measurements range from network quality to user experience, enabling network operators to improve overall uptime and detect network performance issues before they impact end users, ensuring quality of service for the enterprise.</p>

<p>SixSq’s <a href="/platform">Nuvla.io</a> is a proven B2B digital platform for industrialization and automation of containerized edge applications and device management. The Nuvla.io app vendor program gives app vendors and customers tools to interact in a seamless way, including clear pricing and contractual terms. It also provides hassle-free monetization of business applications for telcos, service providers and system integrators.</p>

<p><em>“We are excited to be part of SixSq’s Nuvla.io Marketplace providing network service providers with advanced monitoring via our Hawkeye Network Monitoring Solution. Next-generation networks demand cutting-edge performance monitoring. That’s why businesses trust Keysight Hawkeye to maintain quality of service without the headaches,”</em> said Recep Ozdag, Vice President and General Manager, Network Visibility Solutions at Keysight.</p>

<p><em>“Understanding the real performance of networks is key for many industries and verticals. With the Keysight Hawkeye solution, Nuvla.io users now have a simple way to better understand what they can expect from their network and stay ahead of the curve,”</em> said Marc-Elian Bégin, SixSq CEO and Co-founder. <em>“The solution fits perfectly into our edge computing ecosystem and can also be used with the Ekinops <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/products-services/products/compose/virtualization">virtualization</a> solutions.”</em></p>

<p>With the Keysight Hawkeye Active Network Monitoring available in the <a href="/marketplace">Nuvla.io Marketplace</a>, companies can now deploy, manage, and update their application remotely and securely. The purchasing and deployment process is fast, simple, and robust, with the app deployed at scale in a few clicks via the Nuvla.io dashboard.</p>

<p>The service is available via a pay-as-you-go subscription. You will find Keysight’s Hawkeye on the Nuvla Marketplace <a href="https://nuvla.io/ui/apps/keysight/">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[SixSq’s Nuvla.io ecosystem facilitates the deployment, management, and update of Keysight’s Hawkeye Active Monitoring Solution Geneva, April 18 2024, SixSq, an Ekinops Company, and Keysight Technologies today announced a partnership to deliver Keysight Hawkeye Active Network Monitoring Solution via the Nuvla.io Marketplace. This collaboration significantly simplifies the procurement, deployment, and management of Keysight’s solution. In today’s digital age, networks must operate at peak performance. If service providers wait for their network monitoring tools to detect a problem, performance issues could impact their customers and potentially damage their reputation. Telecommunications companies and enterprise businesses need tools that can simulate real-world application traffic in order to anticipate potential issues and optimize network performance. The Keysight Hawkeye Active Network Monitoring Solution meets this challenge by quickly and effectively validating network performance, isolating problems, and proactively detecting issues. It does this by running scheduled verification tests on any site using wireline or wireless connections. Using a combination of hardware and software agents, Hawkeye simulates application traffic and sends key performance metrics to a central console for fast action. Measurements range from network quality to user experience, enabling network operators to improve overall uptime and detect network performance issues before they impact end users, ensuring quality of service for the enterprise. SixSq’s Nuvla.io is a proven B2B digital platform for industrialization and automation of containerized edge applications and device management. The Nuvla.io app vendor program gives app vendors and customers tools to interact in a seamless way, including clear pricing and contractual terms. It also provides hassle-free monetization of business applications for telcos, service providers and system integrators. “We are excited to be part of SixSq’s Nuvla.io Marketplace providing network service providers with advanced monitoring via our Hawkeye Network Monitoring Solution. Next-generation networks demand cutting-edge performance monitoring. That’s why businesses trust Keysight Hawkeye to maintain quality of service without the headaches,” said Recep Ozdag, Vice President and General Manager, Network Visibility Solutions at Keysight. “Understanding the real performance of networks is key for many industries and verticals. With the Keysight Hawkeye solution, Nuvla.io users now have a simple way to better understand what they can expect from their network and stay ahead of the curve,” said Marc-Elian Bégin, SixSq CEO and Co-founder. “The solution fits perfectly into our edge computing ecosystem and can also be used with the Ekinops virtualization solutions.” With the Keysight Hawkeye Active Network Monitoring available in the Nuvla.io Marketplace, companies can now deploy, manage, and update their application remotely and securely. The purchasing and deployment process is fast, simple, and robust, with the app deployed at scale in a few clicks via the Nuvla.io dashboard. The service is available via a pay-as-you-go subscription. You will find Keysight’s Hawkeye on the Nuvla Marketplace here.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/app-vendor-keysight.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/app-vendor-keysight.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Enhancing AI strategies with CPE – a telco perspective</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2024/03/22/enhancing-AI-strategies-with-CPE-telco-perspective.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Enhancing AI strategies with CPE – a telco perspective" /><published>2024-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2024/03/22/enhancing-AI-strategies-with-CPE-telco-perspective</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2024/03/22/enhancing-AI-strategies-with-CPE-telco-perspective.html"><![CDATA[<p>If I tell you the internal temperature of a specific outdoor telecom cabinet has been reported as 55⁰C (131⁰F) multiple times, would that concern you? Do you think <strong>urgent intervention</strong> is required? If it’s midsummer and the cabinet is located on the French Riviera, probably not. But if these temperature readings are collected around midnight from a cabinet at the top of the Matterhorn, certainly yes!</p>

<h3 id="data-context-is-crucial">Data context is crucial</h3>

<p>The issue here is context. Fundamental to your own understanding is not just having an abundance of high-quality data (although this is essential) but also knowing the context of this data – the <strong>“where”</strong>, <strong>“when”</strong> and <strong>“how”</strong> of the information. It’s fundamental to artificial intelligence (AI) systems too. Having both high volumes and full context achieves data that is actionable and trustworthy for AI analysis.</p>

<h3 id="the-underlying-challenge">The underlying challenge</h3>

<p>There’s an underlying challenge to this. AI and machine learning (ML) training typically takes place in cloud or data center environments; this is because training makes heavy computational and storage demands. However, by the time data arrives in the cloud or data center, its context may have been lost (the AI system can’t tell its French Riviera from its Matterhorn) and typically it is too late to rebuild this context.</p>

<p>This has a negative impact on data quality and prevents effective comparison and exploitation of the data, especially over time. Fortunately, there’s now an innovative solution to this challenge.</p>

<h3 id="the-role-of-customer-premises-equipment-cpe">The role of customer-premises equipment (CPE)</h3>

<p>Today’s <strong>customer-premises equipment (CPE) can run sophisticated software</strong> to facilitate data collection, using AI/ML or traditional methods, at the edge along with highly secure data transmission to the cloud or data center for training purposes. Once trained, models can be deployed at the edge, Before transmission, performing AI/ML analyses on this local, real-time data – the network edge is the optimal place for AI/ML systems to render decisions (inference), gathering all the context that’s required.</p>

<p>Enabled by over-the-air deployment capabilities, software-enabled CPE can become a set of pivotal assets for implementing AI/ML strategies at the network edge.</p>

<h6 id="for-any-telecom-organization-seeking-ai-strategy-enhancement--particularly-for-geographically-dispersed-companies--this-represents-a-huge-opportunity-each-organization-can-use-existing-cpe-investments-and-infrastructure-to-advance-its-ai-strategy">For any telecom organization seeking AI strategy enhancement – particularly for geographically dispersed companies – this represents a huge opportunity. Each organization can use existing CPE investments and infrastructure to advance its AI strategy.</h6>

<h3 id="introducing-a-comprehensive-solution">Introducing a comprehensive solution</h3>

<p>The <a href="/platform">Nuvla.io </a> platform, developed by SixSq and a part of <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/">Ekinops</a>, offers an all-encompassing solution for managing CPE. This platform supports local data processing, enables secure data transfer and integrates data science tools, featuring:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Data lakes: Simplified management of unstructured data using cloud object storage, with a metadata catalog for easy navigation</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Data warehouses: Efficient handling of structured data through time-series databases and metadata catalogs, making data easy to use for AI training</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Edge data retrieval: Leverages standard equipment for data capture and processing, enabling both cloud storage and edge computing</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Contextual integrity: Guarantees data integrity and provenance, essential for reliable AI-driven insights</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Edge AI inference: performing AI/ML analysis at the edge, near the source of, and where decisions matter</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>To maximize flexibility and foster innovation, the Nuvla.io platform supports a diverse array of applications: open source, proprietary and custom. This ensures seamless integration into the ecosystem without the need for extensive app redevelopment.</p>

<p>Embedded in <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/products-services/products/oneaccess/ucpe">Ekinops’ next-gen CPE</a>, Nuvla.io kickstarts a robust AI/ML strategy for businesses.</p>

<h3 id="practical-application-at-the-edge">Practical application at the edge</h3>

<p>There are many ways in which CPE-powered AI strategies can enhance edge computing capabilities.</p>

<p>An important example is in telecom operations. Utilizing SNMP probes, the telecom organization can collect extensive data on <strong>CPE performance and system health</strong> and use this to train AI support agents to provide proactive customer support and optimize customer service levels. Once these virtual agents are trained and deployed on CPE, there’s no further need to transmit data to the cloud. Instead, data is analyzed locally and, only when required, the operator can receive summaries and alerts.</p>

<p>Similarly, thinking about <strong>energy management</strong>, the telecom organization can gather essential data by measuring power consumption or inferring it through temperature metrics. It can use this to devise strategies, also with and for its customers, that reduce energy usage, underlining the value of local data processing and analysis.</p>

<p>Another application is <strong>utility monitoring</strong>, using the example of electric grid monitoring. Deployment of sensors connected to CPE facilitates the regular transmission of critical data, enabling advanced strategies like anomaly detection and predictive maintenance.</p>

<h6 id="these-examples-illustrate-how-a-telecom-organization-can-benefit-directly-from-edge-ai-while-also-enabling-its-customers-to-benefit-too">These examples illustrate how a telecom organization can benefit directly from edge AI while also enabling its customers to benefit too.</h6>

<p>From structured data collection to analyzing unstructured data sourced from video and audio feeds, the possibilities are vast. With this readily accessible solution, the organization can improve product and service quality, reduce defects and malfunctions, improve energy efficiency and lower CO2 emissions, make better use of human capital and much more.</p>

<h3 id="a-final-thought">A final thought</h3>

<p>Delivering edge AI through existing CPE investments and infrastructure is a readily accessible solution for each telecom organization. <strong>With high-quality data collection and processing at the network edge, this can unlock valuable insights, streamline operations and deliver competitive advantage.</strong> Ekinops’ CPE solutions, powered by the Nuvla.io platform, provide an orchestrated data ecosystem to foster AI success at the edge of every organization.</p>

<p>This post was first published on the <a href="https://www.edgeir.com/enhancing-ai-strategies-with-cpe-a-telco-perspective-20240228">EdgeIR</a> website.</p>]]></content><author><name>Marc-Elian Bégin</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="edge" /><category term="telco" /><category term="ai" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If I tell you the internal temperature of a specific outdoor telecom cabinet has been reported as 55⁰C (131⁰F) multiple times, would that concern you? Do you think urgent intervention is required? If it’s midsummer and the cabinet is located on the French Riviera, probably not. But if these temperature readings are collected around midnight from a cabinet at the top of the Matterhorn, certainly yes! Data context is crucial The issue here is context. Fundamental to your own understanding is not just having an abundance of high-quality data (although this is essential) but also knowing the context of this data – the “where”, “when” and “how” of the information. It’s fundamental to artificial intelligence (AI) systems too. Having both high volumes and full context achieves data that is actionable and trustworthy for AI analysis. The underlying challenge There’s an underlying challenge to this. AI and machine learning (ML) training typically takes place in cloud or data center environments; this is because training makes heavy computational and storage demands. However, by the time data arrives in the cloud or data center, its context may have been lost (the AI system can’t tell its French Riviera from its Matterhorn) and typically it is too late to rebuild this context. This has a negative impact on data quality and prevents effective comparison and exploitation of the data, especially over time. Fortunately, there’s now an innovative solution to this challenge. The role of customer-premises equipment (CPE) Today’s customer-premises equipment (CPE) can run sophisticated software to facilitate data collection, using AI/ML or traditional methods, at the edge along with highly secure data transmission to the cloud or data center for training purposes. Once trained, models can be deployed at the edge, Before transmission, performing AI/ML analyses on this local, real-time data – the network edge is the optimal place for AI/ML systems to render decisions (inference), gathering all the context that’s required. Enabled by over-the-air deployment capabilities, software-enabled CPE can become a set of pivotal assets for implementing AI/ML strategies at the network edge. For any telecom organization seeking AI strategy enhancement – particularly for geographically dispersed companies – this represents a huge opportunity. Each organization can use existing CPE investments and infrastructure to advance its AI strategy. Introducing a comprehensive solution The Nuvla.io platform, developed by SixSq and a part of Ekinops, offers an all-encompassing solution for managing CPE. This platform supports local data processing, enables secure data transfer and integrates data science tools, featuring: Data lakes: Simplified management of unstructured data using cloud object storage, with a metadata catalog for easy navigation Data warehouses: Efficient handling of structured data through time-series databases and metadata catalogs, making data easy to use for AI training Edge data retrieval: Leverages standard equipment for data capture and processing, enabling both cloud storage and edge computing Contextual integrity: Guarantees data integrity and provenance, essential for reliable AI-driven insights Edge AI inference: performing AI/ML analysis at the edge, near the source of, and where decisions matter To maximize flexibility and foster innovation, the Nuvla.io platform supports a diverse array of applications: open source, proprietary and custom. This ensures seamless integration into the ecosystem without the need for extensive app redevelopment. Embedded in Ekinops’ next-gen CPE, Nuvla.io kickstarts a robust AI/ML strategy for businesses. Practical application at the edge There are many ways in which CPE-powered AI strategies can enhance edge computing capabilities. An important example is in telecom operations. Utilizing SNMP probes, the telecom organization can collect extensive data on CPE performance and system health and use this to train AI support agents to provide proactive customer support and optimize customer service levels. Once these virtual agents are trained and deployed on CPE, there’s no further need to transmit data to the cloud. Instead, data is analyzed locally and, only when required, the operator can receive summaries and alerts. Similarly, thinking about energy management, the telecom organization can gather essential data by measuring power consumption or inferring it through temperature metrics. It can use this to devise strategies, also with and for its customers, that reduce energy usage, underlining the value of local data processing and analysis. Another application is utility monitoring, using the example of electric grid monitoring. Deployment of sensors connected to CPE facilitates the regular transmission of critical data, enabling advanced strategies like anomaly detection and predictive maintenance. These examples illustrate how a telecom organization can benefit directly from edge AI while also enabling its customers to benefit too. From structured data collection to analyzing unstructured data sourced from video and audio feeds, the possibilities are vast. With this readily accessible solution, the organization can improve product and service quality, reduce defects and malfunctions, improve energy efficiency and lower CO2 emissions, make better use of human capital and much more. A final thought Delivering edge AI through existing CPE investments and infrastructure is a readily accessible solution for each telecom organization. With high-quality data collection and processing at the network edge, this can unlock valuable insights, streamline operations and deliver competitive advantage. Ekinops’ CPE solutions, powered by the Nuvla.io platform, provide an orchestrated data ecosystem to foster AI success at the edge of every organization. This post was first published on the EdgeIR website.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/telco-blog.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/telco-blog.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Empowering the Energy Sector</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2024/02/27/edge-computing-solutions-for-energy-sector.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Empowering the Energy Sector" /><published>2024-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2024/02/27/edge-computing-solutions-for-energy-sector</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2024/02/27/edge-computing-solutions-for-energy-sector.html"><![CDATA[<p>Looking at the energy landscape, a major transition towards renewable sources like solar and wind power is reshaping the industry. In the past couple of years, there has been a massive shift towards renewable energy. Renewables have been confirmed to be the <strong>cheapest form of power</strong> <sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>, with solar and wind in many countries being cheaper and more secure than fossil fuels. Despite the cost-effectiveness of these alternatives and the promises of a cleaner and more sustainable future, challenges arise due to the intermittent nature of energy production.</p>

<p>The energy sector covers a multitude of extremely broad topics that can go from resource and energy grid management to energy production, EV charging stations, national incentives, and much more. For this reason, this article will unveil some of the predominant edge computing solutions that can support utilities and energy providers, grid operators, and Point of Consumption Managers.</p>

<p>[For a more in-depth overview and support please <a href="/contact">contact us</a>].</p>

<h3 id="utilities-and-energy-providers">Utilities and Energy Providers</h3>

<p>Energy providers generate or procure energy, while utilities distribute and manage their delivery to consumers, ensuring a reliable supply of essential resources like electricity, natural gas, or water. The incorporation of edge computing technologies provides a comprehensive solution to challenges faced by utilities and energy producers. It provides <strong>real-time insights</strong>, supports adaptability to <strong>renewable energy transitions</strong>, <strong>optimizes distribution networks</strong>, enhances <strong>building energy efficiency</strong>, and efficiently manages <strong>EV charging infrastructure</strong>.</p>

<p>In the utilities and energy production domain, the adoption of edge computing addresses a spectrum of crucial needs. Firstly, it enables real-time monitoring of energy output and production processes, providing enhanced visibility and control over operations. This becomes particularly significant in the context of renewable energy sources, which often exhibit intermittent generation patterns.</p>

<p>As the energy industry undergoes a pivotal shift from fossil fuels to renewables, edge computing plays a central role in supporting this transition. It facilitates the intelligent adaptation and repurposing of machinery, fostering collaboration with machine makers to enhance the intelligence of industrial equipment. For example, gas generators can be switched to hydrogen, and edge computing can support machine makers to turn their machineries into adaptable and intelligent solutions. Edge computing can make the transformation smoother and facilitates the repurposing of existing infrastructure. 
Optimizing the distribution of energy through power grids is another critical aspect where edge computing proves to be invaluable. Improved instrumentation of the grid enables better balance, availability, and reliability. Notable use cases underscore the need for highly accurate real-time monitoring at high-power and medium exchange points, facilitating both immediate system insights and the creation of historical data for comprehensive analysis.</p>

<p>Furthermore, edge computing offers tailored solutions for monitoring and optimizing the energy efficiency of buildings. Given that a significant portion of CO2 emissions (<a href="https://www.iea.org/energy-system/buildings">30%</a>) arise from buildings, real-time monitoring, data analytics and AI at the edge can play a pivotal role in reducing environmental impact.</p>

<p>Additionally, the integration of edge computing transforms Electric Vehicle (EV) charging stations into strategic points of energy distribution for utility providers. This ensures the efficient management of energy resources, aligning the charging infrastructure with the broader energy distribution strategy.</p>

<h3 id="energy-grid-operators">Energy Grid Operators:</h3>
<p>Energy grid operators have a critical need for real-time and comprehensive monitoring of the entire distribution grid to ensure the efficiency and reliability of power supply. The deployment of sensors and smart devices at various points in the grid is made possible through edge computing, enabling continuous data collection and analysis at the source. By processing data at the edge, operators can gain instant insights into grid conditions, detect anomalies, and respond swiftly to potential issues, ultimately enhancing overall grid resilience.</p>

<p>Another significant challenge for energy grid operators is managing the intermittency of renewable energy sources such as wind and solar power. These sources introduce fluctuations in power production, leading to dynamic energy flows. Edge computing addresses this challenge by offering a proactive solution for managing these fluctuations through localized decision-making near the energy sources. In situations of excess power on the grid, edge devices can autonomously trigger the switching off of specific renewable sources, preventing overloads and grid instability. Conversely, when excess power can be stored in alternative forms, edge computing provides the intelligence to initiate the storage process efficiently.</p>

<h3 id="point-of-consumption-management">Point of Consumption Management:</h3>
<p>Point of Consumption Managers frequently face the challenge of monitoring and understanding the users’ consumption patterns. Edge computing proves to be instrumental in addressing this concern by facilitating <strong>real-time analysis of data at the edge of the network</strong>, in close proximity to the data source, using AI when appropriate. This localized processing allows for swift analysis of substantial volumes of user data without the necessity to transmit it to a centralized cloud server. The result is an expedited understanding of users’ behaviors, preferences, and trends. The capability to gain immediate insights empowers managers to make informed decisions promptly and adjust strategies in response to the evolving consumption patterns.</p>

<p>Edge computing also brings an important advantage when implementing measures to effectively influence users’ habits. By conducting data processing locally at the edge, managers can implement personalized and timely interventions aimed at encouraging specific behaviors. For instance, the calculation and communication of discounts for delayed consumption can be dynamically executed in real-time, aligning with users’ current consumption patterns. The low latency and responsiveness inherent in edge computing ensure that users receive targeted incentives or messages precisely when they are most likely to impact decision-making. This proactive approach enhances managers’ capacity to shape user habits in alignment with their business objectives.</p>

<h3 id="sovereignty-in-domestic-production">Sovereignty in Domestic Production:</h3>
<p>Energy security is a strategic objective of many countries, with the aim of avoiding excessive reliance on external markets for power procurement. Countries, entities, and even individuals can have the capacity to make their own decisions regarding consumption and distribution of energy. This is where edge computing plays an impactful role. By leveraging edge computing technologies, it is possible to strategically manage energy consumption patterns, thereby reducing the need to purchase additional power from external markets during peak periods, giving more independence to the private or public users and producers.</p>

<p>Additionally, by employing edge computing to smooth out power consumption peaks, countries enhance their energy self-sufficiency and reduce susceptibility to market fluctuations. This not only contributes to greater economic stability but also aligns with the broader goal of fostering national autonomy in managing critical resources. The integration of edge computing technologies therefore becomes a strategic imperative for nations aiming to strengthen their sovereignty and safeguard against vulnerabilities associated with energy dependencies.</p>

<p>SixSq stands at the forefront of transforming the energy sector with a comprehensive array of solutions embedded within its Nuvla.io ecosystem. Out of the many apps that SixSq provides via <a href="/platform">Nuvla.io</a>, AI EdgeLabs, Parquery, Clearblade, Kadiska, Eximprod, and CLEMAP collectively offer a multifaceted approach to addressing key challenges in the industry. Through these applications and its <a href="/nuvlaedge">NuvlaEdge</a> software, SixSq provides invaluable tools for monitoring production and consumption, capturing crucial metrics such as voltage, current, phase, and much more. The platform’s capability to create a robust data warehouse facilitates the storage of historical data, laying the foundation for <strong>AI training</strong> and <strong>predictive analytics</strong>.</p>

<p>SixSq’s commitment to security is exemplified by its option to deploy the platform and a subset of the marketplace on-premises, ensuring a high level of data security. This strategic integration of technology not only empowers organizations in real-time monitoring and consumption analysis but also paves the way for informed decision-making and sustainable practices within the dynamic landscape of the energy sector.</p>

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://www.un.org/en/climatechange/renewables-cheapest-form-power">Renewables: Cheapest form of power</a> <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Rebecca Schenato</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="edge" /><category term="energy" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking at the energy landscape, a major transition towards renewable sources like solar and wind power is reshaping the industry. In the past couple of years, there has been a massive shift towards renewable energy. Renewables have been confirmed to be the cheapest form of power 1, with solar and wind in many countries being cheaper and more secure than fossil fuels. Despite the cost-effectiveness of these alternatives and the promises of a cleaner and more sustainable future, challenges arise due to the intermittent nature of energy production. The energy sector covers a multitude of extremely broad topics that can go from resource and energy grid management to energy production, EV charging stations, national incentives, and much more. For this reason, this article will unveil some of the predominant edge computing solutions that can support utilities and energy providers, grid operators, and Point of Consumption Managers. [For a more in-depth overview and support please contact us]. Utilities and Energy Providers Energy providers generate or procure energy, while utilities distribute and manage their delivery to consumers, ensuring a reliable supply of essential resources like electricity, natural gas, or water. The incorporation of edge computing technologies provides a comprehensive solution to challenges faced by utilities and energy producers. It provides real-time insights, supports adaptability to renewable energy transitions, optimizes distribution networks, enhances building energy efficiency, and efficiently manages EV charging infrastructure. In the utilities and energy production domain, the adoption of edge computing addresses a spectrum of crucial needs. Firstly, it enables real-time monitoring of energy output and production processes, providing enhanced visibility and control over operations. This becomes particularly significant in the context of renewable energy sources, which often exhibit intermittent generation patterns. As the energy industry undergoes a pivotal shift from fossil fuels to renewables, edge computing plays a central role in supporting this transition. It facilitates the intelligent adaptation and repurposing of machinery, fostering collaboration with machine makers to enhance the intelligence of industrial equipment. For example, gas generators can be switched to hydrogen, and edge computing can support machine makers to turn their machineries into adaptable and intelligent solutions. Edge computing can make the transformation smoother and facilitates the repurposing of existing infrastructure. Optimizing the distribution of energy through power grids is another critical aspect where edge computing proves to be invaluable. Improved instrumentation of the grid enables better balance, availability, and reliability. Notable use cases underscore the need for highly accurate real-time monitoring at high-power and medium exchange points, facilitating both immediate system insights and the creation of historical data for comprehensive analysis. Furthermore, edge computing offers tailored solutions for monitoring and optimizing the energy efficiency of buildings. Given that a significant portion of CO2 emissions (30%) arise from buildings, real-time monitoring, data analytics and AI at the edge can play a pivotal role in reducing environmental impact. Additionally, the integration of edge computing transforms Electric Vehicle (EV) charging stations into strategic points of energy distribution for utility providers. This ensures the efficient management of energy resources, aligning the charging infrastructure with the broader energy distribution strategy. Energy Grid Operators: Energy grid operators have a critical need for real-time and comprehensive monitoring of the entire distribution grid to ensure the efficiency and reliability of power supply. The deployment of sensors and smart devices at various points in the grid is made possible through edge computing, enabling continuous data collection and analysis at the source. By processing data at the edge, operators can gain instant insights into grid conditions, detect anomalies, and respond swiftly to potential issues, ultimately enhancing overall grid resilience. Another significant challenge for energy grid operators is managing the intermittency of renewable energy sources such as wind and solar power. These sources introduce fluctuations in power production, leading to dynamic energy flows. Edge computing addresses this challenge by offering a proactive solution for managing these fluctuations through localized decision-making near the energy sources. In situations of excess power on the grid, edge devices can autonomously trigger the switching off of specific renewable sources, preventing overloads and grid instability. Conversely, when excess power can be stored in alternative forms, edge computing provides the intelligence to initiate the storage process efficiently. Point of Consumption Management: Point of Consumption Managers frequently face the challenge of monitoring and understanding the users’ consumption patterns. Edge computing proves to be instrumental in addressing this concern by facilitating real-time analysis of data at the edge of the network, in close proximity to the data source, using AI when appropriate. This localized processing allows for swift analysis of substantial volumes of user data without the necessity to transmit it to a centralized cloud server. The result is an expedited understanding of users’ behaviors, preferences, and trends. The capability to gain immediate insights empowers managers to make informed decisions promptly and adjust strategies in response to the evolving consumption patterns. Edge computing also brings an important advantage when implementing measures to effectively influence users’ habits. By conducting data processing locally at the edge, managers can implement personalized and timely interventions aimed at encouraging specific behaviors. For instance, the calculation and communication of discounts for delayed consumption can be dynamically executed in real-time, aligning with users’ current consumption patterns. The low latency and responsiveness inherent in edge computing ensure that users receive targeted incentives or messages precisely when they are most likely to impact decision-making. This proactive approach enhances managers’ capacity to shape user habits in alignment with their business objectives. Sovereignty in Domestic Production: Energy security is a strategic objective of many countries, with the aim of avoiding excessive reliance on external markets for power procurement. Countries, entities, and even individuals can have the capacity to make their own decisions regarding consumption and distribution of energy. This is where edge computing plays an impactful role. By leveraging edge computing technologies, it is possible to strategically manage energy consumption patterns, thereby reducing the need to purchase additional power from external markets during peak periods, giving more independence to the private or public users and producers. Additionally, by employing edge computing to smooth out power consumption peaks, countries enhance their energy self-sufficiency and reduce susceptibility to market fluctuations. This not only contributes to greater economic stability but also aligns with the broader goal of fostering national autonomy in managing critical resources. The integration of edge computing technologies therefore becomes a strategic imperative for nations aiming to strengthen their sovereignty and safeguard against vulnerabilities associated with energy dependencies. SixSq stands at the forefront of transforming the energy sector with a comprehensive array of solutions embedded within its Nuvla.io ecosystem. Out of the many apps that SixSq provides via Nuvla.io, AI EdgeLabs, Parquery, Clearblade, Kadiska, Eximprod, and CLEMAP collectively offer a multifaceted approach to addressing key challenges in the industry. Through these applications and its NuvlaEdge software, SixSq provides invaluable tools for monitoring production and consumption, capturing crucial metrics such as voltage, current, phase, and much more. The platform’s capability to create a robust data warehouse facilitates the storage of historical data, laying the foundation for AI training and predictive analytics. SixSq’s commitment to security is exemplified by its option to deploy the platform and a subset of the marketplace on-premises, ensuring a high level of data security. This strategic integration of technology not only empowers organizations in real-time monitoring and consumption analysis but also paves the way for informed decision-making and sustainable practices within the dynamic landscape of the energy sector. Renewables: Cheapest form of power &#8617;]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/industry-energy.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/industry-energy.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Nuvla.io and Kubernetes</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/blog/tech-corner/2024/01/23/nuvla-and-kubernetes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nuvla.io and Kubernetes" /><published>2024-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/blog/tech-corner/2024/01/23/nuvla-and-kubernetes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/blog/tech-corner/2024/01/23/nuvla-and-kubernetes.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="nuvlaio-now-supports-deployment-via-kubernetes">Nuvla.io now supports deployment via Kubernetes</h1>

<p>One of the <a href="/blog/discover/2022/05/03/4-ways-to-know-if-you-need-edge-computing.html">advantages of edge computing</a> is that you can collect, process and store data near its source, in factories, shops, warehouses, energy plants, in fact anywhere you need a better understanding of what is going on in your business or organisation. As is the nature of such locations, this often requires the use of small, portable and low energy devices.  As is the nature of business, we constantly expect better, faster and easier to use edge intelligence, including AI algorithms running at the edge, improved resource consumption and so on.</p>

<p>In these situations, hardware becomes the limiting factor. Small devices cannot host the increasingly resource-demanding applications required by business, so we have to look for clever software solutions.  For that reason, SixSq’s <a href="/nuvlaedge">NuvlaEdge</a> software has been container-ready and Docker-friendly since the outset. Responding to the requirements of a wide range of customers, from fields as diverse as humanitarian work, smart cities, open science and earth observation, the SixSq team is pleased to announce that NuvlaEdges can now also be deployed via the <a href="https://kubernetes.io/">Kubernetes</a> “family”. Kubernetes brings <strong>more functionality and security</strong>, improved load balancing and resilience. Applications that are defined via Kubernetes manifest files can be deployed to NuvlaEdges. All the features and flexibility of Kubernetes are utilised behind the Nuvla.io interface, making it easier for you to deploy.</p>

<p>Now we’ll dive into the details of how you can leverage this improved deployment feature. ⬇️</p>

<h2 id="installation-requirements">Installation requirements</h2>

<p>The <a href="https://docs.nuvla.io/nuvlaedge/installation/requirements/#prerequisites-when-running-on-k8s-distribution">prerequisite</a> is for a Kubernetes flavour and <a href="https://helm.sh">Helm</a> to be installed.</p>

<ul>
  <li>The <a href="https://k3s.io/">k3s</a> distribution is preferred distribution when considering memory footprint and ease of installation and configuration.</li>
  <li>Helm is used for deploying the NuvlaEdge containers.</li>
  <li>The documentation can be found <a href="https://docs.nuvla.io/nuvlaedge/installation/install-with-helm/">here</a></li>
</ul>

<h3 id="footprint">Footprint</h3>

<p>As NuvlaEdge is designed to be run in devices at the computing edge (giveaway is in the name), the resource footprint of the
underlying Container Orchestration Engine (COE) is an important consideration.
In this case we look for a full-feature Kubernetes installation.
Another consideration is the ease of installation of the COE.
Given the requirements for memory, features and installation the <a href="https://k3s.io/">k3s</a> distribution is preferred.</p>

<p>The table below follows the methodology as outlined <a href="https://www.portainer.io/blog/comparing-k0s-k3s-microk8s">here</a></p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/blog/kubernetes_coe_footprint.png" alt="image info" title="a title" /></p>

<p>As can be seen in the table, the memory footprints are very similar between the COEs.
In fact, the the total memory footprint of k3s is slightly larger than the base k8s COE.
The main factor in selecting the <a href="https://k3s.io/">k3s</a> distribution as the recommended COE for NuvlaEdge 
is the extremely easy one-line deployment and subsequent configuration steps.</p>

<h2 id="application-deployment">Application deployment</h2>

<p>In a manner similar to the Docker NuvlaEdge case, applications can be deployed to Kubernetes NuvlaEdges.
The base requirement is that the application is defined by a Kubernetes YAML manifest.
The manifest may contain multiple Kubernetes “Kinds” e.g. Deployments, Jobs, Services etc.
When an application is deployed in this fashion, the management and life-cycle on the NuvlaEdge
node is managed by the Kubernetes COE.
All the functionality of a NuvlaEdge, as in the Docker case, is available e.g.
update; clone; shutdown/restart; access to log files.</p>

<h2 id="learn-more">Learn more</h2>

<p><a href="https://youtu.be/yqly8M_l2Cs">Video</a> on how to get started with Nuvla.io</p>

<p><a href="https://sixsq.com/nuvlaedge#techspecs">NuvlaEdge tech specs</a></p>

<p><a href="https://sixsq.com/nuvlaedge#hardware">NuvlaEdge certified hardware</a></p>]]></content><author><name>John White</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="edge" /><category term="cloud" /><category term="kubernetes" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nuvla.io now supports deployment via Kubernetes One of the advantages of edge computing is that you can collect, process and store data near its source, in factories, shops, warehouses, energy plants, in fact anywhere you need a better understanding of what is going on in your business or organisation. As is the nature of such locations, this often requires the use of small, portable and low energy devices. As is the nature of business, we constantly expect better, faster and easier to use edge intelligence, including AI algorithms running at the edge, improved resource consumption and so on. In these situations, hardware becomes the limiting factor. Small devices cannot host the increasingly resource-demanding applications required by business, so we have to look for clever software solutions. For that reason, SixSq’s NuvlaEdge software has been container-ready and Docker-friendly since the outset. Responding to the requirements of a wide range of customers, from fields as diverse as humanitarian work, smart cities, open science and earth observation, the SixSq team is pleased to announce that NuvlaEdges can now also be deployed via the Kubernetes “family”. Kubernetes brings more functionality and security, improved load balancing and resilience. Applications that are defined via Kubernetes manifest files can be deployed to NuvlaEdges. All the features and flexibility of Kubernetes are utilised behind the Nuvla.io interface, making it easier for you to deploy. Now we’ll dive into the details of how you can leverage this improved deployment feature. ⬇️ Installation requirements The prerequisite is for a Kubernetes flavour and Helm to be installed. The k3s distribution is preferred distribution when considering memory footprint and ease of installation and configuration. Helm is used for deploying the NuvlaEdge containers. The documentation can be found here Footprint As NuvlaEdge is designed to be run in devices at the computing edge (giveaway is in the name), the resource footprint of the underlying Container Orchestration Engine (COE) is an important consideration. In this case we look for a full-feature Kubernetes installation. Another consideration is the ease of installation of the COE. Given the requirements for memory, features and installation the k3s distribution is preferred. The table below follows the methodology as outlined here As can be seen in the table, the memory footprints are very similar between the COEs. In fact, the the total memory footprint of k3s is slightly larger than the base k8s COE. The main factor in selecting the k3s distribution as the recommended COE for NuvlaEdge is the extremely easy one-line deployment and subsequent configuration steps. Application deployment In a manner similar to the Docker NuvlaEdge case, applications can be deployed to Kubernetes NuvlaEdges. The base requirement is that the application is defined by a Kubernetes YAML manifest. The manifest may contain multiple Kubernetes “Kinds” e.g. Deployments, Jobs, Services etc. When an application is deployed in this fashion, the management and life-cycle on the NuvlaEdge node is managed by the Kubernetes COE. All the functionality of a NuvlaEdge, as in the Docker case, is available e.g. update; clone; shutdown/restart; access to log files. Learn more Video on how to get started with Nuvla.io NuvlaEdge tech specs NuvlaEdge certified hardware]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/kubernetes-vignette.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/kubernetes-vignette.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Energy management in the 21st century</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/12/31/energy-management-in-the-21st-century.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Energy management in the 21st century" /><published>2023-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/12/31/energy-management-in-the-21st-century</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/12/31/energy-management-in-the-21st-century.html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="why-is-energy-such-a-hot-topic">Why is energy such a hot topic?</h3>

<p>The issues of energy provision and management have been at the forefront of discussions both in domestic and business settings over the last couple of years. Conflicts that impact supply coupled with increasing concern about our rapidly warming planet have made us all much more aware of how we use and source our energy. It seems, therefore, like a great idea to switch to <strong>renewable, decentralized energy</strong> sources, doesn’t it? But have you thought about how these energy supplies will be managed? The complex distribution system that ensures the lights go on when we flick the switch has been in place for decades and we need to turn it all on its head to make sure renewably-sourced energy hits our households and businesses with the same efficiency.</p>

<p>Traditional power grids date back to when Thomas Edison was a young man and are designed to supply electricity at constant voltages, driven by fossil fuel supplies.  We have had a long time to perfect the generation, transmission and distribution of electricity in this way, but now solar, wind and other renewable energy sources with their decentralized production are shaking up the model. Unless you live in the Truman Show, wind and sunlight are much more difficult to predict, which means forecasting and managing supply and demand is more challenging. On top of that, people are not only consuming electricity in different ways, with, for example, the increased usage of electric vehicles, but also potentially putting energy back into the grid via solar panels. All of this can affect the stability of power grids and mess with the way stakeholders in the system are funded. So <strong>how can we transition to cleaner energy while still ensuring that the grid infrastructure is stable, properly maintained and funded?</strong></p>

<h3 id="what-do-we-need-for-a-smarter-grid">What do we need for a smarter grid?</h3>

<p>Many elements are required to make this work, including updates to policy and regulatory frameworks, public awareness campaigns, consumer incentives and of course cutting-edge technologies. All stakeholders in the energy market will have to embrace innovative solutions to deliver the dynamic market needed to address these challenges. Decentralized microgrids, where a group of interconnected buildings form their own local energy system, will certainly play a part. Efficient microgrids will rely heavily on the latest technologies such as the Internet of Things, Artificial Intelligence and cloud and edge computing. Moreover , the liberalization of the electrical energy market will certainly lead to the emergence of new digital services in the energy sector. These services will mainly rely on the electrical energy consumption/production forecast. And here is where <strong>SWARM</strong> comes in.</p>

<h3 id="the-work-of-the-swarm-project">The work of the SWARM project</h3>

<p>The members of the SWARM consortium are focusing on the technological challenges of the above problem. The project is building a digital platform based on a “Smart Energy Management Appliance” (SEMA) which can be deployed on microgrid infrastructures. The plan is to provide new services which will allow users to become active participants, thus becoming direct beneficiaries of a liberalized energy market. The SEMA will provide not only supply and usage predictions, but also the ability to trade energy and flexibility. The project is supported by experts in the fields of energy and digitalization.</p>

<p><strong>Reimagining the grid</strong></p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/news/smartgrid.png" alt="SWARM" /></p>

<h3 id="swarm-partners">SWARM Partners</h3>

<p><strong><a href="https://www.hesge.ch/hepia/">HEPIA</a></strong> Haute école du paysage, d’ingénierie et d’architecture is one of the 6 schools of the HES-SO Geneva campus. With its four research institutes, HEPIA forms a centre of excellence in engineering and architecture. Its expertise in the domain of edge-cloud solutions and self-adaptive IoT applications is critical to the SWARM project.</p>

<p><a href="https://en.clemap.com/">CLEMAP</a> pursues the vision of a world where people, devices, buildings and industries understand their energy flows and work towards sustainable energy use. As a technology partner, the company offers solutions to system integrators, electrical installers, and industrial consumers when it comes to using energy efficiently in the market of Smart Grid, Smart Building</p>

<p><a href="https://www.groupe-e.ch/fr">Groupe E SA</a> is a leading Energy Company operating in western Switzerland. As a Grid Distribution Operator, it delivers electrical energy to over 400’000 private citizens and numerous professional customers in its service area. As grid operator, Groupe E provides the business view of its industry, helping with providing data and suggesting applications for deployment .</p>

<p><a href="https://power.recapenergy.com/en/">Recap Power</a> started in 2018 under the name Tvinn, with a vision to create solutions that contribute to a more sustainable future. Recap Power offers aggregator services, solve capacity problems and offer smart management of batteries, electric vehicle chargers and local energy production, as a service!
KTH Royal Institute of Technology is an international technical university, spanning from natural sciences to all the branches of engineering.</p>

<p>The Geneva communes of <a href="https://www.meyrin.ch/fr">Meyrin</a> and <a href="https://www.chene-bougeries.ch/accueil/">Chêne-Bougeries</a> act as microgrid infrastructure providers, working in close collaboration with the project.</p>

<p>SWARM is a Eureka <a href="https://www.eurekanetwork.org/countries/united-kingdom/eurostars/">Eurostars</a> project, co-funded by the <a href="https://www.innosuisse.ch/inno/en/home.html">Innosuisse</a> Swiss Innovation Agency and the European Union.</p>

<h4 id="learn-more">Learn more</h4>

<p><a href="https://lsds.hesge.ch/smart-and-widely-distributed-appliances-for-renewable-energy-management/">lsds.hesge.ch/smart-and-widely-distributed-appliances-for-renewable-energy-management</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Louise Merifield</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="energy" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why is energy such a hot topic? The issues of energy provision and management have been at the forefront of discussions both in domestic and business settings over the last couple of years. Conflicts that impact supply coupled with increasing concern about our rapidly warming planet have made us all much more aware of how we use and source our energy. It seems, therefore, like a great idea to switch to renewable, decentralized energy sources, doesn’t it? But have you thought about how these energy supplies will be managed? The complex distribution system that ensures the lights go on when we flick the switch has been in place for decades and we need to turn it all on its head to make sure renewably-sourced energy hits our households and businesses with the same efficiency. Traditional power grids date back to when Thomas Edison was a young man and are designed to supply electricity at constant voltages, driven by fossil fuel supplies. We have had a long time to perfect the generation, transmission and distribution of electricity in this way, but now solar, wind and other renewable energy sources with their decentralized production are shaking up the model. Unless you live in the Truman Show, wind and sunlight are much more difficult to predict, which means forecasting and managing supply and demand is more challenging. On top of that, people are not only consuming electricity in different ways, with, for example, the increased usage of electric vehicles, but also potentially putting energy back into the grid via solar panels. All of this can affect the stability of power grids and mess with the way stakeholders in the system are funded. So how can we transition to cleaner energy while still ensuring that the grid infrastructure is stable, properly maintained and funded? What do we need for a smarter grid? Many elements are required to make this work, including updates to policy and regulatory frameworks, public awareness campaigns, consumer incentives and of course cutting-edge technologies. All stakeholders in the energy market will have to embrace innovative solutions to deliver the dynamic market needed to address these challenges. Decentralized microgrids, where a group of interconnected buildings form their own local energy system, will certainly play a part. Efficient microgrids will rely heavily on the latest technologies such as the Internet of Things, Artificial Intelligence and cloud and edge computing. Moreover , the liberalization of the electrical energy market will certainly lead to the emergence of new digital services in the energy sector. These services will mainly rely on the electrical energy consumption/production forecast. And here is where SWARM comes in. The work of the SWARM project The members of the SWARM consortium are focusing on the technological challenges of the above problem. The project is building a digital platform based on a “Smart Energy Management Appliance” (SEMA) which can be deployed on microgrid infrastructures. The plan is to provide new services which will allow users to become active participants, thus becoming direct beneficiaries of a liberalized energy market. The SEMA will provide not only supply and usage predictions, but also the ability to trade energy and flexibility. The project is supported by experts in the fields of energy and digitalization. Reimagining the grid SWARM Partners HEPIA Haute école du paysage, d’ingénierie et d’architecture is one of the 6 schools of the HES-SO Geneva campus. With its four research institutes, HEPIA forms a centre of excellence in engineering and architecture. Its expertise in the domain of edge-cloud solutions and self-adaptive IoT applications is critical to the SWARM project. CLEMAP pursues the vision of a world where people, devices, buildings and industries understand their energy flows and work towards sustainable energy use. As a technology partner, the company offers solutions to system integrators, electrical installers, and industrial consumers when it comes to using energy efficiently in the market of Smart Grid, Smart Building Groupe E SA is a leading Energy Company operating in western Switzerland. As a Grid Distribution Operator, it delivers electrical energy to over 400’000 private citizens and numerous professional customers in its service area. As grid operator, Groupe E provides the business view of its industry, helping with providing data and suggesting applications for deployment . Recap Power started in 2018 under the name Tvinn, with a vision to create solutions that contribute to a more sustainable future. Recap Power offers aggregator services, solve capacity problems and offer smart management of batteries, electric vehicle chargers and local energy production, as a service! KTH Royal Institute of Technology is an international technical university, spanning from natural sciences to all the branches of engineering. The Geneva communes of Meyrin and Chêne-Bougeries act as microgrid infrastructure providers, working in close collaboration with the project. SWARM is a Eureka Eurostars project, co-funded by the Innosuisse Swiss Innovation Agency and the European Union. Learn more lsds.hesge.ch/smart-and-widely-distributed-appliances-for-renewable-energy-management]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/swarm-energy-blog.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/swarm-energy-blog.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Navigating the Waves of Change; How Edge Computing Transforms Maritime Logistics</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/12/21/how-edge-computing-transforms-maritime-logistics.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Navigating the Waves of Change; How Edge Computing Transforms Maritime Logistics" /><published>2023-12-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/12/21/how-edge-computing-transforms-maritime-logistics</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/12/21/how-edge-computing-transforms-maritime-logistics.html"><![CDATA[<p>Maritime commerce has been widely used throughout history and has grown in importance to the point where it’s now responsible for <strong>80% of the world’s trade</strong> <sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>. Over the years, the maritime industry has faced multiple challenges, but arguably none greater than today, with environmental,  cost and safety issues causing concern to operators. Edge computing is able to address these challenges and emerges as an essential innovation for maritime logistics, promising to revolutionize the way we navigate the seas.</p>

<h3 id="keeping-tabs-on-containers-and-codes">Keeping Tabs on Containers and Codes</h3>

<p>In the vast expanse of the ocean, the fear of lost containers is a significant concern. Edge computing tackles this issue by enabling advanced tracking systems that provide real-time insights into container movements. Equipped with sophisticated sensors and cameras, these systems read alphanumeric codes on containers, offering precise information about their location and contents. This not only prevents losses but also enhances supply chain visibility.</p>

<h3 id="monitoring-container-movements-in-real-time">Monitoring Container Movements in Real Time</h3>

<p>Containers in transit face various risks, from accidental falls to physical damage. Edge computing introduces continuous monitoring of containers, instantly alerting operators to potential hazards. This proactive approach ensures a swift response to prevent accidents, falls, or displacements, safeguarding both personnel and valuable cargo.</p>

<h3 id="ensuring-workers-safety">Ensuring Workers’ Safety</h3>

<p>Worker safety is a top priority in maritime operations, and edge computing plays a crucial role in ensuring compliance with safety protocols. Cameras with edge processing capabilities keep a vigilant eye, confirming that workers wear necessary safety gear, stay in designated areas, and follow safety guidelines. This not only enhances overall safety but also reduces the risk of accidents at sea.</p>

<h2 id="fire-hazard-prevention-and-management">Fire Hazard Prevention and Management</h2>

<p>Potential fire hazards pose a significant threat in the maritime industry, underscoring the need for advanced safety measures. To manage this, edge computing introduces innovative solutions linked to fire detection and smoke monitoring systems. These systems are able to provide real-time insights into potential fire risks, allowing for swift response and containment. It is in fact not only possible to detect the presence of smoke but also analyze its characteristics, aiding in early fire detection. This proactive approach to fire safety is instrumental in mitigating risks, supporting both the cargo and crew.</p>

<h2 id="tracking-mariner-movements-and-safety-zones">Tracking Mariner Movements and Safety Zones</h2>

<p>Understanding and managing movement of workers on ships is vital for safety. Edge computing facilitates the creation of safety zones, tracking personnel in real time and sending alerts if they venture into unsafe areas. This not only enhances safety protocols but also ensures swift and efficient evacuation procedures during emergencies.</p>

<h2 id="securing-shipping-content-through-weight-monitoring">Securing Shipping Content through Weight Monitoring</h2>

<p>Edge computing supports a sturdy approach to securing goods stored in containers. By monitoring container weight before embarkation and upon disembarkation, any discrepancies indicate potential tampering. This enhances security, ensuring that the merchandise remains intact throughout the journey, minimizing the risk of theft or damage during transport.</p>

<h2 id="proactive-engine-insights">Proactive Engine Insights</h2>

<p>Understanding the intricate dynamics of a ship’s engine and its surrounding subsystems is fundamental to ensuring a smooth and secure journey. Edge computing enables crews to take a proactive approach by supporting real-time monitoring and analysis of engine performance. By leveraging the power of artificial intelligence and algorithms, the engine and its associated subsystems can be protected using anomaly detection and predictive analysis. This capability can prevent failures, accidents and breakdowns, therefore enhancing overall operational efficiency, while reducing operational costs.</p>

<h2 id="towards-a-greener-horizon">Towards a Greener Horizon</h2>

<p>Beyond safety and efficiency, edge computing contributes to environmental sustainability. By preventing lost-at-sea containers and implementing efficient monitoring systems, it minimizes ocean pollution and encourages responsible maritime practices. The result is a more eco-friendly and conscientious approach to navigating the high seas.</p>

<h2 id="sixsq-and-its-impact-in-the-maritime-industry">SixSq and its Impact in the Maritime Industry</h2>

<p>SixSq stands at the forefront of positive transformation through its innovative edge computing solutions. In fact, it plays a pivotal role in enhancing the efficiency, safety, and sustainability of the maritime industry. By integrating its robust edge computing <a href="/platform">Nuvla.io</a> platform, <a href="/marketplace">marketplace</a>, and edge solution into maritime operations, SixSq facilitates seamless communication, real-time container tracking, and continuous monitoring of movements—establishing a proactive approach to safety. With a commitment to worker protection, SixSq’s solutions enforce safety compliance and contribute to creating a secure and conducive working environment.</p>

<p>As the maritime industry embraces the power of edge computing, we find ourselves at the beginning of a new technological era. The challenges that once seemed impossible to overcome are now met with innovative solutions, creating a safer, more efficient, and environmentally conscious maritime landscape. The waves of change are upon us, and with edge computing as our compass, the journey will be both transformative and promising. Supporting the maritime sector, SixSq is driving positive change, navigating the seas towards a safer, more efficient, and environmentally conscious future.</p>

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://unctad.org/publication/review-maritime-transport-2021#:~:text=Maritime%20transport%20is%20the%20backbone,higher%20for%20most%20developing%20countries.">Review of Maritime Transport</a> <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Rebecca Schenato</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="edge" /><category term="logistics" /><category term="shipping" /><category term="safety" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maritime commerce has been widely used throughout history and has grown in importance to the point where it’s now responsible for 80% of the world’s trade 1. Over the years, the maritime industry has faced multiple challenges, but arguably none greater than today, with environmental, cost and safety issues causing concern to operators. Edge computing is able to address these challenges and emerges as an essential innovation for maritime logistics, promising to revolutionize the way we navigate the seas. Keeping Tabs on Containers and Codes In the vast expanse of the ocean, the fear of lost containers is a significant concern. Edge computing tackles this issue by enabling advanced tracking systems that provide real-time insights into container movements. Equipped with sophisticated sensors and cameras, these systems read alphanumeric codes on containers, offering precise information about their location and contents. This not only prevents losses but also enhances supply chain visibility. Monitoring Container Movements in Real Time Containers in transit face various risks, from accidental falls to physical damage. Edge computing introduces continuous monitoring of containers, instantly alerting operators to potential hazards. This proactive approach ensures a swift response to prevent accidents, falls, or displacements, safeguarding both personnel and valuable cargo. Ensuring Workers’ Safety Worker safety is a top priority in maritime operations, and edge computing plays a crucial role in ensuring compliance with safety protocols. Cameras with edge processing capabilities keep a vigilant eye, confirming that workers wear necessary safety gear, stay in designated areas, and follow safety guidelines. This not only enhances overall safety but also reduces the risk of accidents at sea. Fire Hazard Prevention and Management Potential fire hazards pose a significant threat in the maritime industry, underscoring the need for advanced safety measures. To manage this, edge computing introduces innovative solutions linked to fire detection and smoke monitoring systems. These systems are able to provide real-time insights into potential fire risks, allowing for swift response and containment. It is in fact not only possible to detect the presence of smoke but also analyze its characteristics, aiding in early fire detection. This proactive approach to fire safety is instrumental in mitigating risks, supporting both the cargo and crew. Tracking Mariner Movements and Safety Zones Understanding and managing movement of workers on ships is vital for safety. Edge computing facilitates the creation of safety zones, tracking personnel in real time and sending alerts if they venture into unsafe areas. This not only enhances safety protocols but also ensures swift and efficient evacuation procedures during emergencies. Securing Shipping Content through Weight Monitoring Edge computing supports a sturdy approach to securing goods stored in containers. By monitoring container weight before embarkation and upon disembarkation, any discrepancies indicate potential tampering. This enhances security, ensuring that the merchandise remains intact throughout the journey, minimizing the risk of theft or damage during transport. Proactive Engine Insights Understanding the intricate dynamics of a ship’s engine and its surrounding subsystems is fundamental to ensuring a smooth and secure journey. Edge computing enables crews to take a proactive approach by supporting real-time monitoring and analysis of engine performance. By leveraging the power of artificial intelligence and algorithms, the engine and its associated subsystems can be protected using anomaly detection and predictive analysis. This capability can prevent failures, accidents and breakdowns, therefore enhancing overall operational efficiency, while reducing operational costs. Towards a Greener Horizon Beyond safety and efficiency, edge computing contributes to environmental sustainability. By preventing lost-at-sea containers and implementing efficient monitoring systems, it minimizes ocean pollution and encourages responsible maritime practices. The result is a more eco-friendly and conscientious approach to navigating the high seas. SixSq and its Impact in the Maritime Industry SixSq stands at the forefront of positive transformation through its innovative edge computing solutions. In fact, it plays a pivotal role in enhancing the efficiency, safety, and sustainability of the maritime industry. By integrating its robust edge computing Nuvla.io platform, marketplace, and edge solution into maritime operations, SixSq facilitates seamless communication, real-time container tracking, and continuous monitoring of movements—establishing a proactive approach to safety. With a commitment to worker protection, SixSq’s solutions enforce safety compliance and contribute to creating a secure and conducive working environment. As the maritime industry embraces the power of edge computing, we find ourselves at the beginning of a new technological era. The challenges that once seemed impossible to overcome are now met with innovative solutions, creating a safer, more efficient, and environmentally conscious maritime landscape. The waves of change are upon us, and with edge computing as our compass, the journey will be both transformative and promising. Supporting the maritime sector, SixSq is driving positive change, navigating the seas towards a safer, more efficient, and environmentally conscious future. Review of Maritime Transport &#8617;]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/maritime-blog.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/maritime-blog.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">SixSq Welcomes its Global Sales Director</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/11/20/news-sixsq-global-sales-director.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SixSq Welcomes its Global Sales Director" /><published>2023-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/news/2023/11/20/news-sixsq-global-sales-director</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/11/20/news-sixsq-global-sales-director.html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="damien-defer-joins-the-team-as-global-sales-director-for-sixsq">Damien Defer joins the team as Global Sales Director for SixSq</h3>

<p><strong>Geneva, 20th November 2023</strong> - It is with great pleasure that SixSq, an Ekinops company, can announce that <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/damien-defer-2784905/">Damien Defer</a> has been appointed to fill the new position of <strong>Global Sales Director</strong>. Damien joined the team on 20th November 2023 and is located in Paris, France. He will be responsible for leading the sales organisation globally.</p>

<p>Damien has extensive experience in sales and strategic business development as well as an international perspective. He brings over 15 year’s knowledge of the IT industry and an impressive track record, both in Europe and North America, placing him in an excellent position to drive growth for the company and provide a high-quality service to our global customers.</p>

<p>Commenting on his appointment, Damien said, <em>“I’m delighted to join the SixSq team and the <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/">Ekinops</a> family at the same time. The <a href="/platform">Nuvla.io</a> solution is generating a lot of interest across both enterprises and communication service providers (CSP). Our unique Application Marketplace helps end-customers to click and deploy public or private apps, across thousands of sites, on devices managed by them or by CSPs. The solution provides seamless container management between the sites, datacentres and Clouds.”</em></p>

<p>SixSq CEO, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mebster/">Marc-Elian Bégin</a> said, <em>“Damien brings not only a wealth of experience, but also the right mindset for our fast-moving sector of edge computing. I’m really looking forward to working with Damien to strengthen our sales, and partnerships, in order to accelerate our growth.”</em></p>

<p>With this addition to the sales team, SixSq shows it commitment to meeting the growing demand for software services in the edge computing space.</p>

<h4 id="contact">Contact</h4>

<p><strong>Damien Defer</strong>
 <br />
SixSq Global Sales Director
 <br />
damien.defer@sixsq.com
 <br />
+33 6 89 9948 52</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Damien Defer joins the team as Global Sales Director for SixSq Geneva, 20th November 2023 - It is with great pleasure that SixSq, an Ekinops company, can announce that Damien Defer has been appointed to fill the new position of Global Sales Director. Damien joined the team on 20th November 2023 and is located in Paris, France. He will be responsible for leading the sales organisation globally. Damien has extensive experience in sales and strategic business development as well as an international perspective. He brings over 15 year’s knowledge of the IT industry and an impressive track record, both in Europe and North America, placing him in an excellent position to drive growth for the company and provide a high-quality service to our global customers. Commenting on his appointment, Damien said, “I’m delighted to join the SixSq team and the Ekinops family at the same time. The Nuvla.io solution is generating a lot of interest across both enterprises and communication service providers (CSP). Our unique Application Marketplace helps end-customers to click and deploy public or private apps, across thousands of sites, on devices managed by them or by CSPs. The solution provides seamless container management between the sites, datacentres and Clouds.” SixSq CEO, Marc-Elian Bégin said, “Damien brings not only a wealth of experience, but also the right mindset for our fast-moving sector of edge computing. I’m really looking forward to working with Damien to strengthen our sales, and partnerships, in order to accelerate our growth.” With this addition to the sales team, SixSq shows it commitment to meeting the growing demand for software services in the edge computing space. Contact Damien Defer SixSq Global Sales Director damien.defer@sixsq.com +33 6 89 9948 52]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/news-damien.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/news-damien.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Leveraging Edge Computing for Enhanced Transportation Services</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/11/17/leveraging-edge-computing-for-enhanced-transportation-services.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Leveraging Edge Computing for Enhanced Transportation Services" /><published>2023-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/11/17/leveraging-edge-computing-for-enhanced-transportation-services</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/11/17/leveraging-edge-computing-for-enhanced-transportation-services.html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>The transportation industry is in a constant state of evolution, compelled by the ever-increasing need for efficiency, safety, and passenger satisfaction.</strong></p>

<p>Like many people-centric industries, transportation is facing challenges due to rising costs, staff shortages and evolving passenger demands. The drive to improve safety, traveller satisfaction, and operational efficiency are elements that push transport providers to find new ways to improve their services and offerings. The key to success in this dynamic field lies in harnessing revolutionizing technologies such as <a href="/blog/discover/2019/11/08/what-is-edge-computing">edge computing</a>, an innovative yet proven technology that optimises data processing, to provide efficient, safe, and attractive services.</p>

<h3 id="understanding-the-transportation-landscape">Understanding the Transportation Landscape</h3>

<p>To appreciate the benefits of edge computing in transportation, it is essential to grasp the multifaceted nature of the industry. The transportation network is of course not only about vehicles, but also a multitude of other elements such as stops, tram and train lines, ticket machines, traffic signals, all of which serve as critical points in the transportation business.  Thanks to edge computing, all of these key areas can be equipped with sensors, data processing capabilities and connectivity, thereby providing actionable insights to improve communication, security and passenger services. A sudden problem can cause delays throughout the network and quickly become costly. Edge computing can highlight the problem right away, limiting any damage.</p>

<p>Furthermore, in this intricate landscape, it is fundamental not to forget stakeholders’ needs. To understand this better, we will look in more detail at the main stakeholders in this industry.</p>

<h4 id="passengers">Passengers:</h4>
<p>Modern travellers are looking for a more complete and tailored experience, and not just a means of transport from point A to point B. Passengers usually carry a smartphone in their pocket and expect access to features like real-time updates on routes, schedules, and disruptions, to ensure their journey is as smooth as possible. Getting timely notifications about specific events or issues during their ride allows passengers to stay informed and secure throughout their journey, ensuring them a more comfortable ride. 
For an even more enjoyable experience, passengers appreciate on-board entertainment that can be seamlessly provided during transits.</p>

<p>Another aspect that is valued by passengers and which improves their journey experience is the convenience of digital ticketing solutions, which simplify the process of buying and using tickets.</p>

<h4 id="drivers">Drivers:</h4>
<p>Drivers’ primary responsibility is safety, while ensuring a punctual service. This requires them to have easy cockpit access to consolidated dashboards and alerts, allowing fast examination of key metrics needed for optimal driving. 
For safety reasons, drivers require data presented in a format that is easy to understand, and that does not distract them from their main driving activity. This is why prompt notifications about critical events, affecting both passengers and crew, are fundamental features. For this support to work, it is important to have high quality data to feed into the system.</p>

<h4 id="service-providers-and-operators">Service providers and operators:</h4>
<p>Transportation service providers and vehicle operators need data to optimise operations, manage resources, and ensure passengers’ well-being. This includes vehicle location, performance, passenger volumes, punctuality, embark/disembark timings, issue detection, and risk assessment. This data enhances service reliability, informs planning, and improves passenger safety. Companies like <a href="https://www.tpg.ch/">tpg</a> in Geneva are already leveraging data gathered by sensors along the network via their <a href="https://opendata.tpg.ch/pages/accueil/">Open Data Portal</a>.  This wealth of published data provides transparency to users and informs the operator’s decision making.</p>

<p>Exceptional event detection and real-time notifications are crucial for an effective response. However, protecting confidential data from hacking is essential, and this is why implementing cybersecurity measures is of fundamental importance, as is respecting data privacy laws.</p>

<p>Enhancing the IT infrastructure behind public transportation to deliver more efficient and safe services is a big challenge. <a href="/platform">Nuvla.io</a>, the innovative infrastructure of SixSq, an Ekinops company, reduces complexity and can be implemented alongside existing systems to respond to needs of the transport landscape and stakeholders alike.</p>

<h3 id="a-comprehensive-suite-of-edge-applications">A Comprehensive Suite of Edge Applications</h3>
<p>Nuvla.io provides a <a href="/marketplace">marketplace</a>, offering a diverse suite of containerised edge applications that seamlessly integrate into the transportation ecosystem. These applications can be packaged as tailored bouquets of apps, catering to a wide range of needs. These apps can be selected from the marketplace, but also from the customers own portfolio of apps, or third party. Here is an example of a bouquet of apps:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Publicity and Media: Engaging passengers with relevant content and advertisements, enhancing the travel experience.</li>
  <li>Video Analytics: Enhancing security and providing valuable insights for both safety and operational efficiency, while respecting privacy.</li>
  <li>Accounting: Streamlining financial processes and ensuring transparent financial management.</li>
  <li>Statistics (GDPR Compliant): Providing key and actionable metrics on vehicle and passenger statistics, behavior, and patterns, while protecting data privacy, a critical consideration in today’s digital age.</li>
  <li>Data Fusion (at Cockpit level): Providing consolidated information for drivers, allowing for more informed decision-making.</li>
  <li>Cybersecurity: Delivering sustained protection systems against cyberattacks while protecting the network and data from theft, damage, or unauthorized access, safeguarding digital assets.</li>
</ul>

<p>Nuvla.io’s portfolio includes solutions like <a href="https://parquery.com/">Parquery</a> for GDPR video analytics, <a href="https://kadiska.com/">Kadiska</a> for digital experience monitoring, <a href="https://edgelabs.ai/">AI EdgeLabs</a> for cyber defense, and private apps for ticket distribution and media publicity, among others. We are also working with partners such as Spinetix for data fusion and display. This versatile ecosystem empowers transportation companies to tailor their offerings to meet their specific requirements.</p>

<p>Nuvla.io is spearheading innovation in the transportation industry with its edge computing solutions. By meeting the diverse needs of passengers, drivers, and operators, and by addressing industry challenges, these solutions are poised to transform the transportation sector. With a bouquet of versatile applications and a robust infrastructure, the future of transportation is not just efficient, it is smart, secure, and passenger-centric. Finally, transport companies can integrate Nuvla.io simply and efficiently, without risk, in order to generate incremental value, while saving costs.</p>]]></content><author><name>Rebecca Schenato</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="edge" /><category term="transport" /><category term="public-transport" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The transportation industry is in a constant state of evolution, compelled by the ever-increasing need for efficiency, safety, and passenger satisfaction. Like many people-centric industries, transportation is facing challenges due to rising costs, staff shortages and evolving passenger demands. The drive to improve safety, traveller satisfaction, and operational efficiency are elements that push transport providers to find new ways to improve their services and offerings. The key to success in this dynamic field lies in harnessing revolutionizing technologies such as edge computing, an innovative yet proven technology that optimises data processing, to provide efficient, safe, and attractive services. Understanding the Transportation Landscape To appreciate the benefits of edge computing in transportation, it is essential to grasp the multifaceted nature of the industry. The transportation network is of course not only about vehicles, but also a multitude of other elements such as stops, tram and train lines, ticket machines, traffic signals, all of which serve as critical points in the transportation business. Thanks to edge computing, all of these key areas can be equipped with sensors, data processing capabilities and connectivity, thereby providing actionable insights to improve communication, security and passenger services. A sudden problem can cause delays throughout the network and quickly become costly. Edge computing can highlight the problem right away, limiting any damage. Furthermore, in this intricate landscape, it is fundamental not to forget stakeholders’ needs. To understand this better, we will look in more detail at the main stakeholders in this industry. Passengers: Modern travellers are looking for a more complete and tailored experience, and not just a means of transport from point A to point B. Passengers usually carry a smartphone in their pocket and expect access to features like real-time updates on routes, schedules, and disruptions, to ensure their journey is as smooth as possible. Getting timely notifications about specific events or issues during their ride allows passengers to stay informed and secure throughout their journey, ensuring them a more comfortable ride. For an even more enjoyable experience, passengers appreciate on-board entertainment that can be seamlessly provided during transits. Another aspect that is valued by passengers and which improves their journey experience is the convenience of digital ticketing solutions, which simplify the process of buying and using tickets. Drivers: Drivers’ primary responsibility is safety, while ensuring a punctual service. This requires them to have easy cockpit access to consolidated dashboards and alerts, allowing fast examination of key metrics needed for optimal driving. For safety reasons, drivers require data presented in a format that is easy to understand, and that does not distract them from their main driving activity. This is why prompt notifications about critical events, affecting both passengers and crew, are fundamental features. For this support to work, it is important to have high quality data to feed into the system. Service providers and operators: Transportation service providers and vehicle operators need data to optimise operations, manage resources, and ensure passengers’ well-being. This includes vehicle location, performance, passenger volumes, punctuality, embark/disembark timings, issue detection, and risk assessment. This data enhances service reliability, informs planning, and improves passenger safety. Companies like tpg in Geneva are already leveraging data gathered by sensors along the network via their Open Data Portal. This wealth of published data provides transparency to users and informs the operator’s decision making. Exceptional event detection and real-time notifications are crucial for an effective response. However, protecting confidential data from hacking is essential, and this is why implementing cybersecurity measures is of fundamental importance, as is respecting data privacy laws. Enhancing the IT infrastructure behind public transportation to deliver more efficient and safe services is a big challenge. Nuvla.io, the innovative infrastructure of SixSq, an Ekinops company, reduces complexity and can be implemented alongside existing systems to respond to needs of the transport landscape and stakeholders alike. A Comprehensive Suite of Edge Applications Nuvla.io provides a marketplace, offering a diverse suite of containerised edge applications that seamlessly integrate into the transportation ecosystem. These applications can be packaged as tailored bouquets of apps, catering to a wide range of needs. These apps can be selected from the marketplace, but also from the customers own portfolio of apps, or third party. Here is an example of a bouquet of apps: Publicity and Media: Engaging passengers with relevant content and advertisements, enhancing the travel experience. Video Analytics: Enhancing security and providing valuable insights for both safety and operational efficiency, while respecting privacy. Accounting: Streamlining financial processes and ensuring transparent financial management. Statistics (GDPR Compliant): Providing key and actionable metrics on vehicle and passenger statistics, behavior, and patterns, while protecting data privacy, a critical consideration in today’s digital age. Data Fusion (at Cockpit level): Providing consolidated information for drivers, allowing for more informed decision-making. Cybersecurity: Delivering sustained protection systems against cyberattacks while protecting the network and data from theft, damage, or unauthorized access, safeguarding digital assets. Nuvla.io’s portfolio includes solutions like Parquery for GDPR video analytics, Kadiska for digital experience monitoring, AI EdgeLabs for cyber defense, and private apps for ticket distribution and media publicity, among others. We are also working with partners such as Spinetix for data fusion and display. This versatile ecosystem empowers transportation companies to tailor their offerings to meet their specific requirements. Nuvla.io is spearheading innovation in the transportation industry with its edge computing solutions. By meeting the diverse needs of passengers, drivers, and operators, and by addressing industry challenges, these solutions are poised to transform the transportation sector. With a bouquet of versatile applications and a robust infrastructure, the future of transportation is not just efficient, it is smart, secure, and passenger-centric. Finally, transport companies can integrate Nuvla.io simply and efficiently, without risk, in order to generate incremental value, while saving costs.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/transport-blog.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/transport-blog.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>