<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://sixsq.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://sixsq.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-08-29T07:31:02+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">SixSq Website</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Redefining logistics and shipping with edge computing</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/08/23/redefining-logistics-and-shipping-with-edge-computing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Redefining logistics and shipping with edge computing" /><published>2023-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/08/23/redefining-logistics-and-shipping-with-edge-computing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/08/23/redefining-logistics-and-shipping-with-edge-computing.html"><![CDATA[<p>The efficient management of logistics and shipping operations relies on the smooth coordination of multiple tasks, including warehouse operations, product &amp; parcel tracking, and workplace safety, all in a dynamic environment. To achieve these goals, logistics and shipping centers can leverage the power of <strong><a href="/blog/discover/2019/11/08/what-is-edge-computing">edge computing</a></strong>, an innovative technology that optimizes data processing and provides a safer workplace while respecting workers’ privacy and anonymity.</p>

<h3 id="real-time-tracking-and-monitoring-for-enhanced-safety">Real-time tracking and monitoring for enhanced safety</h3>

<p>In any complex working environment, the safety of workers is of fundamental importance. By deploying edge devices and sensors in strategic locations throughout the workplace, warehouses and centers can process data on worker movements, safety compliance, environmental conditions, risky behavior, and potential hazards in <strong>real-time</strong>.</p>

<p>With edge computing, this data can be processed close to the action, reducing latency and minimizing the reliance on cloud or centralized servers. By utilizing advanced analytics and machine learning algorithms at the edge, safety issues, such as collisions, falls, or hazardous maneuvers, can be identified and frontline workers alerted in real-time. This proactive approach to safety can mitigate accidents, ensuring the well-being of workers. Meanwhile, it is of essential importance not to use these tools to discriminate against workers. This is why data anonymization is a key element of this type of solution. The aim is to spot, understand and correct potential issues, while protecting workers’ privacy.</p>

<p>In addition, this data can later be retrieved and analyzed. This helps, for example, to determine the root cause of accidents and inform future workplace planning.</p>

<h3 id="efficient-asset-tracking-for-process-optimization">Efficient asset tracking for process optimization</h3>

<p>Effective asset tracking is vital to maintaining the smooth flow of goods within logistics and shipping centers. By equipping centers with edge computing devices connected to camera sensors, it is possible to:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Efficiently track unique assets, using label character recognition, across zones</strong>.</li>
  <li><strong>Count and categorize assets within defined zones</strong>.</li>
  <li><strong>Identify and count trolleys and carts</strong>.</li>
  <li><strong>Distinguish between loaded and unloaded assets (e.g. empty or loaded containers or trolleys)</strong>.</li>
</ul>

<p>Edge devices do this by communicating with nearby sensors, such as standard cameras, to provide accurate information on the asset’s position, location, status, load charge, and much more. This data is gathered regardless of the lighting or weather conditions, both during day and night, and for both stationery and mobile assets. This information can then be used to interface with inventory systems and streamline logistics operations. Managers can then quickly identify the whereabouts of assets, ensuring efficient product flow, reducing search time, and minimizing disruptions to the supply chain.</p>

<h3 id="maintaining-privacy-and-anonymity">Maintaining privacy and anonymity</h3>

<p>While harnessing technology to optimize logistics operations, it is essential to address concerns related to data privacy and identity of individuals. Edge computing offers a decentralized approach that ensures the protection of sensitive information, such as personal data and worker identity.
By processing data at the edge, logistics and shipping centers can eliminate the transmission of personal information to the cloud or centralized servers. This can be efficiently implemented using established techniques such as tokenization. This works by replacing personally identifiable information (PII) with unique tokens, so that the operations remain efficient while maintaining anonymous identity of workers.</p>

<p>In conclusion, edge computing emerges as a game-changer in revolutionizing the logistics and shipping industry, by ensuring worker safety, efficient asset tracking, and anonymous identity. Real-time tracking and monitoring systems powered by edge computing protect warehouse workers by proactively identifying safety risks. Efficient asset tracking enhances logistics operations, minimizing delays and disruptions.</p>

<p>At the same time, edge computing addresses privacy concerns by processing data locally, employing privacy-preserving techniques, and enabling anonymous identity management. By striking a balance between operational efficiency and data protection, logistics and shipping organizations can build trust with workers and comply with privacy regulations.</p>

<p>In many cases, these practices require technical knowledge, training, and specialized personnel able to run such a digital ecosystem. Nuvla.io from SixSq was created for you not to worry about all this. Nuvla.io is a gateway to a world of tailored apps, in a unique edge-first <a href="/marketplace">marketplace</a> that serves a multitude of industries and sectors. All backed by a team of edge experts. We dedicate our efforts to providing a simple interface and enjoyable user experience, which allows anyone to operate otherwise complex edge computing systems, and at the same time avoid technology lock-in.</p>

<p>To deep dive into more tangible elements linked to your needs, visit our webpage <a href="/home">sixsq.com</a> and reach out to learn how we can support your logistics and shipping transition with innovative problem solving via edge computing.</p>]]></content><author><name>Rebecca Schenato</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="edge" /><category term="logistics" /><category term="shipping" /><category term="anonymity" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The efficient management of logistics and shipping operations relies on the smooth coordination of multiple tasks, including warehouse operations, product &amp; parcel tracking, and workplace safety, all in a dynamic environment. To achieve these goals, logistics and shipping centers can leverage the power of edge computing, an innovative technology that optimizes data processing and provides a safer workplace while respecting workers’ privacy and anonymity. Real-time tracking and monitoring for enhanced safety In any complex working environment, the safety of workers is of fundamental importance. By deploying edge devices and sensors in strategic locations throughout the workplace, warehouses and centers can process data on worker movements, safety compliance, environmental conditions, risky behavior, and potential hazards in real-time. With edge computing, this data can be processed close to the action, reducing latency and minimizing the reliance on cloud or centralized servers. By utilizing advanced analytics and machine learning algorithms at the edge, safety issues, such as collisions, falls, or hazardous maneuvers, can be identified and frontline workers alerted in real-time. This proactive approach to safety can mitigate accidents, ensuring the well-being of workers. Meanwhile, it is of essential importance not to use these tools to discriminate against workers. This is why data anonymization is a key element of this type of solution. The aim is to spot, understand and correct potential issues, while protecting workers’ privacy. In addition, this data can later be retrieved and analyzed. This helps, for example, to determine the root cause of accidents and inform future workplace planning. Efficient asset tracking for process optimization Effective asset tracking is vital to maintaining the smooth flow of goods within logistics and shipping centers. By equipping centers with edge computing devices connected to camera sensors, it is possible to: Efficiently track unique assets, using label character recognition, across zones. Count and categorize assets within defined zones. Identify and count trolleys and carts. Distinguish between loaded and unloaded assets (e.g. empty or loaded containers or trolleys). Edge devices do this by communicating with nearby sensors, such as standard cameras, to provide accurate information on the asset’s position, location, status, load charge, and much more. This data is gathered regardless of the lighting or weather conditions, both during day and night, and for both stationery and mobile assets. This information can then be used to interface with inventory systems and streamline logistics operations. Managers can then quickly identify the whereabouts of assets, ensuring efficient product flow, reducing search time, and minimizing disruptions to the supply chain. Maintaining privacy and anonymity While harnessing technology to optimize logistics operations, it is essential to address concerns related to data privacy and identity of individuals. Edge computing offers a decentralized approach that ensures the protection of sensitive information, such as personal data and worker identity. By processing data at the edge, logistics and shipping centers can eliminate the transmission of personal information to the cloud or centralized servers. This can be efficiently implemented using established techniques such as tokenization. This works by replacing personally identifiable information (PII) with unique tokens, so that the operations remain efficient while maintaining anonymous identity of workers. In conclusion, edge computing emerges as a game-changer in revolutionizing the logistics and shipping industry, by ensuring worker safety, efficient asset tracking, and anonymous identity. Real-time tracking and monitoring systems powered by edge computing protect warehouse workers by proactively identifying safety risks. Efficient asset tracking enhances logistics operations, minimizing delays and disruptions. At the same time, edge computing addresses privacy concerns by processing data locally, employing privacy-preserving techniques, and enabling anonymous identity management. By striking a balance between operational efficiency and data protection, logistics and shipping organizations can build trust with workers and comply with privacy regulations. In many cases, these practices require technical knowledge, training, and specialized personnel able to run such a digital ecosystem. Nuvla.io from SixSq was created for you not to worry about all this. Nuvla.io is a gateway to a world of tailored apps, in a unique edge-first marketplace that serves a multitude of industries and sectors. All backed by a team of edge experts. We dedicate our efforts to providing a simple interface and enjoyable user experience, which allows anyone to operate otherwise complex edge computing systems, and at the same time avoid technology lock-in. To deep dive into more tangible elements linked to your needs, visit our webpage sixsq.com and reach out to learn how we can support your logistics and shipping transition with innovative problem solving via edge computing.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/logistics-blog.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/logistics-blog.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">4 ways edge computing can help you achieve sustainable development goals</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/07/19/edge-computing-and-sustainable-development-goals.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="4 ways edge computing can help you achieve sustainable development goals" /><published>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/07/19/edge-computing-and-sustainable-development-goals</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/07/19/edge-computing-and-sustainable-development-goals.html"><![CDATA[<p>In recent years, the urgency to address pressing global challenges has led to increased attention on the <a href="https://sdgs.un.org/goals">United Nations’ Sustainable Development Goals</a> (SDGs). Technological innovations such as <a href="/blog/discover/2019/11/08/what-is-edge-computing.html">edge computing</a> have emerged as promising tools to drive sustainable development. However, it is crucial for businesses to embrace edge computing with a genuine commitment to sustainability.</p>

<h3 id="but-first-what-is-edge-computing">But first… what is edge computing?</h3>

<p>Edge computing refers to the decentralized approach of processing and storing data closer to its source, at the network’s edge, rather than relying solely on centralized cloud servers. Edge computing complements cloud computing by extending its capabilities to the edge of the network, enabling faster processing, <strong>reduced latency</strong>, and enhanced data privacy. Together, edge and cloud computing create a powerful and comprehensive infrastructure that supports a wide range of applications and delivers a seamless user experience. Moreover, edge computing enables <strong>data sovereignty</strong> and business autonomy by processing and storing data locally, reducing reliance on centralized servers. This decentralized approach empowers organizations to maintain control over their data while benefiting from real-time insights and low-latency processing.</p>

<h3 id="and-what-are-the-sustainable-development-goals-sdgs">And what are the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs)?</h3>

<p>The <a href="(https://sdgs.un.org/goals)">Sustainable Development Goals</a> (SDGs), comprise a set of 17 interconnected objectives established by the United Nations in 2015. The SDGs serve as a universal call to action that addresses a wide range of critical global challenges and which provide a comprehensive framework to create a sustainable and equitable future.</p>

<h4 id="here-are-4-sdgs-where-edge-computing-can-make-an-impact">Here are 4 SDGs where edge computing can make an impact</h4>

<h3 id="sdg-7-affordable-and-clean-energy">SDG 7: Affordable and Clean Energy</h3>

<p><a href="https://sdgs.un.org/goals/goal7">SDG7</a> aims to ensure universal access to affordable, reliable, sustainable, and modern energy sources. Edge computing can play a pivotal role by optimizing energy consumption and enabling more efficient energy distribution. By processing data at the edge, energy management systems can minimize wasteful energy practices, identify energy-saving opportunities, and facilitate the integration of renewable energy sources into the power grid.</p>

<h3 id="sdg-9-industry-innovation-and-infrastructure">SDG 9: Industry, Innovation, and Infrastructure</h3>

<p><a href="https://sdgs.un.org/goals/goal9">SDG9</a> seeks to drive economic growth and improve the overall well-being of societies. Edge computing supports this advancement by enabling real-time monitoring, predictive maintenance, and intelligent automation in various sectors. Edge computing also facilitates the deployment of smart infrastructure, enhancing the efficiency and reliability of transportation systems, energy grids, and public services.</p>

<h3 id="sdg-11-sustainable-cities-and-communities">SDG 11: Sustainable Cities and Communities</h3>

<p><a href="https://sdgs.un.org/goals/goal11">SDG11</a> aims at making cities inclusive, safe, resilient, and sustainable by improving urban planning, ensuring access to basic services, and promoting sustainable practices for housing, transportation, and infrastructure. Edge computing contributes to this by enabling smart city solutions. Real-time data processing at the edge allows for efficient traffic management, waste management, and urban planning. By utilizing edge analytics, cities can optimize resource allocation, reduce congestion, and minimize environmental impact, leading to improved quality of life for residents.</p>

<h3 id="sdg-13-climate-action">SDG 13: Climate Action</h3>

<p><a href="https://sdgs.un.org/goals/goal13">SDG13</a> addresses the urgent need for climate action. Edge computing can support this goal by allowing precise climate monitoring. By processing data locally, organizations can reduce the need for large-scale data transfers, which often results in increased energy consumption and carbon emissions. Additionally, edge-enabled environmental monitoring systems can provide accurate and timely data on climate indicators, aiding in climate modeling, disaster response, and the development of sustainable policies.</p>

<h3 id="responsible-implementation-of-edge-computing">Responsible Implementation of Edge Computing</h3>

<p>To avoid being guilty of greenwashing and to ensure meaningful contributions to SDG achievements, companies must approach edge computing with a responsible mindset. Consider the following:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Holistic Sustainability Strategy</strong><br />
Companies should adopt a holistic sustainability strategy that aligns with their core values and business objectives. Edge computing should be integrated into this strategy as a means to drive sustainable development, rather than as a superficial marketing tool.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Energy Efficiency and Renewable Resources</strong><br />
Companies should prioritize energy-efficient hardware and infrastructure for edge computing deployments. Utilizing renewable energy sources to power edge computing systems can further reduce environmental impact and contribute to the clean energy transition.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Lifecycle Assessment</strong><br />
Performing a thorough lifecycle assessment of edge computing infrastructure is essential. This assessment should consider the environmental impact of manufacturing, deployment, operation, and end-of-life disposal of edge devices, promoting responsible consumption and production.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Collaboration and Knowledge Sharing</strong><br />
Businesses should actively participate in collaborative initiatives, industry partnerships, and knowledge-sharing platforms focused on sustainable edge computing practices. Sharing best practices, lessons learned, and research findings can foster innovation and collective progress.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Edge computing holds tremendous potential to support companies in their journey towards achievement of SDGs. By leveraging the benefits of edge computing while maintaining a responsible and genuine commitment to sustainability, businesses can drive positive change in energy efficiency, industry innovation, sustainable cities, and climate action. Embracing edge computing with a responsible mindset ensures that companies will make a tangible impact on global sustainability goals, contributing to a sustainable future.</p>

<p>As SixSq, we provide a diverse bouquet of applications in a unique edge-based <a href="/marketplace">marketplace</a> that serves a multitude of industries and sectors. We aim to provide future-proof solutions that support redeployment of existing <a href="/nuvlaedge#hardware">hardware</a> and efficient use of resources. To deep dive into more tangible elements linked to your business, visit our <a href="/case-studies">webpage</a> or reach out to learn how we can support your sustainable transition and innovative problem solving via edge computing.</p>]]></content><author><name>Rebecca Schenato</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="edge" /><category term="cloud" /><category term="smart_cities" /><category term="sustainability" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In recent years, the urgency to address pressing global challenges has led to increased attention on the United Nations’ Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs). Technological innovations such as edge computing have emerged as promising tools to drive sustainable development. However, it is crucial for businesses to embrace edge computing with a genuine commitment to sustainability. But first… what is edge computing? Edge computing refers to the decentralized approach of processing and storing data closer to its source, at the network’s edge, rather than relying solely on centralized cloud servers. Edge computing complements cloud computing by extending its capabilities to the edge of the network, enabling faster processing, reduced latency, and enhanced data privacy. Together, edge and cloud computing create a powerful and comprehensive infrastructure that supports a wide range of applications and delivers a seamless user experience. Moreover, edge computing enables data sovereignty and business autonomy by processing and storing data locally, reducing reliance on centralized servers. This decentralized approach empowers organizations to maintain control over their data while benefiting from real-time insights and low-latency processing. And what are the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs)? The Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), comprise a set of 17 interconnected objectives established by the United Nations in 2015. The SDGs serve as a universal call to action that addresses a wide range of critical global challenges and which provide a comprehensive framework to create a sustainable and equitable future. Here are 4 SDGs where edge computing can make an impact SDG 7: Affordable and Clean Energy SDG7 aims to ensure universal access to affordable, reliable, sustainable, and modern energy sources. Edge computing can play a pivotal role by optimizing energy consumption and enabling more efficient energy distribution. By processing data at the edge, energy management systems can minimize wasteful energy practices, identify energy-saving opportunities, and facilitate the integration of renewable energy sources into the power grid. SDG 9: Industry, Innovation, and Infrastructure SDG9 seeks to drive economic growth and improve the overall well-being of societies. Edge computing supports this advancement by enabling real-time monitoring, predictive maintenance, and intelligent automation in various sectors. Edge computing also facilitates the deployment of smart infrastructure, enhancing the efficiency and reliability of transportation systems, energy grids, and public services. SDG 11: Sustainable Cities and Communities SDG11 aims at making cities inclusive, safe, resilient, and sustainable by improving urban planning, ensuring access to basic services, and promoting sustainable practices for housing, transportation, and infrastructure. Edge computing contributes to this by enabling smart city solutions. Real-time data processing at the edge allows for efficient traffic management, waste management, and urban planning. By utilizing edge analytics, cities can optimize resource allocation, reduce congestion, and minimize environmental impact, leading to improved quality of life for residents. SDG 13: Climate Action SDG13 addresses the urgent need for climate action. Edge computing can support this goal by allowing precise climate monitoring. By processing data locally, organizations can reduce the need for large-scale data transfers, which often results in increased energy consumption and carbon emissions. Additionally, edge-enabled environmental monitoring systems can provide accurate and timely data on climate indicators, aiding in climate modeling, disaster response, and the development of sustainable policies. Responsible Implementation of Edge Computing To avoid being guilty of greenwashing and to ensure meaningful contributions to SDG achievements, companies must approach edge computing with a responsible mindset. Consider the following: Holistic Sustainability Strategy Companies should adopt a holistic sustainability strategy that aligns with their core values and business objectives. Edge computing should be integrated into this strategy as a means to drive sustainable development, rather than as a superficial marketing tool. Energy Efficiency and Renewable Resources Companies should prioritize energy-efficient hardware and infrastructure for edge computing deployments. Utilizing renewable energy sources to power edge computing systems can further reduce environmental impact and contribute to the clean energy transition. Lifecycle Assessment Performing a thorough lifecycle assessment of edge computing infrastructure is essential. This assessment should consider the environmental impact of manufacturing, deployment, operation, and end-of-life disposal of edge devices, promoting responsible consumption and production. Collaboration and Knowledge Sharing Businesses should actively participate in collaborative initiatives, industry partnerships, and knowledge-sharing platforms focused on sustainable edge computing practices. Sharing best practices, lessons learned, and research findings can foster innovation and collective progress. Edge computing holds tremendous potential to support companies in their journey towards achievement of SDGs. By leveraging the benefits of edge computing while maintaining a responsible and genuine commitment to sustainability, businesses can drive positive change in energy efficiency, industry innovation, sustainable cities, and climate action. Embracing edge computing with a responsible mindset ensures that companies will make a tangible impact on global sustainability goals, contributing to a sustainable future. As SixSq, we provide a diverse bouquet of applications in a unique edge-based marketplace that serves a multitude of industries and sectors. We aim to provide future-proof solutions that support redeployment of existing hardware and efficient use of resources. To deep dive into more tangible elements linked to your business, visit our webpage or reach out to learn how we can support your sustainable transition and innovative problem solving via edge computing.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/SDG.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/SDG.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">SixSq announces updates to the Nuvla platform and marketplace legal framework for improved business enablement</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/05/23/news-nuvla-updated-terms-and-conditions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SixSq announces updates to the Nuvla platform and marketplace legal framework for improved business enablement" /><published>2023-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/news/2023/05/23/news-nuvla-updated-terms-and-conditions</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/05/23/news-nuvla-updated-terms-and-conditions.html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Geneva, May 23rd, 2023 - SixSq SA, an Ekinops company</strong>, today announced important updates to the legal framework for the Nuvla platform and marketplace, provided by its subsidiary SixSq SA.</p>

<p><a href="https://sixsq.com/platform">Nuvla</a> is a proven B2B SaaS digital platform and marketplace for industrialization and automation of containerized edge applications and device management. Nuvla enables the deployment of these applications on the Ekinops <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/products-services/products/oneaccess">OneAccess</a> branded customer premise equipment (CPE), as well as a large range of certified hardware platforms. The Nuvla marketplace contains a growing number of ready-made apps, provided by domain matter experts (aka app vendors). These apps can be automatically deployed in 1-click to any Nuvla-enabled edges, eliminating human error and improving quality. Furthermore, users can register their own apps, creating a private app store, mixing in commercially available apps from the marketplace.</p>

<p>The simplified Terms and Conditions (T&amp;C) and End User License Agreement (EULA) make business between app vendors, customers and end users frictionless and straightforward. They also support network service providers and system integrators in generating additional recurring revenue at the edge and in the cloud.</p>

<p><strong>SixSq’s CEO Marc-Elian Bégin</strong> said, <em>“With this major update to our T&amp;C, we are bringing to edge computing the frictionless business enablement that Amazon created when they introduced cloud computing 17 years ago.”</em></p>

<p>The key highlights of the new legal framework are:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Clear terms between app vendors, the Nuvla operator (SixSq) and customers to enable frictionless business, including payments</li>
  <li>Geographical legal coverage now including Europe, North America, the Middle East and Asia Pacific</li>
  <li>Easier to read and better organized terms</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Ekinops’s CEO Didier Brédy</strong> said, <em>“Ekinops is always pushing innovation and simplicity in our industry. With this updated legal framework, we are able to offer telecom operators, as well as their enterprise &amp; SMB customers, a new and much simpler way of leveraging edge computing, building on the well-established Ekinops portfolio. This is a win-win for both Ekinops and our customers to create new revenue streams.”</em></p>

<p>The changes came into force on 11 May 2023 and users were given the opportunity to review the details before continuing to use the service.</p>

<p>The updated Terms and Conditions can be found <a href="https://sixsq.com/legal/legal-general-terms-and-conditions-v2.html">here</a>.</p>

<p>The updated standard apps EULA can be found <a href="https://sixsq.com/legal/standard-apps-eula-v2.html">here</a>.</p>

<h3 id="your-contacts">Your contacts</h3>

<p><strong>Ekinops</strong></p>

<p>For further media information, or to schedule an interview with Ekinops, please contact:
<br />
<strong>Fraser Kay</strong>
<br />
iseepr
<br />
44(0) 113 350 1922
<br />
<a href="mailto:fraser@iseepr.co.uk">fraser@iseepr.co.uk</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Geneva, May 23rd, 2023 - SixSq SA, an Ekinops company, today announced important updates to the legal framework for the Nuvla platform and marketplace, provided by its subsidiary SixSq SA. Nuvla is a proven B2B SaaS digital platform and marketplace for industrialization and automation of containerized edge applications and device management. Nuvla enables the deployment of these applications on the Ekinops OneAccess branded customer premise equipment (CPE), as well as a large range of certified hardware platforms. The Nuvla marketplace contains a growing number of ready-made apps, provided by domain matter experts (aka app vendors). These apps can be automatically deployed in 1-click to any Nuvla-enabled edges, eliminating human error and improving quality. Furthermore, users can register their own apps, creating a private app store, mixing in commercially available apps from the marketplace. The simplified Terms and Conditions (T&amp;C) and End User License Agreement (EULA) make business between app vendors, customers and end users frictionless and straightforward. They also support network service providers and system integrators in generating additional recurring revenue at the edge and in the cloud. SixSq’s CEO Marc-Elian Bégin said, “With this major update to our T&amp;C, we are bringing to edge computing the frictionless business enablement that Amazon created when they introduced cloud computing 17 years ago.” The key highlights of the new legal framework are: Clear terms between app vendors, the Nuvla operator (SixSq) and customers to enable frictionless business, including payments Geographical legal coverage now including Europe, North America, the Middle East and Asia Pacific Easier to read and better organized terms Ekinops’s CEO Didier Brédy said, “Ekinops is always pushing innovation and simplicity in our industry. With this updated legal framework, we are able to offer telecom operators, as well as their enterprise &amp; SMB customers, a new and much simpler way of leveraging edge computing, building on the well-established Ekinops portfolio. This is a win-win for both Ekinops and our customers to create new revenue streams.” The changes came into force on 11 May 2023 and users were given the opportunity to review the details before continuing to use the service. The updated Terms and Conditions can be found here. The updated standard apps EULA can be found here. Your contacts Ekinops For further media information, or to schedule an interview with Ekinops, please contact: Fraser Kay iseepr 44(0) 113 350 1922 fraser@iseepr.co.uk]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/legal-nuvla-tc.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/legal-nuvla-tc.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Pushing the edge-to-cloud continuum with Horizon Europe</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/05/09/news-horizon-europe.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pushing the edge-to-cloud continuum with Horizon Europe" /><published>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/news/2023/05/09/news-horizon-europe</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/05/09/news-horizon-europe.html"><![CDATA[<p>SixSq is proud to be part of 3 new <a href="https://research-and-innovation.ec.europa.eu/funding/funding-opportunities/funding-programmes-and-open-calls/horizon-europe_en?utm_source=hs_email&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;_hsenc=p2ANqtz-_ADIcfTzwAg6q5_ZHWG0WnKO7fayNUFoOvu3MwVWQpcmCYv8T1gAZUyyJdcrLizxfHPxbq">Horizon Europe</a> projects, thanks to funding from the Swiss government agency <a href="https://www.sbfi.admin.ch/sbfi/en/home.html">SEFRI</a>, which supports Swiss participation in the EU Framework Programme. The projects will give the team the opportunity of working with the very best innovators in Europe to keep SixSq software and services at the cutting edge of technology. All of the 3-year projects focus on computer architecture in the edge-to-cloud space and will be tested via concrete use cases across a wide range of sectors.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://sixsq.com/rd/icos.html?utm_source=hs_email&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;_hsenc=p2ANqtz-_ADIcfTzwAg6q5_ZHWG0WnKO7fayNUFoOvu3MwVWQpcmCYv8T1gAZUyyJdcrLizxfHPxbq">ICOS</a> is designing an AI-powered continuum which is open, secure, adaptable and technology-agnostic. The solution will be tested via <a href="https://www.icos-project.eu/use-cases">4 use cases</a> in the fields of agriculture, multimedia systems, railway infrastructure monitoring and energy mangement.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://sixsq.com/rd/extract.html">EXTRACT</a> aims to develop a data-mining platform for extreme data, leveraging the knowledge of 10 Consortium partners around two interesting use cases: personalised evacuation routing in case of emergency and transforming huge volumes of raw data from radio-telescopes into high quality reusable datasets for use in 15 different scientific domains.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The <a href="https://sixsq.com/rd/aces.html">ACES</a> edge-to-cloud framework will be able of managing itself in terms of workload placement, service and resource management, as well as data and policy management, thanks to AI capabilities.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Participaton in these projects confirms SixSq’s commitment to delivering the most innovative solutions to its customers.</p>

<h3 id="useful-links">Useful links</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.icos-project.eu/">ICOS website</a></p>

<p><a href="https://extract-project.eu/">EXTRACT website</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.aces-edge.eu/">ACES website</a></p>

<p>For a bit of background reading on <strong>edge and cloud computing</strong>, take a look at our <a href="/blog">blog</a> page.</p>

<h3 id="funding">Funding</h3>

<p>The ICOS project is funded through from the European Union’s <a href="https://research-and-innovation.ec.europa.eu/funding/funding-opportunities/funding-programmes-and-open-calls/horizon-europe_en">HORIZON EUROPE</a> research and innovation programme under grant agreement No 101070177. SixSq is funded by SERI under contract number 22.00262.</p>

<p>The EXTRACT project is funded through from the European Union’s <a href="https://research-and-innovation.ec.europa.eu/funding/funding-opportunities/funding-programmes-and-open-calls/horizon-europe_en">HORIZON EUROPE</a> research and innovation programme under grant agreement No 101093110. SixSq is funded by <a href="https://www.sbfi.admin.ch/sbfi/en/home.html">SEFRI</a>.</p>

<p>The ACES project is funded through from the European Union’s <a href="https://research-and-innovation.ec.europa.eu/funding/funding-opportunities/funding-programmes-and-open-calls/horizon-europe_en">HORIZON EUROPE</a> research and innovation programme under grant agreement No 101093126. SixSq is funded by <a href="https://www.sbfi.admin.ch/sbfi/en/home.html">SEFRI</a> under contract number 22.00532.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[SixSq is proud to be part of 3 new Horizon Europe projects, thanks to funding from the Swiss government agency SEFRI, which supports Swiss participation in the EU Framework Programme. The projects will give the team the opportunity of working with the very best innovators in Europe to keep SixSq software and services at the cutting edge of technology. All of the 3-year projects focus on computer architecture in the edge-to-cloud space and will be tested via concrete use cases across a wide range of sectors. ICOS is designing an AI-powered continuum which is open, secure, adaptable and technology-agnostic. The solution will be tested via 4 use cases in the fields of agriculture, multimedia systems, railway infrastructure monitoring and energy mangement. EXTRACT aims to develop a data-mining platform for extreme data, leveraging the knowledge of 10 Consortium partners around two interesting use cases: personalised evacuation routing in case of emergency and transforming huge volumes of raw data from radio-telescopes into high quality reusable datasets for use in 15 different scientific domains. The ACES edge-to-cloud framework will be able of managing itself in terms of workload placement, service and resource management, as well as data and policy management, thanks to AI capabilities. Participaton in these projects confirms SixSq’s commitment to delivering the most innovative solutions to its customers. Useful links ICOS website EXTRACT website ACES website For a bit of background reading on edge and cloud computing, take a look at our blog page. Funding The ICOS project is funded through from the European Union’s HORIZON EUROPE research and innovation programme under grant agreement No 101070177. SixSq is funded by SERI under contract number 22.00262. The EXTRACT project is funded through from the European Union’s HORIZON EUROPE research and innovation programme under grant agreement No 101093110. SixSq is funded by SEFRI. The ACES project is funded through from the European Union’s HORIZON EUROPE research and innovation programme under grant agreement No 101093126. SixSq is funded by SEFRI under contract number 22.00532.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/horizon-europe.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/horizon-europe.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Introducing our new Marketing &amp;amp; Communications Manager</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/03/27/news-rebecca-schenato.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing our new Marketing &amp;amp; Communications Manager" /><published>2023-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/news/2023/03/27/news-rebecca-schenato</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/03/27/news-rebecca-schenato.html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>On 13 March 2023, Rebecca Schenato took up her role as Marketing &amp; Communications Manager in Geneva</strong></p>

<p>SixSq is excited to announce that Rebecca Schenato has joined the team as Marketing &amp; Communications Manager. Rebecca brings a wealth of experience in making tech brands shine with a proven track record of in IoT and B2B sectors. Her creative marketing approach will help bring the company to the next level, delivering an outstanding experience to current and potential users and customers.</p>

<p>Commenting on her appointment, Rebecca said, <em>“It is a pleasure to be part of the SixSq team and Ekinops ecosystem.  I am thrilled to have the opportunity of contributing to the growth and vision of the company. There is a lot of great potential ahead, and I am looking forward to working together towards the accomplishment of the company’s ambitions”</em>.</p>

<p>As Marketing &amp; Communications Manager Rebecca will be a major contributor to ensure our messaging continues to be clear and crisp, while translating the company’s business objectives into actionable marketing strategies.</p>

<p>SixSq CEO, Marc-Elian Bégin said, <em>“Rebecca is the perfect complement to the team, bringing a wealth of relevant experience and energy. She will be instrumental in forging a path towards our ambitious growth objectives”</em>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[On 13 March 2023, Rebecca Schenato took up her role as Marketing &amp; Communications Manager in Geneva SixSq is excited to announce that Rebecca Schenato has joined the team as Marketing &amp; Communications Manager. Rebecca brings a wealth of experience in making tech brands shine with a proven track record of in IoT and B2B sectors. Her creative marketing approach will help bring the company to the next level, delivering an outstanding experience to current and potential users and customers. Commenting on her appointment, Rebecca said, “It is a pleasure to be part of the SixSq team and Ekinops ecosystem. I am thrilled to have the opportunity of contributing to the growth and vision of the company. There is a lot of great potential ahead, and I am looking forward to working together towards the accomplishment of the company’s ambitions”. As Marketing &amp; Communications Manager Rebecca will be a major contributor to ensure our messaging continues to be clear and crisp, while translating the company’s business objectives into actionable marketing strategies. SixSq CEO, Marc-Elian Bégin said, “Rebecca is the perfect complement to the team, bringing a wealth of relevant experience and energy. She will be instrumental in forging a path towards our ambitious growth objectives”.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/rebecca-schenato.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/rebecca-schenato.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Varnish Software now available on SixSq’s Nuvla Marketplace</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/01/25/news-varnish.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Varnish Software now available on SixSq’s Nuvla Marketplace" /><published>2023-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/news/2023/01/25/news-varnish</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/01/25/news-varnish.html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>SixSq Users Now Have Access to Varnish Software’s Most Powerful Caching and CDN Solutions Via the Nuvla Marketplace</strong></p>

<p><strong>Geneva and Los Angeles - 25 January 2023</strong> SixSq, an <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/">Ekinops</a> Company, and <a href="https://www.varnish-software.com/">Varnish Software</a>, a leader in caching, streaming and content delivery software solutions,  today announced a partnership to integrate and deliver Varnish Software’s feature-rich suite of web cache and HTTP accelerator solutions - <a href="https://www.varnish-software.com/solutions/varnish-enterprise/">Varnish Enterprise</a> - via the Nuvla platform and marketplace. This integration significantly simplifies the procurement, deployment and management of Varnish Software’s technology, enabling new capabilities and unparalleled performance for SixSq customers and their users at the edge.</p>

<p>By utilizing the <a href="https://sixsq.com/marketplace">Nuvla Marketplace</a> to deploy Varnish Software, telecom operators and CSPs in any location can now flawlessly deliver lightning-fast, high-quality web and streaming experiences while significantly lowering costs and hardware requirements across an entire ecosystem of distributed edges.</p>

<p><em>“Service providers require consistent and reliable speed and performance to deliver excellent web experiences for users, at scale,”</em> said Irene Lundin, Chief Delivery Officer at Varnish Software. <em>“Nuvla speeds up the way we can deliver Varnish Software by simplifying the deployment and maintenance process. We are now better equipped to deliver next-gen connectivity wherever it is needed, anywhere in the world.”</em></p>

<p>The new integration is part of a broader collaboration between the two companies to bridge 5G satellite communications with advanced web caching and content delivery at the edge, which includes contributions to the European Broadcasting Union (EBU)’s <a href="https://www.ebu.ch/news/2022/06/esa-and-ebu-to-build-solutions-for-emerging-satellite-enabled-5g-media-market">5G-EMERGE consortium</a>.</p>

<p><em>“Our partnership with Varnish Software perfectly demonstrates the value of app delivery using the Nuvla Marketplace,”</em> said Marc-Elian Bégin, SixSq CEO and Co-founder. <em>“Customers from any business sector can now deploy Varnish Software’s caching app at the telco edge, near edge as well as far edge, with a direct and measurable positive impact on the digital experience of users.”</em></p>

<p>Importantly, Varnish Enterprise is the only software that can provide an edge runtime environment, enabling operators to write and execute compute logic as close to the end user as possible in mere microseconds. It can be installed in front of any server that accepts requests via HTTP/HTTPS to significantly speed up response time by an impressive 300 – 1000%, and reduce backend server load by up to 99%.</p>

<p>SixSq’s Nuvla is a proven B2B digital platform for industrialization and automation of containerized edge applications and device management. The Nuvla app vendor program gives app vendors and customers tools to interact in a seamless way, including clear pricing and contractual terms. It also provides hassle-free monetization of business applications for telcos, service providers and system integrators.</p>

<p>With Varnish Enterprise available on the Nuvla Marketplace, companies can now deploy, manage and update an enterprise-grade caching solution to deliver a high-quality digital experience, remotely and securely. The purchasing and deployment process is fast, simple and robust, with the app deployed at scale in a few clicks via the Nuvla dashboard.</p>

<p>The service is available via a pay-as-you-go subscription. Varnish Enterprise can be found on the Nuvla Marketplace <a href="https://nuvla.io/ui/apps/varnish">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[SixSq Users Now Have Access to Varnish Software’s Most Powerful Caching and CDN Solutions Via the Nuvla Marketplace Geneva and Los Angeles - 25 January 2023 SixSq, an Ekinops Company, and Varnish Software, a leader in caching, streaming and content delivery software solutions, today announced a partnership to integrate and deliver Varnish Software’s feature-rich suite of web cache and HTTP accelerator solutions - Varnish Enterprise - via the Nuvla platform and marketplace. This integration significantly simplifies the procurement, deployment and management of Varnish Software’s technology, enabling new capabilities and unparalleled performance for SixSq customers and their users at the edge. By utilizing the Nuvla Marketplace to deploy Varnish Software, telecom operators and CSPs in any location can now flawlessly deliver lightning-fast, high-quality web and streaming experiences while significantly lowering costs and hardware requirements across an entire ecosystem of distributed edges. “Service providers require consistent and reliable speed and performance to deliver excellent web experiences for users, at scale,” said Irene Lundin, Chief Delivery Officer at Varnish Software. “Nuvla speeds up the way we can deliver Varnish Software by simplifying the deployment and maintenance process. We are now better equipped to deliver next-gen connectivity wherever it is needed, anywhere in the world.” The new integration is part of a broader collaboration between the two companies to bridge 5G satellite communications with advanced web caching and content delivery at the edge, which includes contributions to the European Broadcasting Union (EBU)’s 5G-EMERGE consortium. “Our partnership with Varnish Software perfectly demonstrates the value of app delivery using the Nuvla Marketplace,” said Marc-Elian Bégin, SixSq CEO and Co-founder. “Customers from any business sector can now deploy Varnish Software’s caching app at the telco edge, near edge as well as far edge, with a direct and measurable positive impact on the digital experience of users.” Importantly, Varnish Enterprise is the only software that can provide an edge runtime environment, enabling operators to write and execute compute logic as close to the end user as possible in mere microseconds. It can be installed in front of any server that accepts requests via HTTP/HTTPS to significantly speed up response time by an impressive 300 – 1000%, and reduce backend server load by up to 99%. SixSq’s Nuvla is a proven B2B digital platform for industrialization and automation of containerized edge applications and device management. The Nuvla app vendor program gives app vendors and customers tools to interact in a seamless way, including clear pricing and contractual terms. It also provides hassle-free monetization of business applications for telcos, service providers and system integrators. With Varnish Enterprise available on the Nuvla Marketplace, companies can now deploy, manage and update an enterprise-grade caching solution to deliver a high-quality digital experience, remotely and securely. The purchasing and deployment process is fast, simple and robust, with the app deployed at scale in a few clicks via the Nuvla dashboard. The service is available via a pay-as-you-go subscription. Varnish Enterprise can be found on the Nuvla Marketplace here.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/app-vendor-varnish.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/app-vendor-varnish.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">LatenceTech now available on SixSq’s Nuvla Marketplace</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/01/12/news-latencetech.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LatenceTech now available on SixSq’s Nuvla Marketplace" /><published>2023-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/news/2023/01/12/news-latencetech</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/01/12/news-latencetech.html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>SixSq’s Nuvla ecosystem facilitates the deployment, management and update of LatenceTech quality of service measurement solution at the edge and in the cloud</strong></p>

<p>Geneva, 12 January 2023. SixSq, an <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/">Ekinops</a> Company, and <a href="https://latencetech.com/">LatenceTech</a> today announced a partnership to deliver LatenceTech QoS via the<a href="/marketplace"> Nuvla Marketplace</a>. This collaboration will allow LatenceTech to quickly and easily market and deploy its technology to service and network providers.</p>

<p>With LatenceTech available in the Nuvla Marketplace, it is now easier for companies to track, predict and deploy latency-optimized 5G and private LTE networks remotely and securely. The purchasing and deployment process is fast, simple, and robust, with the app deployed at scale in a few clicks via the Nuvla dashboard.</p>

<p>SixSq’s Nuvla is a proven B2B digital platform for industrialization and automation of containerized edge applications and device management. The <a href="/news/2022/06/09/news-app-vendor-programme.html">Nuvla App Vendor Program</a> gives app vendors and customers tools to interact in a seamless way, including clear pricing and contractual terms. It also provides hassle-free monetization of business applications for telcos, service providers and system integrators.</p>

<p><em>“Our agreement with SixSq is an important milestone for LatenceTech as it allows our company to market our technology on a large scale on an efficient and well-established platform to our target audiences. We believe that the Nuvla platform is an excellent fit for our technology and business model. We are confident that this partnership between SixSq and LatenceTech will be mutually beneficial, and that it will allow our future customers to benefit from the high value-added advantages of our technology in a simple and quick manner,”</em> said <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/benoitgendron/">Benoit Gendron</a>, President and CEO of LatenceTech.</p>

<p><em>“This partnership with LatenceTech fills an important gap in the ability for service providers to monetize 5G. Now users can accurately and easily measure SLA compliance, something that is paramount when selling high quality services, without taking risks. And all this is a few clicks away using Nuvla”</em> said <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mebster/">Marc-Elian Bégin</a>, SixSq CEO and Co-founder.</p>

<p>The service is available via a pay-as-you-go subscription. You will find LatenceTech on the Nuvla Marketplace <a href="https://nuvla.io/ui/apps/latencetech">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[SixSq’s Nuvla ecosystem facilitates the deployment, management and update of LatenceTech quality of service measurement solution at the edge and in the cloud Geneva, 12 January 2023. SixSq, an Ekinops Company, and LatenceTech today announced a partnership to deliver LatenceTech QoS via the Nuvla Marketplace. This collaboration will allow LatenceTech to quickly and easily market and deploy its technology to service and network providers. With LatenceTech available in the Nuvla Marketplace, it is now easier for companies to track, predict and deploy latency-optimized 5G and private LTE networks remotely and securely. The purchasing and deployment process is fast, simple, and robust, with the app deployed at scale in a few clicks via the Nuvla dashboard. SixSq’s Nuvla is a proven B2B digital platform for industrialization and automation of containerized edge applications and device management. The Nuvla App Vendor Program gives app vendors and customers tools to interact in a seamless way, including clear pricing and contractual terms. It also provides hassle-free monetization of business applications for telcos, service providers and system integrators. “Our agreement with SixSq is an important milestone for LatenceTech as it allows our company to market our technology on a large scale on an efficient and well-established platform to our target audiences. We believe that the Nuvla platform is an excellent fit for our technology and business model. We are confident that this partnership between SixSq and LatenceTech will be mutually beneficial, and that it will allow our future customers to benefit from the high value-added advantages of our technology in a simple and quick manner,” said Benoit Gendron, President and CEO of LatenceTech. “This partnership with LatenceTech fills an important gap in the ability for service providers to monetize 5G. Now users can accurately and easily measure SLA compliance, something that is paramount when selling high quality services, without taking risks. And all this is a few clicks away using Nuvla” said Marc-Elian Bégin, SixSq CEO and Co-founder. The service is available via a pay-as-you-go subscription. You will find LatenceTech on the Nuvla Marketplace here.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/app-vendor-latencetech.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/app-vendor-latencetech.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Killer App For The Edge</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/blog/marketplace/2022/11/25/killer-app-for-the-edge.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Killer App For The Edge" /><published>2022-11-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-11-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/blog/marketplace/2022/11/25/killer-app-for-the-edge</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/blog/marketplace/2022/11/25/killer-app-for-the-edge.html"><![CDATA[<p>For some time, analysts and industry experts have been heralding <a href="/blog/discover/2019/11/08/what-is-edge-computing.html">edge computing</a> as the next big thing that will revolutionise the IT and telecom industries. But for industries to move, there needs to be real and meaningful benefits, achievable within reasonable investment and at an acceptable risk.  It would indeed therefore be great to identify the ‘killer app’ for edge computing – a single heroic app to unlock the full potential of this promising distributed computing paradigm, one that’s capable of fulfilling the level of world domination predicted by analysts. So where is it?</p>

<p>Perhaps this is the wrong question. If we stand back, the edge is not there to run a single all-encompassing, killer app, but to enable an ecosystem of applications that allows organisations to better extract value from data near its source. And this objective is neither simple nor standard, since, like us humans, every business is different, with different goals, constraints and assets. However, edge computing will not succeed if all its implementations are bespoke. The good news is that there is an existing ecosystem that exhibits a similar need for wide and wild variety, yet is based on standardised building blocks that tech companies can provide at affordable pricing, thanks to economy of scale.</p>

<p>Where is this ecosystem? I suggest looking in your pocket. The dominance of the smartphone appliance is no longer questioned today… yet what about all those apps? Your mobile device is not satisfied with a one-size-fits-all killer app, so why should your edge infrastructure be any different?</p>

<h3 id="learning-from-the-apple-app-store">Learning from the Apple® App Store</h3>

<p>Apparently, even the mighty Steve Jobs didn’t initially foresee the rise of the App Store as a key part of the iPhone®’s success story, instead expecting web apps to be the next big thing. Apple® had to move quickly to meet developer demands, opening up the iPhone® ecosystem to allow these people to create native iOS apps and this, in turn, led to the creation of the App Store to monetise these apps and make them available to customers.</p>

<h3 id="the-first-marketplace-for-edge-apps">The first marketplace for edge apps</h3>

<p>For edge computing to work well, businesses need a simple and scalable way to purchase apps and immediately deploy them where their data is. But of course no-one needs integration complexity, complicated contractual negotiations and operational risk.</p>

<p>Here at SixSq we’re now on a similar path to Apple®, building the world’s first repository of edge apps, the Nuvla Marketplace, usefully informed by the experiences of the App Store, Google Play® and other digital distribution platforms.</p>

<h3 id="app-vendors">App vendors</h3>

<p>Since June 2022, we’ve been fostering strong relationships with some of the best creative minds in edge computing app development through the SixSq App Vendor Programme. These specialists don’t pull any punches – their powerful apps are oriented to omnipresent AI, steely <a href="https://sixsq.com/news/2022/06/13/news-aiedgelabs.html">cyber defence</a>, operational optimisation and predictive analytics to meet business challenges head on. I’m talking about reducing latency, overcoming bandwidth challenges, increasing autonomy, ensuring data sovereignty, cutting the carbon footprint and more.</p>

<p>To de-risk projects and ensure future-proofed solutions, we’re all about standardised operational, technical and contractual app development within a systematic framework for an open, frictionless ecosystem.</p>

<h3 id="the-source-of-killer-apps-for-the-edge">The source of killer apps for the edge</h3>

<p>Together this makes the <a href="/marketplace">Nuvla Marketplace</a> the go-to source of business-ready apps, provided and maintained by domain experts. If you like a dubious metaphor, we at SixSq provide the Tinder app for edge computing and, as the platform operator, we also come on your date as chaperone!</p>

<p>With our approach, vendors can register new apps on the Nuvla Marketplace in a few hours, while you can deploy these apps in seconds and enable your edge devices in minutes. The potential for our edge marketplace to deliver multiple killer apps is real. Of course time will tell, but the telling is already starting. Don’t wait for the killer app, the marketplace delivers a suite of readily-available apps to deliver your business outcomes.</p>]]></content><author><name>Marc-Elian Bégin</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="edge" /><category term="cloud" /><category term="privacy" /><category term="security" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[For some time, analysts and industry experts have been heralding edge computing as the next big thing that will revolutionise the IT and telecom industries. But for industries to move, there needs to be real and meaningful benefits, achievable within reasonable investment and at an acceptable risk. It would indeed therefore be great to identify the ‘killer app’ for edge computing – a single heroic app to unlock the full potential of this promising distributed computing paradigm, one that’s capable of fulfilling the level of world domination predicted by analysts. So where is it? Perhaps this is the wrong question. If we stand back, the edge is not there to run a single all-encompassing, killer app, but to enable an ecosystem of applications that allows organisations to better extract value from data near its source. And this objective is neither simple nor standard, since, like us humans, every business is different, with different goals, constraints and assets. However, edge computing will not succeed if all its implementations are bespoke. The good news is that there is an existing ecosystem that exhibits a similar need for wide and wild variety, yet is based on standardised building blocks that tech companies can provide at affordable pricing, thanks to economy of scale. Where is this ecosystem? I suggest looking in your pocket. The dominance of the smartphone appliance is no longer questioned today… yet what about all those apps? Your mobile device is not satisfied with a one-size-fits-all killer app, so why should your edge infrastructure be any different? Learning from the Apple® App Store Apparently, even the mighty Steve Jobs didn’t initially foresee the rise of the App Store as a key part of the iPhone®’s success story, instead expecting web apps to be the next big thing. Apple® had to move quickly to meet developer demands, opening up the iPhone® ecosystem to allow these people to create native iOS apps and this, in turn, led to the creation of the App Store to monetise these apps and make them available to customers. The first marketplace for edge apps For edge computing to work well, businesses need a simple and scalable way to purchase apps and immediately deploy them where their data is. But of course no-one needs integration complexity, complicated contractual negotiations and operational risk. Here at SixSq we’re now on a similar path to Apple®, building the world’s first repository of edge apps, the Nuvla Marketplace, usefully informed by the experiences of the App Store, Google Play® and other digital distribution platforms. App vendors Since June 2022, we’ve been fostering strong relationships with some of the best creative minds in edge computing app development through the SixSq App Vendor Programme. These specialists don’t pull any punches – their powerful apps are oriented to omnipresent AI, steely cyber defence, operational optimisation and predictive analytics to meet business challenges head on. I’m talking about reducing latency, overcoming bandwidth challenges, increasing autonomy, ensuring data sovereignty, cutting the carbon footprint and more. To de-risk projects and ensure future-proofed solutions, we’re all about standardised operational, technical and contractual app development within a systematic framework for an open, frictionless ecosystem. The source of killer apps for the edge Together this makes the Nuvla Marketplace the go-to source of business-ready apps, provided and maintained by domain experts. If you like a dubious metaphor, we at SixSq provide the Tinder app for edge computing and, as the platform operator, we also come on your date as chaperone! With our approach, vendors can register new apps on the Nuvla Marketplace in a few hours, while you can deploy these apps in seconds and enable your edge devices in minutes. The potential for our edge marketplace to deliver multiple killer apps is real. Of course time will tell, but the telling is already starting. Don’t wait for the killer app, the marketplace delivers a suite of readily-available apps to deliver your business outcomes.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/marketplace.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/marketplace.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">ICOS; Removing boundaries between IoT, Edge and Cloud</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2022/11/16/icos-remove-boundaries-between-iot-edge-cloud.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ICOS; Removing boundaries between IoT, Edge and Cloud" /><published>2022-11-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-11-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2022/11/16/icos-remove-boundaries-between-iot-edge-cloud</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2022/11/16/icos-remove-boundaries-between-iot-edge-cloud.html"><![CDATA[<p>The first <a href="/rd/icos.html">ICOS</a> face-to-face meeting took place earlier this month in sunny Vilanova I la Geltru, Catalunya, Spain, uniting more than 20 Consortium partners including SixSq. This <a href="https://research-and-innovation.ec.europa.eu/funding/funding-opportunities/funding-programmes-and-open-calls/horizon-europe_en">Horizon Europe</a> project has the ambition of delivering a Meta-Operating System within 3 years, bridging IoT devices to the cloud through <a href="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2019/11/08/what-is-edge-computing.html">edge computing</a> devices.</p>

<p>ICOS, code name for ‘IoT2Cloud Operating System’, is a unique computing system supporting the interconnection of IoT, edge and cloud resources.</p>

<p>The concept of a continuum between IoT, edge and cloud aims to tackle the challenges linked to the ever-growing sector of computing and sensing devices, and to the increasing demand for data-intensive applications, especially at the edge and in the cloud.</p>

<p>By enabling this continuum, in a way which is both technology and device-agnostic, ICOS will facilitate data generation, transfer, and processing - thanks to AI.</p>

<p>ICOS System architecture, functional requirements and use cases were at the heart of the discussions during this 2-day meeting. Indeed, ICOS will address real-life challenges in various fields, with a positive impact on reliability and sustainability.</p>

<p>4 relevant <a href="https://www.icos-project.eu/use-cases">use cases</a> were brought by project partners:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Bring precision agriculture to the next step by embarking ICOS into agricultural robots, or agrobots, in the fields. Thanks to AI modules, the robots will be able to detect a disease among a plantation, calculate the real amount of fertiliser needed by each plant, etc.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Improve railway maintenance thanks to a combination of IoT sensors and edge devices, enabling real-time monitoring of the infrastructure metrics and optimising decision-making process.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Enhance “in-car” user experience thanks to immersive content display linked to touristic trips, and shared media streaming.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Optimise household energy consumption thanks to an autonomous system based on continuum management.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Fruitful interactions took place during the “ICOS match” workshop between technologies and user stories. The SixSq team was glad to see that <a href="/platform">Nuvla</a>/<a href="https://sixsq.com/nuvlaedge">NuvlaEdge</a> had a lot of matches and will bring value to all of the use cases in the project by facilitating management of IoT devices and applications.</p>

<p>Thanks to this working group, all Consortium members (technology and use cases providers) had a chance to draw a mental map of the combination of technologies needed to perform each use case.</p>

<p>Finally, these two days were a great opportunity for partners to meet in-person, but also to taste Catalan gastronomy – especially tapas!</p>

<p>Next step from our side: start working on the component that will be used to manage edge devices, and data flow through the IoT to cloud continuum. We are looking forward to bringing further updates during the life of the project.</p>]]></content><author><name>Agathe Veillon</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="edge" /><category term="cloud" /><category term="iot" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first ICOS face-to-face meeting took place earlier this month in sunny Vilanova I la Geltru, Catalunya, Spain, uniting more than 20 Consortium partners including SixSq. This Horizon Europe project has the ambition of delivering a Meta-Operating System within 3 years, bridging IoT devices to the cloud through edge computing devices. ICOS, code name for ‘IoT2Cloud Operating System’, is a unique computing system supporting the interconnection of IoT, edge and cloud resources. The concept of a continuum between IoT, edge and cloud aims to tackle the challenges linked to the ever-growing sector of computing and sensing devices, and to the increasing demand for data-intensive applications, especially at the edge and in the cloud. By enabling this continuum, in a way which is both technology and device-agnostic, ICOS will facilitate data generation, transfer, and processing - thanks to AI. ICOS System architecture, functional requirements and use cases were at the heart of the discussions during this 2-day meeting. Indeed, ICOS will address real-life challenges in various fields, with a positive impact on reliability and sustainability. 4 relevant use cases were brought by project partners: Bring precision agriculture to the next step by embarking ICOS into agricultural robots, or agrobots, in the fields. Thanks to AI modules, the robots will be able to detect a disease among a plantation, calculate the real amount of fertiliser needed by each plant, etc. Improve railway maintenance thanks to a combination of IoT sensors and edge devices, enabling real-time monitoring of the infrastructure metrics and optimising decision-making process. Enhance “in-car” user experience thanks to immersive content display linked to touristic trips, and shared media streaming. Optimise household energy consumption thanks to an autonomous system based on continuum management. Fruitful interactions took place during the “ICOS match” workshop between technologies and user stories. The SixSq team was glad to see that Nuvla/NuvlaEdge had a lot of matches and will bring value to all of the use cases in the project by facilitating management of IoT devices and applications. Thanks to this working group, all Consortium members (technology and use cases providers) had a chance to draw a mental map of the combination of technologies needed to perform each use case. Finally, these two days were a great opportunity for partners to meet in-person, but also to taste Catalan gastronomy – especially tapas! Next step from our side: start working on the component that will be used to manage edge devices, and data flow through the IoT to cloud continuum. We are looking forward to bringing further updates during the life of the project.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/featured-icos.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/featured-icos.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Relimetrics joins app vendor programme</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/news/2022/09/29/news-relimetrics.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Relimetrics joins app vendor programme" /><published>2022-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/news/2022/09/29/news-relimetrics</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/news/2022/09/29/news-relimetrics.html"><![CDATA[<p>SixSq, an <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/">Ekinops</a> Company, and <a href="https://www.relimetrics.com/">Relimetrics</a> today announced a partnership to deliver <a href="https://www.relimetrics.com/applications">ReliVision</a> via the <a href="/marketplace">Nuvla Marketplace</a>. This collaboration significantly simplifies the procurement, deployment, and management of Relimetric’s ReliVision on the factory floor.</p>

<p>Relimetrics helps companies transform how they design and build products by using cutting edge technologies such as computer vision, machine learning, AI and edge computing. The result is a level of quality control automation that is unmatched in the market today, which is quick, simple and cheap to configure and enable. Once in place, users take advantage of the no-code ReliVision solution to enable quality automation for their assembly.</p>

<p><em>“Nuvla allows ReliVision to be offered to manufacturers using a simple pay-as-you-go model. This means customers can choose when to use ReliVision and get Nuvla to quickly deploy ReliVision modules on the shop floor, leveraging existing hardware.”</em> said <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kemallevi/">Kemal Levi</a>, CEO and Founder of Relimetrics.</p>

<p>With Relimetrics’ ReliVision made available in the Nuvla Marketplace, companies can deploy, manage, and update their quality automation application remotely and securely. The purchasing and deployment process is fast, simple and robust, with the app deployed at scale in a few clicks via the <a href="/platform">Nuvla</a> dashboard.</p>

<p><em>“Helping domain matter experts like Relimetrics to scale across industries is why we created Nuvla. Once the <a href="/nuvlaedge">NuvlaEdge</a> software is installed on the edge infrastructure, customers can deploy the most advanced quality automation solution for assembly lines with Relimetrics’s ReliVision”</em> said <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mebster/">Marc-Elian Bégin</a>, SixSq CEO and Co-founder.</p>

<p>This announcement enriches the <a href="/news/2022/06/09/news-app-vendor-programme.html">Nuvla App Vendor Programme</a>, announced earlier this year. The service is available via a pay-as-you-go subscription. You will find Relimetric’s ReliVision edge application on the Nuvla Marketplace <a href="https://nuvla.io/ui/apps/relimetrics">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[SixSq, an Ekinops Company, and Relimetrics today announced a partnership to deliver ReliVision via the Nuvla Marketplace. This collaboration significantly simplifies the procurement, deployment, and management of Relimetric’s ReliVision on the factory floor. Relimetrics helps companies transform how they design and build products by using cutting edge technologies such as computer vision, machine learning, AI and edge computing. The result is a level of quality control automation that is unmatched in the market today, which is quick, simple and cheap to configure and enable. Once in place, users take advantage of the no-code ReliVision solution to enable quality automation for their assembly. “Nuvla allows ReliVision to be offered to manufacturers using a simple pay-as-you-go model. This means customers can choose when to use ReliVision and get Nuvla to quickly deploy ReliVision modules on the shop floor, leveraging existing hardware.” said Kemal Levi, CEO and Founder of Relimetrics. With Relimetrics’ ReliVision made available in the Nuvla Marketplace, companies can deploy, manage, and update their quality automation application remotely and securely. The purchasing and deployment process is fast, simple and robust, with the app deployed at scale in a few clicks via the Nuvla dashboard. “Helping domain matter experts like Relimetrics to scale across industries is why we created Nuvla. Once the NuvlaEdge software is installed on the edge infrastructure, customers can deploy the most advanced quality automation solution for assembly lines with Relimetrics’s ReliVision” said Marc-Elian Bégin, SixSq CEO and Co-founder. This announcement enriches the Nuvla App Vendor Programme, announced earlier this year. The service is available via a pay-as-you-go subscription. You will find Relimetric’s ReliVision edge application on the Nuvla Marketplace here.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/app-vendor-relimetrics.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/app-vendor-relimetrics.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>