<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://sixsq.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://sixsq.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-01-22T10:35:52+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">SixSq Website</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Navigating the Waves of Change; How Edge Computing Transforms Maritime Logistics</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/12/21/how-edge-computing-transforms-maritime-logistics.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Navigating the Waves of Change; How Edge Computing Transforms Maritime Logistics" /><published>2023-12-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/12/21/how-edge-computing-transforms-maritime-logistics</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/12/21/how-edge-computing-transforms-maritime-logistics.html"><![CDATA[<p>Maritime commerce has been widely used throughout history and has grown in importance to the point where it’s now responsible for <strong>80% of the world’s trade</strong> <sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>. Over the years, the maritime industry has faced multiple challenges, but arguably none greater than today, with thw environmental, escalating costs and safety issues causing concern to operators. Edge computing is able to address these challenges and emerges as an essential innovation for maritime logistics, promising to revolutionize the way we navigate the seas.</p>

<h3 id="keeping-tabs-on-containers-and-codes">Keeping Tabs on Containers and Codes</h3>

<p>In the vast expanse of the ocean, the fear of lost containers is a significant concern. Edge computing tackles this issue by enabling advanced tracking systems that provide real-time insights into container movements. Equipped with sophisticated sensors and cameras, these systems read alphanumeric codes on containers, offering precise information about their location and contents. This not only prevents losses but also enhances supply chain visibility.</p>

<h3 id="monitoring-container-movements-in-real-time">Monitoring Container Movements in Real Time</h3>

<p>Containers in transit face various risks, from accidental falls to physical damage. Edge computing introduces continuous monitoring of containers, instantly alerting operators to potential hazards. This proactive approach ensures a swift response to prevent accidents, falls, or displacements, safeguarding both personnel and valuable cargo.</p>

<h3 id="ensuring-workers-safety">Ensuring Workers’ Safety</h3>

<p>Worker safety is a top priority in maritime operations, and edge computing plays a crucial role in ensuring compliance with safety protocols. Cameras with edge processing capabilities keep a vigilant eye, confirming that workers wear necessary safety gear, stay in designated areas, and follow safety guidelines. This not only enhances overall safety but also reduces the risk of accidents at sea.</p>

<h2 id="fire-hazard-prevention-and-management">Fire Hazard Prevention and Management</h2>

<p>Potential fire hazards pose a significant threat in the maritime industry, underscoring the need for advanced safety measures. To manage this, edge computing introduces innovative solutions linked to fire detection and smoke monitoring systems. These systems are able to provide real-time insights into potential fire risks, allowing for swift response and containment. It is in fact not only possible to detect the presence of smoke but also analyze its characteristics, aiding in early fire detection. This proactive approach to fire safety is instrumental in mitigating risks, supporting both the cargo and crew.</p>

<h2 id="tracking-mariner-movements-and-safety-zones">Tracking Mariner Movements and Safety Zones</h2>

<p>Understanding and managing movement of workers on ships is vital for safety. Edge computing facilitates the creation of safety zones, tracking personnel in real time and sending alerts if they venture into unsafe areas. This not only enhances safety protocols but also ensures swift and efficient evacuation procedures during emergencies.</p>

<h2 id="securing-shipping-content-through-weight-monitoring">Securing Shipping Content through Weight Monitoring</h2>

<p>Edge computing supports a sturdy approach to securing goods stored in containers. By monitoring container weight before embarkation and upon disembarkation, any discrepancies indicate potential tampering. This enhances security, ensuring that the merchandise remains intact throughout the journey, minimizing the risk of theft or damage during transport.</p>

<h2 id="proactive-engine-insights">Proactive Engine Insights</h2>

<p>Understanding the intricate dynamics of a ship’s engine and its surrounding subsystems is fundamental to ensuring a smooth and secure journey. Edge computing enables crews to take a proactive approach by supporting real-time monitoring and analysis of engine performance. By leveraging the power of artificial intelligence and algorithms, the engine and its associated subsystems can be protected using anomaly detection and predictive analysis. This capability can prevent failures, accidents and breakdowns, therefore enhancing overall operational efficiency, while reducing operational costs.</p>

<h2 id="towards-a-greener-horizon">Towards a Greener Horizon</h2>

<p>Beyond safety and efficiency, edge computing contributes to environmental sustainability. By preventing lost-at-sea containers and implementing efficient monitoring systems, it minimizes ocean pollution and encourages responsible maritime practices. The result is a more eco-friendly and conscientious approach to navigating the high seas.</p>

<h2 id="sixsq-and-its-impact-in-the-maritime-industry">SixSq and its Impact in the Maritime Industry</h2>

<p>SixSq stands at the forefront of positive transformation through its innovative edge computing solutions. In fact, it plays a pivotal role in enhancing the efficiency, safety, and sustainability of the maritime industry. By integrating its robust edge computing <a href="/platform">Nuvla.io</a> platform, <a href="/marketplace">marketplace</a>, and edge solution into maritime operations, SixSq facilitates seamless communication, real-time container tracking, and continuous monitoring of movements—establishing a proactive approach to safety. With a commitment to worker protection, SixSq’s solutions enforce safety compliance and contribute to creating a secure and conducive working environment.</p>

<p>As the maritime industry embraces the power of edge computing, we find ourselves at the beginning of a new technological era. The challenges that once seemed impossible to overcome are now met with innovative solutions, creating a safer, more efficient, and environmentally conscious maritime landscape. The waves of change are upon us, and with edge computing as our compass, the journey will be both transformative and promising. Supporting the maritime sector, SixSq is driving positive change, navigating the seas towards a safer, more efficient, and environmentally conscious future.</p>

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
      <p><a href="https://unctad.org/publication/review-maritime-transport-2021#:~:text=Maritime%20transport%20is%20the%20backbone,higher%20for%20most%20developing%20countries.">Review of Maritime Transport</a> <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Rebecca Schenato</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="edge" /><category term="logistics" /><category term="shipping" /><category term="safety" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maritime commerce has been widely used throughout history and has grown in importance to the point where it’s now responsible for 80% of the world’s trade 1. Over the years, the maritime industry has faced multiple challenges, but arguably none greater than today, with thw environmental, escalating costs and safety issues causing concern to operators. Edge computing is able to address these challenges and emerges as an essential innovation for maritime logistics, promising to revolutionize the way we navigate the seas. Keeping Tabs on Containers and Codes In the vast expanse of the ocean, the fear of lost containers is a significant concern. Edge computing tackles this issue by enabling advanced tracking systems that provide real-time insights into container movements. Equipped with sophisticated sensors and cameras, these systems read alphanumeric codes on containers, offering precise information about their location and contents. This not only prevents losses but also enhances supply chain visibility. Monitoring Container Movements in Real Time Containers in transit face various risks, from accidental falls to physical damage. Edge computing introduces continuous monitoring of containers, instantly alerting operators to potential hazards. This proactive approach ensures a swift response to prevent accidents, falls, or displacements, safeguarding both personnel and valuable cargo. Ensuring Workers’ Safety Worker safety is a top priority in maritime operations, and edge computing plays a crucial role in ensuring compliance with safety protocols. Cameras with edge processing capabilities keep a vigilant eye, confirming that workers wear necessary safety gear, stay in designated areas, and follow safety guidelines. This not only enhances overall safety but also reduces the risk of accidents at sea. Fire Hazard Prevention and Management Potential fire hazards pose a significant threat in the maritime industry, underscoring the need for advanced safety measures. To manage this, edge computing introduces innovative solutions linked to fire detection and smoke monitoring systems. These systems are able to provide real-time insights into potential fire risks, allowing for swift response and containment. It is in fact not only possible to detect the presence of smoke but also analyze its characteristics, aiding in early fire detection. This proactive approach to fire safety is instrumental in mitigating risks, supporting both the cargo and crew. Tracking Mariner Movements and Safety Zones Understanding and managing movement of workers on ships is vital for safety. Edge computing facilitates the creation of safety zones, tracking personnel in real time and sending alerts if they venture into unsafe areas. This not only enhances safety protocols but also ensures swift and efficient evacuation procedures during emergencies. Securing Shipping Content through Weight Monitoring Edge computing supports a sturdy approach to securing goods stored in containers. By monitoring container weight before embarkation and upon disembarkation, any discrepancies indicate potential tampering. This enhances security, ensuring that the merchandise remains intact throughout the journey, minimizing the risk of theft or damage during transport. Proactive Engine Insights Understanding the intricate dynamics of a ship’s engine and its surrounding subsystems is fundamental to ensuring a smooth and secure journey. Edge computing enables crews to take a proactive approach by supporting real-time monitoring and analysis of engine performance. By leveraging the power of artificial intelligence and algorithms, the engine and its associated subsystems can be protected using anomaly detection and predictive analysis. This capability can prevent failures, accidents and breakdowns, therefore enhancing overall operational efficiency, while reducing operational costs. Towards a Greener Horizon Beyond safety and efficiency, edge computing contributes to environmental sustainability. By preventing lost-at-sea containers and implementing efficient monitoring systems, it minimizes ocean pollution and encourages responsible maritime practices. The result is a more eco-friendly and conscientious approach to navigating the high seas. SixSq and its Impact in the Maritime Industry SixSq stands at the forefront of positive transformation through its innovative edge computing solutions. In fact, it plays a pivotal role in enhancing the efficiency, safety, and sustainability of the maritime industry. By integrating its robust edge computing Nuvla.io platform, marketplace, and edge solution into maritime operations, SixSq facilitates seamless communication, real-time container tracking, and continuous monitoring of movements—establishing a proactive approach to safety. With a commitment to worker protection, SixSq’s solutions enforce safety compliance and contribute to creating a secure and conducive working environment. As the maritime industry embraces the power of edge computing, we find ourselves at the beginning of a new technological era. The challenges that once seemed impossible to overcome are now met with innovative solutions, creating a safer, more efficient, and environmentally conscious maritime landscape. The waves of change are upon us, and with edge computing as our compass, the journey will be both transformative and promising. Supporting the maritime sector, SixSq is driving positive change, navigating the seas towards a safer, more efficient, and environmentally conscious future. Review of Maritime Transport &#8617;]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/maritime-blog.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/maritime-blog.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">SixSq Welcomes its Global Sales Director</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/11/20/news-sixsq-global-sales-director.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SixSq Welcomes its Global Sales Director" /><published>2023-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/news/2023/11/20/news-sixsq-global-sales-director</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/11/20/news-sixsq-global-sales-director.html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="damien-defer-joins-the-team-as-global-sales-director-for-sixsq">Damien Defer joins the team as Global Sales Director for SixSq</h3>

<p><strong>Geneva, 20th November 2023</strong> - It is with great pleasure that SixSq, an Ekinops company, can announce that <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/damien-defer-2784905/">Damien Defer</a> has been appointed to fill the new position of <strong>Global Sales Director</strong>. Damien joined the team on 20th November 2023 and is located in Paris, France. He will be responsible for leading the sales organisation globally.</p>

<p>Damien has extensive experience in sales and strategic business development as well as an international perspective. He brings over 15 year’s knowledge of the IT industry and an impressive track record, both in Europe and North America, placing him in an excellent position to drive growth for the company and provide a high-quality service to our global customers.</p>

<p>Commenting on his appointment, Damien said, <em>“I’m delighted to join the SixSq team and the <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/">Ekinops</a> family at the same time. The <a href="/platform">Nuvla.io</a> solution is generating a lot of interest across both enterprises and communication service providers (CSP). Our unique Application Marketplace helps end-customers to click and deploy public or private apps, across thousands of sites, on devices managed by them or by CSPs. The solution provides seamless container management between the sites, datacentres and Clouds.”</em></p>

<p>SixSq CEO, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mebster/">Marc-Elian Bégin</a> said, <em>“Damien brings not only a wealth of experience, but also the right mindset for our fast-moving sector of edge computing. I’m really looking forward to working with Damien to strengthen our sales, and partnerships, in order to accelerate our growth.”</em></p>

<p>With this addition to the sales team, SixSq shows it commitment to meeting the growing demand for software services in the edge computing space.</p>

<h4 id="contact">Contact</h4>

<p><strong>Damien Defer</strong>
 <br />
SixSq Global Sales Director
 <br />
damien.defer@sixsq.com
 <br />
+33 6 89 9948 52</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Damien Defer joins the team as Global Sales Director for SixSq Geneva, 20th November 2023 - It is with great pleasure that SixSq, an Ekinops company, can announce that Damien Defer has been appointed to fill the new position of Global Sales Director. Damien joined the team on 20th November 2023 and is located in Paris, France. He will be responsible for leading the sales organisation globally. Damien has extensive experience in sales and strategic business development as well as an international perspective. He brings over 15 year’s knowledge of the IT industry and an impressive track record, both in Europe and North America, placing him in an excellent position to drive growth for the company and provide a high-quality service to our global customers. Commenting on his appointment, Damien said, “I’m delighted to join the SixSq team and the Ekinops family at the same time. The Nuvla.io solution is generating a lot of interest across both enterprises and communication service providers (CSP). Our unique Application Marketplace helps end-customers to click and deploy public or private apps, across thousands of sites, on devices managed by them or by CSPs. The solution provides seamless container management between the sites, datacentres and Clouds.” SixSq CEO, Marc-Elian Bégin said, “Damien brings not only a wealth of experience, but also the right mindset for our fast-moving sector of edge computing. I’m really looking forward to working with Damien to strengthen our sales, and partnerships, in order to accelerate our growth.” With this addition to the sales team, SixSq shows it commitment to meeting the growing demand for software services in the edge computing space. Contact Damien Defer SixSq Global Sales Director damien.defer@sixsq.com +33 6 89 9948 52]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/news-damien.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/news-damien.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Leveraging Edge Computing for Enhanced Transportation Services</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/11/17/leveraging-edge-computing-for-enhanced-transportation-services.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Leveraging Edge Computing for Enhanced Transportation Services" /><published>2023-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/11/17/leveraging-edge-computing-for-enhanced-transportation-services</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/11/17/leveraging-edge-computing-for-enhanced-transportation-services.html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>The transportation industry is in a constant state of evolution, compelled by the ever-increasing need for efficiency, safety, and passenger satisfaction.</strong></p>

<p>Like many people-centric industries, transportation is facing challenges due to rising costs, staff shortages and evolving passenger demands. The drive to improve safety, traveller satisfaction, and operational efficiency are elements that push transport providers to find new ways to improve their services and offerings. The key to success in this dynamic field lies in harnessing revolutionizing technologies such as <a href="/blog/discover/2019/11/08/what-is-edge-computing">edge computing</a>, an innovative yet proven technology that optimises data processing, to provide efficient, safe, and attractive services.</p>

<h3 id="understanding-the-transportation-landscape">Understanding the Transportation Landscape</h3>

<p>To appreciate the benefits of edge computing in transportation, it is essential to grasp the multifaceted nature of the industry. The transportation network is of course not only about vehicles, but also a multitude of other elements such as stops, tram and train lines, ticket machines, traffic signals, all of which serve as critical points in the transportation business.  Thanks to edge computing, all of these key areas can be equipped with sensors, data processing capabilities and connectivity, thereby providing actionable insights to improve communication, security and passenger services. A sudden problem can cause delays throughout the network and quickly become costly. Edge computing can highlight the problem right away, limiting any damage.</p>

<p>Furthermore, in this intricate landscape, it is fundamental not to forget stakeholders’ needs. To understand this better, we will look in more detail at the main stakeholders in this industry.</p>

<h4 id="passengers">Passengers:</h4>
<p>Modern travellers are looking for a more complete and tailored experience, and not just a means of transport from point A to point B. Passengers usually carry a smartphone in their pocket and expect access to features like real-time updates on routes, schedules, and disruptions, to ensure their journey is as smooth as possible. Getting timely notifications about specific events or issues during their ride allows passengers to stay informed and secure throughout their journey, ensuring them a more comfortable ride. 
For an even more enjoyable experience, passengers appreciate on-board entertainment that can be seamlessly provided during transits.</p>

<p>Another aspect that is valued by passengers and which improves their journey experience is the convenience of digital ticketing solutions, which simplify the process of buying and using tickets.</p>

<h4 id="drivers">Drivers:</h4>
<p>Drivers’ primary responsibility is safety, while ensuring a punctual service. This requires them to have easy cockpit access to consolidated dashboards and alerts, allowing fast examination of key metrics needed for optimal driving. 
For safety reasons, drivers require data presented in a format that is easy to understand, and that does not distract them from their main driving activity. This is why prompt notifications about critical events, affecting both passengers and crew, are fundamental features. For this support to work, it is important to have high quality data to feed into the system.</p>

<h4 id="service-providers-and-operators">Service providers and operators:</h4>
<p>Transportation service providers and vehicle operators need data to optimise operations, manage resources, and ensure passengers’ well-being. This includes vehicle location, performance, passenger volumes, punctuality, embark/disembark timings, issue detection, and risk assessment. This data enhances service reliability, informs planning, and improves passenger safety. Companies like <a href="https://www.tpg.ch/">tpg</a> in Geneva are already leveraging data gathered by sensors along the network via their <a href="https://opendata.tpg.ch/pages/accueil/">Open Data Portal</a>.  This wealth of published data provides transparency to users and informs the operator’s decision making.</p>

<p>Exceptional event detection and real-time notifications are crucial for an effective response. However, protecting confidential data from hacking is essential, and this is why implementing cybersecurity measures is of fundamental importance, as is respecting data privacy laws.</p>

<p>Enhancing the IT infrastructure behind public transportation to deliver more efficient and safe services is a big challenge. <a href="/platform">Nuvla.io</a>, the innovative infrastructure of SixSq, an Ekinops company, reduces complexity and can be implemented alongside existing systems to respond to needs of the transport landscape and stakeholders alike.</p>

<h3 id="a-comprehensive-suite-of-edge-applications">A Comprehensive Suite of Edge Applications</h3>
<p>Nuvla.io provides a <a href="/marketplace">marketplace</a>, offering a diverse suite of containerised edge applications that seamlessly integrate into the transportation ecosystem. These applications can be packaged as tailored bouquets of apps, catering to a wide range of needs. These apps can be selected from the marketplace, but also from the customers own portfolio of apps, or third party. Here is an example of a bouquet of apps:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Publicity and Media: Engaging passengers with relevant content and advertisements, enhancing the travel experience.</li>
  <li>Video Analytics: Enhancing security and providing valuable insights for both safety and operational efficiency, while respecting privacy.</li>
  <li>Accounting: Streamlining financial processes and ensuring transparent financial management.</li>
  <li>Statistics (GDPR Compliant): Providing key and actionable metrics on vehicle and passenger statistics, behavior, and patterns, while protecting data privacy, a critical consideration in today’s digital age.</li>
  <li>Data Fusion (at Cockpit level): Providing consolidated information for drivers, allowing for more informed decision-making.</li>
  <li>Cybersecurity: Delivering sustained protection systems against cyberattacks while protecting the network and data from theft, damage, or unauthorized access, safeguarding digital assets.</li>
</ul>

<p>Nuvla.io’s portfolio includes solutions like <a href="https://parquery.com/">Parqueray</a> for GDPR video analytics, <a href="https://kadiska.com/">Kadiska</a> for digital experience monitoring, <a href="https://edgelabs.ai/">AI EdgeLabs</a> for cyber defense, and private apps for ticket distribution and media publicity, among others. We are also working with partners such as Spinetix for data fusion and display. This versatile ecosystem empowers transportation companies to tailor their offerings to meet their specific requirements.</p>

<p>Nuvla.io is spearheading innovation in the transportation industry with its edge computing solutions. By meeting the diverse needs of passengers, drivers, and operators, and by addressing industry challenges, these solutions are poised to transform the transportation sector. With a bouquet of versatile applications and a robust infrastructure, the future of transportation is not just efficient, it is smart, secure, and passenger-centric. Finally, transport companies can integrate Nuvla.io simply and efficiently, without risk, in order to generate incremental value, while saving costs.</p>]]></content><author><name>Rebecca Schenato</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="edge" /><category term="transport" /><category term="public-transport" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The transportation industry is in a constant state of evolution, compelled by the ever-increasing need for efficiency, safety, and passenger satisfaction. Like many people-centric industries, transportation is facing challenges due to rising costs, staff shortages and evolving passenger demands. The drive to improve safety, traveller satisfaction, and operational efficiency are elements that push transport providers to find new ways to improve their services and offerings. The key to success in this dynamic field lies in harnessing revolutionizing technologies such as edge computing, an innovative yet proven technology that optimises data processing, to provide efficient, safe, and attractive services. Understanding the Transportation Landscape To appreciate the benefits of edge computing in transportation, it is essential to grasp the multifaceted nature of the industry. The transportation network is of course not only about vehicles, but also a multitude of other elements such as stops, tram and train lines, ticket machines, traffic signals, all of which serve as critical points in the transportation business. Thanks to edge computing, all of these key areas can be equipped with sensors, data processing capabilities and connectivity, thereby providing actionable insights to improve communication, security and passenger services. A sudden problem can cause delays throughout the network and quickly become costly. Edge computing can highlight the problem right away, limiting any damage. Furthermore, in this intricate landscape, it is fundamental not to forget stakeholders’ needs. To understand this better, we will look in more detail at the main stakeholders in this industry. Passengers: Modern travellers are looking for a more complete and tailored experience, and not just a means of transport from point A to point B. Passengers usually carry a smartphone in their pocket and expect access to features like real-time updates on routes, schedules, and disruptions, to ensure their journey is as smooth as possible. Getting timely notifications about specific events or issues during their ride allows passengers to stay informed and secure throughout their journey, ensuring them a more comfortable ride. For an even more enjoyable experience, passengers appreciate on-board entertainment that can be seamlessly provided during transits. Another aspect that is valued by passengers and which improves their journey experience is the convenience of digital ticketing solutions, which simplify the process of buying and using tickets. Drivers: Drivers’ primary responsibility is safety, while ensuring a punctual service. This requires them to have easy cockpit access to consolidated dashboards and alerts, allowing fast examination of key metrics needed for optimal driving. For safety reasons, drivers require data presented in a format that is easy to understand, and that does not distract them from their main driving activity. This is why prompt notifications about critical events, affecting both passengers and crew, are fundamental features. For this support to work, it is important to have high quality data to feed into the system. Service providers and operators: Transportation service providers and vehicle operators need data to optimise operations, manage resources, and ensure passengers’ well-being. This includes vehicle location, performance, passenger volumes, punctuality, embark/disembark timings, issue detection, and risk assessment. This data enhances service reliability, informs planning, and improves passenger safety. Companies like tpg in Geneva are already leveraging data gathered by sensors along the network via their Open Data Portal. This wealth of published data provides transparency to users and informs the operator’s decision making. Exceptional event detection and real-time notifications are crucial for an effective response. However, protecting confidential data from hacking is essential, and this is why implementing cybersecurity measures is of fundamental importance, as is respecting data privacy laws. Enhancing the IT infrastructure behind public transportation to deliver more efficient and safe services is a big challenge. Nuvla.io, the innovative infrastructure of SixSq, an Ekinops company, reduces complexity and can be implemented alongside existing systems to respond to needs of the transport landscape and stakeholders alike. A Comprehensive Suite of Edge Applications Nuvla.io provides a marketplace, offering a diverse suite of containerised edge applications that seamlessly integrate into the transportation ecosystem. These applications can be packaged as tailored bouquets of apps, catering to a wide range of needs. These apps can be selected from the marketplace, but also from the customers own portfolio of apps, or third party. Here is an example of a bouquet of apps: Publicity and Media: Engaging passengers with relevant content and advertisements, enhancing the travel experience. Video Analytics: Enhancing security and providing valuable insights for both safety and operational efficiency, while respecting privacy. Accounting: Streamlining financial processes and ensuring transparent financial management. Statistics (GDPR Compliant): Providing key and actionable metrics on vehicle and passenger statistics, behavior, and patterns, while protecting data privacy, a critical consideration in today’s digital age. Data Fusion (at Cockpit level): Providing consolidated information for drivers, allowing for more informed decision-making. Cybersecurity: Delivering sustained protection systems against cyberattacks while protecting the network and data from theft, damage, or unauthorized access, safeguarding digital assets. Nuvla.io’s portfolio includes solutions like Parqueray for GDPR video analytics, Kadiska for digital experience monitoring, AI EdgeLabs for cyber defense, and private apps for ticket distribution and media publicity, among others. We are also working with partners such as Spinetix for data fusion and display. This versatile ecosystem empowers transportation companies to tailor their offerings to meet their specific requirements. Nuvla.io is spearheading innovation in the transportation industry with its edge computing solutions. By meeting the diverse needs of passengers, drivers, and operators, and by addressing industry challenges, these solutions are poised to transform the transportation sector. With a bouquet of versatile applications and a robust infrastructure, the future of transportation is not just efficient, it is smart, secure, and passenger-centric. Finally, transport companies can integrate Nuvla.io simply and efficiently, without risk, in order to generate incremental value, while saving costs.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/transport-blog.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/transport-blog.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">SixSq and CYSEC combine expertise to deliver secure edge computing solution</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/10/16/news-sixsq-and-cysec-partnership.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SixSq and CYSEC combine expertise to deliver secure edge computing solution" /><published>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/news/2023/10/16/news-sixsq-and-cysec-partnership</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/10/16/news-sixsq-and-cysec-partnership.html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Geneva, October 16th, 2023</strong> - SixSq SA, an Ekinops company, and CYSEC are thrilled to announce their partnership, combining SixSq’s expertise in providing edge computing solutions with CYSEC’s pioneering work in container security and trusted environments.</p>

<p>With edge computing and cyber security taking increasingly critical roles in operating IoT environments in critical infrastructures, companies recognise the need for inclusive solutions. This partnership represents a significant step towards simplifying edge computing security, giving customers a competitive advantage in a rapidly evolving technology landscape.</p>

<p>The combined solution builds on <a href="https://www.cysec.com/arca/">CYSEC’s Operating System (ARCA Trusted OS)</a>, an immutable operating system with minimum attack surface and secure container orchestration. It is designed to contain system intrusions and prevent data compromise across on-premise, cloud, and edge environments. The only way to modify this operating system is by deploying containers, a widely adopted, standardised and portable software format. <a href="/platform">Nuvla.io</a>, SixSq’s edge computing B2B platform-as-a-service, enables a controlled and predictable workflow to ensure the right containerised apps are deployed at the right time and in the right place. The platform is future-proof, container-native, cloud-neutral, and hardware-agnostic and includes a marketplace of containerised applications.</p>

<p>Together, SixSq and CYSEC ensure that IoT environments for critical infrastructures can now take full advantage of the flexibility of container technologies, without compromise on security. The solution seamlessly integrates with major cloud vendors and is certified for both ARM and x86 architectures, ensuring a trusted environment while safeguarding data and intellectual property against attack propagation and confidentiality breaches.</p>

<p><em>“We are excited about our partnership with CYSEC,”</em> said <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mebster/">Marc-Elian Bégin</a>, CEO and Co-founder at SixSq. <em>“By combining SixSq’s Nuvla.io platform with CYSEC’s cutting-edge container-native, secured operating system, we aim to provide unparalleled edge computing security and peace of mind for organisations operating critical infrastructures.”</em></p>

<p><em>“CYSEC is thrilled to join forces with SixSq,”</em> added <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/patrick-trinkler-4416412/">Patrick Trinkler</a>, CEO and Co-founder at CYSEC. <em>“Our joint offering will empower organizations to harness the potential of edge computing and container technology in trusted environments.”</em></p>

<p>For more information about this partnership and the solutions offered by SixSq and CYSEC, please visit:</p>

<p><a href="https://www.cysec.com/">CYSEC</a>
 <br />
<a href="https://www.cysec.com/arca/">ARCA Trusted OS</a>
<br />
<a href="https://sixsq.com/">SixSq.com</a>
<br />
<a href="/platform">Nuvla.io</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Geneva, October 16th, 2023 - SixSq SA, an Ekinops company, and CYSEC are thrilled to announce their partnership, combining SixSq’s expertise in providing edge computing solutions with CYSEC’s pioneering work in container security and trusted environments. With edge computing and cyber security taking increasingly critical roles in operating IoT environments in critical infrastructures, companies recognise the need for inclusive solutions. This partnership represents a significant step towards simplifying edge computing security, giving customers a competitive advantage in a rapidly evolving technology landscape. The combined solution builds on CYSEC’s Operating System (ARCA Trusted OS), an immutable operating system with minimum attack surface and secure container orchestration. It is designed to contain system intrusions and prevent data compromise across on-premise, cloud, and edge environments. The only way to modify this operating system is by deploying containers, a widely adopted, standardised and portable software format. Nuvla.io, SixSq’s edge computing B2B platform-as-a-service, enables a controlled and predictable workflow to ensure the right containerised apps are deployed at the right time and in the right place. The platform is future-proof, container-native, cloud-neutral, and hardware-agnostic and includes a marketplace of containerised applications. Together, SixSq and CYSEC ensure that IoT environments for critical infrastructures can now take full advantage of the flexibility of container technologies, without compromise on security. The solution seamlessly integrates with major cloud vendors and is certified for both ARM and x86 architectures, ensuring a trusted environment while safeguarding data and intellectual property against attack propagation and confidentiality breaches. “We are excited about our partnership with CYSEC,” said Marc-Elian Bégin, CEO and Co-founder at SixSq. “By combining SixSq’s Nuvla.io platform with CYSEC’s cutting-edge container-native, secured operating system, we aim to provide unparalleled edge computing security and peace of mind for organisations operating critical infrastructures.” “CYSEC is thrilled to join forces with SixSq,” added Patrick Trinkler, CEO and Co-founder at CYSEC. “Our joint offering will empower organizations to harness the potential of edge computing and container technology in trusted environments.” For more information about this partnership and the solutions offered by SixSq and CYSEC, please visit: CYSEC ARCA Trusted OS SixSq.com Nuvla.io]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/cysec-partnership.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/cysec-partnership.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Revolutionizing enterprise telco services with edge computing</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/10/10/revolutionizing-enterprise-telco-services-with-edge-computing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Revolutionizing enterprise telco services with edge computing" /><published>2023-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/10/10/revolutionizing-enterprise-telco-services-with-edge-computing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/10/10/revolutionizing-enterprise-telco-services-with-edge-computing.html"><![CDATA[<p>Given that providing network services and connectivity is no longer enough due to internet platforms and smartphones, telco companies are faced with the need to adapt to a changing digital landscape, with increased demand for faster and more secure ecosystems. Tech giants, OTT players, and hyperscalers are disrupting the market with their infrastructure and innovation, forcing telcos to reevaluate their business models. This is not the first time the industry has experienced a seismic shift, but this time service providers must act rapidly to stay relevant and improve revenue and margin in the current market.</p>

<p>Thankfully there is an innovative way to transform services which, if approached with the right tools, provides a way to <strong>reduce risk, decrease costs and remove complexity</strong>, finding a balance between tradition and adapting to stay competitive in this evolving landscape.</p>

<h3 id="edge-computing-delivers-innovative-solutions">Edge computing delivers innovative solutions</h3>

<p>The emergence of <strong><a href="/blog/discover/2019/11/08/what-is-edge-computing">edge computing</a></strong> provides a unique opportunity for telcos to revolutionize their offering, presenting innovative solutions that suit the diverse needs of multiple industries. Through the integration of edge computing, telcos can effectively address a multitude of challenges for both wired and mobile networks.
Within the sphere of the telco industry, service providers are in constant pursuit of enhancing the quality and security of their services. Through the power of edge computing, telcos can introduce cutting-edge monitoring solutions that offer real-time insights into network performance. This, in turn, empowers proactive maintenance and rapid issue resolution. Furthermore, edge-based cybersecurity mechanisms can swiftly identify and mitigate potential security threats, thereby ensuring the integrity of data and fostering user trust. Moreover, the minimized latency achieved through edge computing significantly optimizes service delivery, resulting in elevated user experiences.</p>

<h3 id="a-customer-centric-approach">A customer-centric approach</h3>

<p>The pursuit of innovation, however, shouldn’t only focus on understanding the needs of telcos themselves; it’s equally important to understand the aspirations of telco customers and how edge computing can support them and their businesses. Edge computing empowers telcos to offer solutions that appeal to a wide range of sectors, including:</p>

<h4 id="logistics--shipping">Logistics &amp; shipping:</h4>

<p>In Logistics and shipping, edge computing aims at enhancing worker safety in industrial settings through AI-driven safety monitoring. It also improves product tracking and inventory management, while using edge-based analytics to facilitate accurate supply chain management.</p>

<h4 id="retail-and-transport">Retail and transport:</h4>

<p>In the retail and transport verticals, edge computing provides anonymized video services with no privacy intrusion, while still delivering insights for business operations.</p>

<h4 id="manufacturing">Manufacturing:</h4>

<p>For manufacturing, edge integrates predictive analytics to contribute to decision-making processes.</p>

<p>Moreover, edge computing delivers robust <strong>cybersecurity</strong> measures embedded in edge solutions to safeguard data security across all business operations.</p>

<p>In addition to all of this, edge computing is also able to tackle the challenge of providing efficient solutions for managing and scaling containerized applications. In fact, edge computing emerges as a powerful solution to this problem, streamlining the complexity associated with handling these applications while supporting operational and resource demands.</p>

<p>Other customers are on the lookout for a more all-rounded ecosystem that allows them to manage all applications needed to deliver a complete and tailored solution to their problems. The idea centers around integrating a comprehensive marketplace with containerized app management. The answer to this need comes in the form of <a href="/platform">Nuvla.io</a>, an integrated platform from SixSq that facilitates seamless access to a diverse range of applications, coupled with streamlined management and scalability options.</p>

<p>In essence, edge computing can drive a transformation within the telco industry, enabling providers to introduce innovative solutions that cater to a wide spectrum of requirements spanning wired and mobile networks. Through the utilization of SixSq’s Nuvla.io ecosystem, telcos can push their services to new heights, enhancing performance, security, and efficiency. From <strong>cutting-edge monitoring</strong> and <strong>cybersecurity</strong> to <strong>AI-driven video analysis</strong>, the possibilities are endless. As the telco landscape continues to evolve, embracing edge computing is no longer an option—it’s a necessity for staying ahead in the digital age.</p>]]></content><author><name>Rebecca Schenato</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="edge" /><category term="telco" /><category term="networks" /><category term="telecommunications" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Given that providing network services and connectivity is no longer enough due to internet platforms and smartphones, telco companies are faced with the need to adapt to a changing digital landscape, with increased demand for faster and more secure ecosystems. Tech giants, OTT players, and hyperscalers are disrupting the market with their infrastructure and innovation, forcing telcos to reevaluate their business models. This is not the first time the industry has experienced a seismic shift, but this time service providers must act rapidly to stay relevant and improve revenue and margin in the current market. Thankfully there is an innovative way to transform services which, if approached with the right tools, provides a way to reduce risk, decrease costs and remove complexity, finding a balance between tradition and adapting to stay competitive in this evolving landscape. Edge computing delivers innovative solutions The emergence of edge computing provides a unique opportunity for telcos to revolutionize their offering, presenting innovative solutions that suit the diverse needs of multiple industries. Through the integration of edge computing, telcos can effectively address a multitude of challenges for both wired and mobile networks. Within the sphere of the telco industry, service providers are in constant pursuit of enhancing the quality and security of their services. Through the power of edge computing, telcos can introduce cutting-edge monitoring solutions that offer real-time insights into network performance. This, in turn, empowers proactive maintenance and rapid issue resolution. Furthermore, edge-based cybersecurity mechanisms can swiftly identify and mitigate potential security threats, thereby ensuring the integrity of data and fostering user trust. Moreover, the minimized latency achieved through edge computing significantly optimizes service delivery, resulting in elevated user experiences. A customer-centric approach The pursuit of innovation, however, shouldn’t only focus on understanding the needs of telcos themselves; it’s equally important to understand the aspirations of telco customers and how edge computing can support them and their businesses. Edge computing empowers telcos to offer solutions that appeal to a wide range of sectors, including: Logistics &amp; shipping: In Logistics and shipping, edge computing aims at enhancing worker safety in industrial settings through AI-driven safety monitoring. It also improves product tracking and inventory management, while using edge-based analytics to facilitate accurate supply chain management. Retail and transport: In the retail and transport verticals, edge computing provides anonymized video services with no privacy intrusion, while still delivering insights for business operations. Manufacturing: For manufacturing, edge integrates predictive analytics to contribute to decision-making processes. Moreover, edge computing delivers robust cybersecurity measures embedded in edge solutions to safeguard data security across all business operations. In addition to all of this, edge computing is also able to tackle the challenge of providing efficient solutions for managing and scaling containerized applications. In fact, edge computing emerges as a powerful solution to this problem, streamlining the complexity associated with handling these applications while supporting operational and resource demands. Other customers are on the lookout for a more all-rounded ecosystem that allows them to manage all applications needed to deliver a complete and tailored solution to their problems. The idea centers around integrating a comprehensive marketplace with containerized app management. The answer to this need comes in the form of Nuvla.io, an integrated platform from SixSq that facilitates seamless access to a diverse range of applications, coupled with streamlined management and scalability options. In essence, edge computing can drive a transformation within the telco industry, enabling providers to introduce innovative solutions that cater to a wide spectrum of requirements spanning wired and mobile networks. Through the utilization of SixSq’s Nuvla.io ecosystem, telcos can push their services to new heights, enhancing performance, security, and efficiency. From cutting-edge monitoring and cybersecurity to AI-driven video analysis, the possibilities are endless. As the telco landscape continues to evolve, embracing edge computing is no longer an option—it’s a necessity for staying ahead in the digital age.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/telco-blog.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/telco-blog.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Redefining logistics and shipping with edge computing</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/08/23/redefining-logistics-and-shipping-with-edge-computing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Redefining logistics and shipping with edge computing" /><published>2023-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/08/23/redefining-logistics-and-shipping-with-edge-computing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/08/23/redefining-logistics-and-shipping-with-edge-computing.html"><![CDATA[<p>The efficient management of logistics and shipping operations relies on the smooth coordination of multiple tasks, including warehouse operations, product &amp; parcel tracking, and workplace safety, all in a dynamic environment. To achieve these goals, logistics and shipping centers can leverage the power of <strong><a href="/blog/discover/2019/11/08/what-is-edge-computing">edge computing</a></strong>, an innovative technology that optimizes data processing and provides a safer workplace while respecting workers’ privacy and anonymity.</p>

<h3 id="real-time-tracking-and-monitoring-for-enhanced-safety">Real-time tracking and monitoring for enhanced safety</h3>

<p>In any complex working environment, the safety of workers is of fundamental importance. By deploying edge devices and sensors in strategic locations throughout the workplace, warehouses and centers can process data on worker movements, safety compliance, environmental conditions, risky behavior, and potential hazards in <strong>real-time</strong>.</p>

<p>With edge computing, this data can be processed close to the action, reducing latency and minimizing the reliance on cloud or centralized servers. By utilizing advanced analytics and machine learning algorithms at the edge, safety issues, such as collisions, falls, or hazardous maneuvers, can be identified and frontline workers alerted in real-time. This proactive approach to safety can mitigate accidents, ensuring the well-being of workers. Meanwhile, it is of essential importance not to use these tools to discriminate against workers. This is why data anonymization is a key element of this type of solution. The aim is to spot, understand and correct potential issues, while protecting workers’ privacy.</p>

<p>In addition, this data can later be retrieved and analyzed. This helps, for example, to determine the root cause of accidents and inform future workplace planning.</p>

<h3 id="efficient-asset-tracking-for-process-optimization">Efficient asset tracking for process optimization</h3>

<p>Effective asset tracking is vital to maintaining the smooth flow of goods within logistics and shipping centers. By equipping centers with edge computing devices connected to camera sensors, it is possible to:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Efficiently track unique assets, using label character recognition, across zones</strong>.</li>
  <li><strong>Count and categorize assets within defined zones</strong>.</li>
  <li><strong>Identify and count trolleys and carts</strong>.</li>
  <li><strong>Distinguish between loaded and unloaded assets (e.g. empty or loaded containers or trolleys)</strong>.</li>
</ul>

<p>Edge devices do this by communicating with nearby sensors, such as standard cameras, to provide accurate information on the asset’s position, location, status, load charge, and much more. This data is gathered regardless of the lighting or weather conditions, both during day and night, and for both stationery and mobile assets. This information can then be used to interface with inventory systems and streamline logistics operations. Managers can then quickly identify the whereabouts of assets, ensuring efficient product flow, reducing search time, and minimizing disruptions to the supply chain.</p>

<h3 id="maintaining-privacy-and-anonymity">Maintaining privacy and anonymity</h3>

<p>While harnessing technology to optimize logistics operations, it is essential to address concerns related to data privacy and identity of individuals. Edge computing offers a decentralized approach that ensures the protection of sensitive information, such as personal data and worker identity.
By processing data at the edge, logistics and shipping centers can eliminate the transmission of personal information to the cloud or centralized servers. This can be efficiently implemented using established techniques such as tokenization. This works by replacing personally identifiable information (PII) with unique tokens, so that the operations remain efficient while maintaining anonymous identity of workers.</p>

<p>In conclusion, edge computing emerges as a game-changer in revolutionizing the logistics and shipping industry, by ensuring worker safety, efficient asset tracking, and anonymous identity. Real-time tracking and monitoring systems powered by edge computing protect warehouse workers by proactively identifying safety risks. Efficient asset tracking enhances logistics operations, minimizing delays and disruptions.</p>

<p>At the same time, edge computing addresses privacy concerns by processing data locally, employing privacy-preserving techniques, and enabling anonymous identity management. By striking a balance between operational efficiency and data protection, logistics and shipping organizations can build trust with workers and comply with privacy regulations.</p>

<p>In many cases, these practices require technical knowledge, training, and specialized personnel able to run such a digital ecosystem. Nuvla.io from SixSq was created for you not to worry about all this. Nuvla.io is a gateway to a world of tailored apps, in a unique edge-first <a href="/marketplace">marketplace</a> that serves a multitude of industries and sectors. All backed by a team of edge experts. We dedicate our efforts to providing a simple interface and enjoyable user experience, which allows anyone to operate otherwise complex edge computing systems, and at the same time avoid technology lock-in.</p>

<p>To deep dive into more tangible elements linked to your needs, visit our webpages and <a href="/contact">reach out</a> to learn how we can support your logistics and shipping transition with innovative problem solving via edge computing.</p>]]></content><author><name>Rebecca Schenato</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="edge" /><category term="logistics" /><category term="shipping" /><category term="anonymity" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The efficient management of logistics and shipping operations relies on the smooth coordination of multiple tasks, including warehouse operations, product &amp; parcel tracking, and workplace safety, all in a dynamic environment. To achieve these goals, logistics and shipping centers can leverage the power of edge computing, an innovative technology that optimizes data processing and provides a safer workplace while respecting workers’ privacy and anonymity. Real-time tracking and monitoring for enhanced safety In any complex working environment, the safety of workers is of fundamental importance. By deploying edge devices and sensors in strategic locations throughout the workplace, warehouses and centers can process data on worker movements, safety compliance, environmental conditions, risky behavior, and potential hazards in real-time. With edge computing, this data can be processed close to the action, reducing latency and minimizing the reliance on cloud or centralized servers. By utilizing advanced analytics and machine learning algorithms at the edge, safety issues, such as collisions, falls, or hazardous maneuvers, can be identified and frontline workers alerted in real-time. This proactive approach to safety can mitigate accidents, ensuring the well-being of workers. Meanwhile, it is of essential importance not to use these tools to discriminate against workers. This is why data anonymization is a key element of this type of solution. The aim is to spot, understand and correct potential issues, while protecting workers’ privacy. In addition, this data can later be retrieved and analyzed. This helps, for example, to determine the root cause of accidents and inform future workplace planning. Efficient asset tracking for process optimization Effective asset tracking is vital to maintaining the smooth flow of goods within logistics and shipping centers. By equipping centers with edge computing devices connected to camera sensors, it is possible to: Efficiently track unique assets, using label character recognition, across zones. Count and categorize assets within defined zones. Identify and count trolleys and carts. Distinguish between loaded and unloaded assets (e.g. empty or loaded containers or trolleys). Edge devices do this by communicating with nearby sensors, such as standard cameras, to provide accurate information on the asset’s position, location, status, load charge, and much more. This data is gathered regardless of the lighting or weather conditions, both during day and night, and for both stationery and mobile assets. This information can then be used to interface with inventory systems and streamline logistics operations. Managers can then quickly identify the whereabouts of assets, ensuring efficient product flow, reducing search time, and minimizing disruptions to the supply chain. Maintaining privacy and anonymity While harnessing technology to optimize logistics operations, it is essential to address concerns related to data privacy and identity of individuals. Edge computing offers a decentralized approach that ensures the protection of sensitive information, such as personal data and worker identity. By processing data at the edge, logistics and shipping centers can eliminate the transmission of personal information to the cloud or centralized servers. This can be efficiently implemented using established techniques such as tokenization. This works by replacing personally identifiable information (PII) with unique tokens, so that the operations remain efficient while maintaining anonymous identity of workers. In conclusion, edge computing emerges as a game-changer in revolutionizing the logistics and shipping industry, by ensuring worker safety, efficient asset tracking, and anonymous identity. Real-time tracking and monitoring systems powered by edge computing protect warehouse workers by proactively identifying safety risks. Efficient asset tracking enhances logistics operations, minimizing delays and disruptions. At the same time, edge computing addresses privacy concerns by processing data locally, employing privacy-preserving techniques, and enabling anonymous identity management. By striking a balance between operational efficiency and data protection, logistics and shipping organizations can build trust with workers and comply with privacy regulations. In many cases, these practices require technical knowledge, training, and specialized personnel able to run such a digital ecosystem. Nuvla.io from SixSq was created for you not to worry about all this. Nuvla.io is a gateway to a world of tailored apps, in a unique edge-first marketplace that serves a multitude of industries and sectors. All backed by a team of edge experts. We dedicate our efforts to providing a simple interface and enjoyable user experience, which allows anyone to operate otherwise complex edge computing systems, and at the same time avoid technology lock-in. To deep dive into more tangible elements linked to your needs, visit our webpages and reach out to learn how we can support your logistics and shipping transition with innovative problem solving via edge computing.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/logistics-blog.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/logistics-blog.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">4 ways edge computing can help you achieve sustainable development goals</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/07/19/edge-computing-and-sustainable-development-goals.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="4 ways edge computing can help you achieve sustainable development goals" /><published>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/07/19/edge-computing-and-sustainable-development-goals</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2023/07/19/edge-computing-and-sustainable-development-goals.html"><![CDATA[<p>In recent years, the urgency to address pressing global challenges has led to increased attention on the <a href="https://sdgs.un.org/goals">United Nations’ Sustainable Development Goals</a> (SDGs). Technological innovations such as <a href="/blog/discover/2019/11/08/what-is-edge-computing.html">edge computing</a> have emerged as promising tools to drive sustainable development. However, it is crucial for businesses to embrace edge computing with a genuine commitment to sustainability.</p>

<h3 id="but-first-what-is-edge-computing">But first… what is edge computing?</h3>

<p>Edge computing refers to the decentralized approach of processing and storing data closer to its source, at the network’s edge, rather than relying solely on centralized cloud servers. Edge computing complements cloud computing by extending its capabilities to the edge of the network, enabling faster processing, <strong>reduced latency</strong>, and enhanced data privacy. Together, edge and cloud computing create a powerful and comprehensive infrastructure that supports a wide range of applications and delivers a seamless user experience. Moreover, edge computing enables <strong>data sovereignty</strong> and business autonomy by processing and storing data locally, reducing reliance on centralized servers. This decentralized approach empowers organizations to maintain control over their data while benefiting from real-time insights and low-latency processing.</p>

<h3 id="and-what-are-the-sustainable-development-goals-sdgs">And what are the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs)?</h3>

<p>The <a href="https://sdgs.un.org/goals">Sustainable Development Goals</a> (SDGs), comprise a set of 17 interconnected objectives established by the United Nations in 2015. The SDGs serve as a universal call to action that addresses a wide range of critical global challenges and which provide a comprehensive framework to create a sustainable and equitable future.</p>

<h4 id="here-are-4-sdgs-where-edge-computing-can-make-an-impact">Here are 4 SDGs where edge computing can make an impact</h4>

<h3 id="sdg-7-affordable-and-clean-energy">SDG 7: Affordable and Clean Energy</h3>

<p><a href="https://sdgs.un.org/goals/goal7">SDG7</a> aims to ensure universal access to affordable, reliable, sustainable, and modern energy sources. Edge computing can play a pivotal role by optimizing energy consumption and enabling more efficient energy distribution. By processing data at the edge, energy management systems can minimize wasteful energy practices, identify energy-saving opportunities, and facilitate the integration of renewable energy sources into the power grid.</p>

<h3 id="sdg-9-industry-innovation-and-infrastructure">SDG 9: Industry, Innovation, and Infrastructure</h3>

<p><a href="https://sdgs.un.org/goals/goal9">SDG9</a> seeks to drive economic growth and improve the overall well-being of societies. Edge computing supports this advancement by enabling real-time monitoring, predictive maintenance, and intelligent automation in various sectors. Edge computing also facilitates the deployment of smart infrastructure, enhancing the efficiency and reliability of transportation systems, energy grids, and public services.</p>

<h3 id="sdg-11-sustainable-cities-and-communities">SDG 11: Sustainable Cities and Communities</h3>

<p><a href="https://sdgs.un.org/goals/goal11">SDG11</a> aims at making cities inclusive, safe, resilient, and sustainable by improving urban planning, ensuring access to basic services, and promoting sustainable practices for housing, transportation, and infrastructure. Edge computing contributes to this by enabling smart city solutions. Real-time data processing at the edge allows for efficient traffic management, waste management, and urban planning. By utilizing edge analytics, cities can optimize resource allocation, reduce congestion, and minimize environmental impact, leading to improved quality of life for residents.</p>

<h3 id="sdg-13-climate-action">SDG 13: Climate Action</h3>

<p><a href="https://sdgs.un.org/goals/goal13">SDG13</a> addresses the urgent need for climate action. Edge computing can support this goal by allowing precise climate monitoring. By processing data locally, organizations can reduce the need for large-scale data transfers, which often results in increased energy consumption and carbon emissions. Additionally, edge-enabled environmental monitoring systems can provide accurate and timely data on climate indicators, aiding in climate modeling, disaster response, and the development of sustainable policies.</p>

<h3 id="responsible-implementation-of-edge-computing">Responsible Implementation of Edge Computing</h3>

<p>To avoid being guilty of greenwashing and to ensure meaningful contributions to SDG achievements, companies must approach edge computing with a responsible mindset. Consider the following:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Holistic Sustainability Strategy</strong><br />
Companies should adopt a holistic sustainability strategy that aligns with their core values and business objectives. Edge computing should be integrated into this strategy as a means to drive sustainable development, rather than as a superficial marketing tool.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Energy Efficiency and Renewable Resources</strong><br />
Companies should prioritize energy-efficient hardware and infrastructure for edge computing deployments. Utilizing renewable energy sources to power edge computing systems can further reduce environmental impact and contribute to the clean energy transition.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Lifecycle Assessment</strong><br />
Performing a thorough lifecycle assessment of edge computing infrastructure is essential. This assessment should consider the environmental impact of manufacturing, deployment, operation, and end-of-life disposal of edge devices, promoting responsible consumption and production.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Collaboration and Knowledge Sharing</strong><br />
Businesses should actively participate in collaborative initiatives, industry partnerships, and knowledge-sharing platforms focused on sustainable edge computing practices. Sharing best practices, lessons learned, and research findings can foster innovation and collective progress.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Edge computing holds tremendous potential to support companies in their journey towards achievement of SDGs. By leveraging the benefits of edge computing while maintaining a responsible and genuine commitment to sustainability, businesses can drive positive change in energy efficiency, industry innovation, sustainable cities, and climate action. Embracing edge computing with a responsible mindset ensures that companies will make a tangible impact on global sustainability goals, contributing to a sustainable future.</p>

<p>As SixSq, we provide a diverse bouquet of applications in a unique edge-based <a href="/marketplace">marketplace</a> that serves a multitude of industries and sectors. We aim to provide future-proof solutions that support redeployment of existing <a href="/nuvlaedge#hardware">hardware</a> and efficient use of resources. To deep dive into more tangible elements linked to your business, visit our <a href="/industries">webpage</a> or reach out to learn how we can support your sustainable transition and innovative problem solving via edge computing.</p>]]></content><author><name>Rebecca Schenato</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="edge" /><category term="cloud" /><category term="smart-cities" /><category term="sustainability" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In recent years, the urgency to address pressing global challenges has led to increased attention on the United Nations’ Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs). Technological innovations such as edge computing have emerged as promising tools to drive sustainable development. However, it is crucial for businesses to embrace edge computing with a genuine commitment to sustainability. But first… what is edge computing? Edge computing refers to the decentralized approach of processing and storing data closer to its source, at the network’s edge, rather than relying solely on centralized cloud servers. Edge computing complements cloud computing by extending its capabilities to the edge of the network, enabling faster processing, reduced latency, and enhanced data privacy. Together, edge and cloud computing create a powerful and comprehensive infrastructure that supports a wide range of applications and delivers a seamless user experience. Moreover, edge computing enables data sovereignty and business autonomy by processing and storing data locally, reducing reliance on centralized servers. This decentralized approach empowers organizations to maintain control over their data while benefiting from real-time insights and low-latency processing. And what are the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs)? The Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), comprise a set of 17 interconnected objectives established by the United Nations in 2015. The SDGs serve as a universal call to action that addresses a wide range of critical global challenges and which provide a comprehensive framework to create a sustainable and equitable future. Here are 4 SDGs where edge computing can make an impact SDG 7: Affordable and Clean Energy SDG7 aims to ensure universal access to affordable, reliable, sustainable, and modern energy sources. Edge computing can play a pivotal role by optimizing energy consumption and enabling more efficient energy distribution. By processing data at the edge, energy management systems can minimize wasteful energy practices, identify energy-saving opportunities, and facilitate the integration of renewable energy sources into the power grid. SDG 9: Industry, Innovation, and Infrastructure SDG9 seeks to drive economic growth and improve the overall well-being of societies. Edge computing supports this advancement by enabling real-time monitoring, predictive maintenance, and intelligent automation in various sectors. Edge computing also facilitates the deployment of smart infrastructure, enhancing the efficiency and reliability of transportation systems, energy grids, and public services. SDG 11: Sustainable Cities and Communities SDG11 aims at making cities inclusive, safe, resilient, and sustainable by improving urban planning, ensuring access to basic services, and promoting sustainable practices for housing, transportation, and infrastructure. Edge computing contributes to this by enabling smart city solutions. Real-time data processing at the edge allows for efficient traffic management, waste management, and urban planning. By utilizing edge analytics, cities can optimize resource allocation, reduce congestion, and minimize environmental impact, leading to improved quality of life for residents. SDG 13: Climate Action SDG13 addresses the urgent need for climate action. Edge computing can support this goal by allowing precise climate monitoring. By processing data locally, organizations can reduce the need for large-scale data transfers, which often results in increased energy consumption and carbon emissions. Additionally, edge-enabled environmental monitoring systems can provide accurate and timely data on climate indicators, aiding in climate modeling, disaster response, and the development of sustainable policies. Responsible Implementation of Edge Computing To avoid being guilty of greenwashing and to ensure meaningful contributions to SDG achievements, companies must approach edge computing with a responsible mindset. Consider the following: Holistic Sustainability Strategy Companies should adopt a holistic sustainability strategy that aligns with their core values and business objectives. Edge computing should be integrated into this strategy as a means to drive sustainable development, rather than as a superficial marketing tool. Energy Efficiency and Renewable Resources Companies should prioritize energy-efficient hardware and infrastructure for edge computing deployments. Utilizing renewable energy sources to power edge computing systems can further reduce environmental impact and contribute to the clean energy transition. Lifecycle Assessment Performing a thorough lifecycle assessment of edge computing infrastructure is essential. This assessment should consider the environmental impact of manufacturing, deployment, operation, and end-of-life disposal of edge devices, promoting responsible consumption and production. Collaboration and Knowledge Sharing Businesses should actively participate in collaborative initiatives, industry partnerships, and knowledge-sharing platforms focused on sustainable edge computing practices. Sharing best practices, lessons learned, and research findings can foster innovation and collective progress. Edge computing holds tremendous potential to support companies in their journey towards achievement of SDGs. By leveraging the benefits of edge computing while maintaining a responsible and genuine commitment to sustainability, businesses can drive positive change in energy efficiency, industry innovation, sustainable cities, and climate action. Embracing edge computing with a responsible mindset ensures that companies will make a tangible impact on global sustainability goals, contributing to a sustainable future. As SixSq, we provide a diverse bouquet of applications in a unique edge-based marketplace that serves a multitude of industries and sectors. We aim to provide future-proof solutions that support redeployment of existing hardware and efficient use of resources. To deep dive into more tangible elements linked to your business, visit our webpage or reach out to learn how we can support your sustainable transition and innovative problem solving via edge computing.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/SDG.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/SDG.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">SixSq announces updates to the Nuvla platform and marketplace legal framework for improved business enablement</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/05/23/news-nuvla-updated-terms-and-conditions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SixSq announces updates to the Nuvla platform and marketplace legal framework for improved business enablement" /><published>2023-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/news/2023/05/23/news-nuvla-updated-terms-and-conditions</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/05/23/news-nuvla-updated-terms-and-conditions.html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Geneva, May 23rd, 2023 - SixSq SA, an Ekinops company</strong>, today announced important updates to the legal framework for the Nuvla platform and marketplace, provided by its subsidiary SixSq SA.</p>

<p><a href="https://sixsq.com/platform">Nuvla</a> is a proven B2B SaaS digital platform and marketplace for industrialization and automation of containerized edge applications and device management. Nuvla enables the deployment of these applications on the Ekinops <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/products-services/products/oneaccess">OneAccess</a> branded customer premise equipment (CPE), as well as a large range of certified hardware platforms. The Nuvla marketplace contains a growing number of ready-made apps, provided by domain matter experts (aka app vendors). These apps can be automatically deployed in 1-click to any Nuvla-enabled edges, eliminating human error and improving quality. Furthermore, users can register their own apps, creating a private app store, mixing in commercially available apps from the marketplace.</p>

<p>The simplified Terms and Conditions (T&amp;C) and End User License Agreement (EULA) make business between app vendors, customers and end users frictionless and straightforward. They also support network service providers and system integrators in generating additional recurring revenue at the edge and in the cloud.</p>

<p><strong>SixSq’s CEO Marc-Elian Bégin</strong> said, <em>“With this major update to our T&amp;C, we are bringing to edge computing the frictionless business enablement that Amazon created when they introduced cloud computing 17 years ago.”</em></p>

<p>The key highlights of the new legal framework are:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Clear terms between app vendors, the Nuvla operator (SixSq) and customers to enable frictionless business, including payments</li>
  <li>Geographical legal coverage now including Europe, North America, the Middle East and Asia Pacific</li>
  <li>Easier to read and better organized terms</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Ekinops’s CEO Didier Brédy</strong> said, <em>“Ekinops is always pushing innovation and simplicity in our industry. With this updated legal framework, we are able to offer telecom operators, as well as their enterprise &amp; SMB customers, a new and much simpler way of leveraging edge computing, building on the well-established Ekinops portfolio. This is a win-win for both Ekinops and our customers to create new revenue streams.”</em></p>

<p>The changes came into force on 11 May 2023 and users were given the opportunity to review the details before continuing to use the service.</p>

<p>The updated Terms and Conditions can be found <a href="https://sixsq.com/legal/legal-general-terms-and-conditions-v2.html">here</a>.</p>

<p>The updated standard apps EULA can be found <a href="https://sixsq.com/legal/standard-apps-eula-v2.html">here</a>.</p>

<h3 id="your-contacts">Your contacts</h3>

<p><strong>Ekinops</strong></p>

<p>For further media information, or to schedule an interview with Ekinops, please contact:
<br />
<strong>Fraser Kay</strong>
<br />
iseepr
<br />
44(0) 113 350 1922
<br />
<a href="mailto:fraser@iseepr.co.uk">fraser@iseepr.co.uk</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Geneva, May 23rd, 2023 - SixSq SA, an Ekinops company, today announced important updates to the legal framework for the Nuvla platform and marketplace, provided by its subsidiary SixSq SA. Nuvla is a proven B2B SaaS digital platform and marketplace for industrialization and automation of containerized edge applications and device management. Nuvla enables the deployment of these applications on the Ekinops OneAccess branded customer premise equipment (CPE), as well as a large range of certified hardware platforms. The Nuvla marketplace contains a growing number of ready-made apps, provided by domain matter experts (aka app vendors). These apps can be automatically deployed in 1-click to any Nuvla-enabled edges, eliminating human error and improving quality. Furthermore, users can register their own apps, creating a private app store, mixing in commercially available apps from the marketplace. The simplified Terms and Conditions (T&amp;C) and End User License Agreement (EULA) make business between app vendors, customers and end users frictionless and straightforward. They also support network service providers and system integrators in generating additional recurring revenue at the edge and in the cloud. SixSq’s CEO Marc-Elian Bégin said, “With this major update to our T&amp;C, we are bringing to edge computing the frictionless business enablement that Amazon created when they introduced cloud computing 17 years ago.” The key highlights of the new legal framework are: Clear terms between app vendors, the Nuvla operator (SixSq) and customers to enable frictionless business, including payments Geographical legal coverage now including Europe, North America, the Middle East and Asia Pacific Easier to read and better organized terms Ekinops’s CEO Didier Brédy said, “Ekinops is always pushing innovation and simplicity in our industry. With this updated legal framework, we are able to offer telecom operators, as well as their enterprise &amp; SMB customers, a new and much simpler way of leveraging edge computing, building on the well-established Ekinops portfolio. This is a win-win for both Ekinops and our customers to create new revenue streams.” The changes came into force on 11 May 2023 and users were given the opportunity to review the details before continuing to use the service. The updated Terms and Conditions can be found here. The updated standard apps EULA can be found here. Your contacts Ekinops For further media information, or to schedule an interview with Ekinops, please contact: Fraser Kay iseepr 44(0) 113 350 1922 fraser@iseepr.co.uk]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/legal-nuvla-tc.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/legal-nuvla-tc.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Pushing the edge-to-cloud continuum with Horizon Europe</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/05/09/news-horizon-europe.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pushing the edge-to-cloud continuum with Horizon Europe" /><published>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/news/2023/05/09/news-horizon-europe</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/05/09/news-horizon-europe.html"><![CDATA[<p>SixSq is proud to be part of 3 new <a href="https://research-and-innovation.ec.europa.eu/funding/funding-opportunities/funding-programmes-and-open-calls/horizon-europe_en?utm_source=hs_email&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;_hsenc=p2ANqtz-_ADIcfTzwAg6q5_ZHWG0WnKO7fayNUFoOvu3MwVWQpcmCYv8T1gAZUyyJdcrLizxfHPxbq">Horizon Europe</a> projects, thanks to funding from the Swiss government agency <a href="https://www.sbfi.admin.ch/sbfi/en/home.html">SEFRI</a>, which supports Swiss participation in the EU Framework Programme. The projects will give the team the opportunity of working with the very best innovators in Europe to keep SixSq software and services at the cutting edge of technology. All of the 3-year projects focus on computer architecture in the edge-to-cloud space and will be tested via concrete use cases across a wide range of sectors.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://sixsq.com/rd/icos.html?utm_source=hs_email&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;_hsenc=p2ANqtz-_ADIcfTzwAg6q5_ZHWG0WnKO7fayNUFoOvu3MwVWQpcmCYv8T1gAZUyyJdcrLizxfHPxbq">ICOS</a> is designing an AI-powered continuum which is open, secure, adaptable and technology-agnostic. The solution will be tested via <a href="https://www.icos-project.eu/use-cases">4 use cases</a> in the fields of agriculture, multimedia systems, railway infrastructure monitoring and energy mangement.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://sixsq.com/rd/extract.html">EXTRACT</a> aims to develop a data-mining platform for extreme data, leveraging the knowledge of 10 Consortium partners around two interesting use cases: personalised evacuation routing in case of emergency and transforming huge volumes of raw data from radio-telescopes into high quality reusable datasets for use in 15 different scientific domains.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The <a href="https://sixsq.com/rd/aces.html">ACES</a> edge-to-cloud framework will be able of managing itself in terms of workload placement, service and resource management, as well as data and policy management, thanks to AI capabilities.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Participaton in these projects confirms SixSq’s commitment to delivering the most innovative solutions to its customers.</p>

<h3 id="useful-links">Useful links</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.icos-project.eu/">ICOS website</a></p>

<p><a href="https://extract-project.eu/">EXTRACT website</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.aces-edge.eu/">ACES website</a></p>

<p>For a bit of background reading on <strong>edge and cloud computing</strong>, take a look at our <a href="/blog">blog</a> page.</p>

<h3 id="funding">Funding</h3>

<p>The ICOS project is funded through from the European Union’s <a href="https://research-and-innovation.ec.europa.eu/funding/funding-opportunities/funding-programmes-and-open-calls/horizon-europe_en">HORIZON EUROPE</a> research and innovation programme under grant agreement No 101070177. SixSq is funded by SERI under contract number 22.00262.</p>

<p>The EXTRACT project is funded through from the European Union’s <a href="https://research-and-innovation.ec.europa.eu/funding/funding-opportunities/funding-programmes-and-open-calls/horizon-europe_en">HORIZON EUROPE</a> research and innovation programme under grant agreement No 101093110. SixSq is funded by <a href="https://www.sbfi.admin.ch/sbfi/en/home.html">SEFRI</a>.</p>

<p>The ACES project is funded through from the European Union’s <a href="https://research-and-innovation.ec.europa.eu/funding/funding-opportunities/funding-programmes-and-open-calls/horizon-europe_en">HORIZON EUROPE</a> research and innovation programme under grant agreement No 101093126. SixSq is funded by <a href="https://www.sbfi.admin.ch/sbfi/en/home.html">SEFRI</a> under contract number 22.00532.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[SixSq is proud to be part of 3 new Horizon Europe projects, thanks to funding from the Swiss government agency SEFRI, which supports Swiss participation in the EU Framework Programme. The projects will give the team the opportunity of working with the very best innovators in Europe to keep SixSq software and services at the cutting edge of technology. All of the 3-year projects focus on computer architecture in the edge-to-cloud space and will be tested via concrete use cases across a wide range of sectors. ICOS is designing an AI-powered continuum which is open, secure, adaptable and technology-agnostic. The solution will be tested via 4 use cases in the fields of agriculture, multimedia systems, railway infrastructure monitoring and energy mangement. EXTRACT aims to develop a data-mining platform for extreme data, leveraging the knowledge of 10 Consortium partners around two interesting use cases: personalised evacuation routing in case of emergency and transforming huge volumes of raw data from radio-telescopes into high quality reusable datasets for use in 15 different scientific domains. The ACES edge-to-cloud framework will be able of managing itself in terms of workload placement, service and resource management, as well as data and policy management, thanks to AI capabilities. Participaton in these projects confirms SixSq’s commitment to delivering the most innovative solutions to its customers. Useful links ICOS website EXTRACT website ACES website For a bit of background reading on edge and cloud computing, take a look at our blog page. Funding The ICOS project is funded through from the European Union’s HORIZON EUROPE research and innovation programme under grant agreement No 101070177. SixSq is funded by SERI under contract number 22.00262. The EXTRACT project is funded through from the European Union’s HORIZON EUROPE research and innovation programme under grant agreement No 101093110. SixSq is funded by SEFRI. The ACES project is funded through from the European Union’s HORIZON EUROPE research and innovation programme under grant agreement No 101093126. SixSq is funded by SEFRI under contract number 22.00532.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/horizon-europe.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/horizon-europe.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Introducing our new Marketing &amp;amp; Communications Manager</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/03/27/news-rebecca-schenato.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing our new Marketing &amp;amp; Communications Manager" /><published>2023-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/news/2023/03/27/news-rebecca-schenato</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/03/27/news-rebecca-schenato.html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>On 13 March 2023, Rebecca Schenato took up her role as Marketing &amp; Communications Manager in Geneva</strong></p>

<p>SixSq is excited to announce that Rebecca Schenato has joined the team as Marketing &amp; Communications Manager. Rebecca brings a wealth of experience in making tech brands shine with a proven track record of in IoT and B2B sectors. Her creative marketing approach will help bring the company to the next level, delivering an outstanding experience to current and potential users and customers.</p>

<p>Commenting on her appointment, Rebecca said, <em>“It is a pleasure to be part of the SixSq team and Ekinops ecosystem.  I am thrilled to have the opportunity of contributing to the growth and vision of the company. There is a lot of great potential ahead, and I am looking forward to working together towards the accomplishment of the company’s ambitions”</em>.</p>

<p>As Marketing &amp; Communications Manager Rebecca will be a major contributor to ensure our messaging continues to be clear and crisp, while translating the company’s business objectives into actionable marketing strategies.</p>

<p>SixSq CEO, Marc-Elian Bégin said, <em>“Rebecca is the perfect complement to the team, bringing a wealth of relevant experience and energy. She will be instrumental in forging a path towards our ambitious growth objectives”</em>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[On 13 March 2023, Rebecca Schenato took up her role as Marketing &amp; Communications Manager in Geneva SixSq is excited to announce that Rebecca Schenato has joined the team as Marketing &amp; Communications Manager. Rebecca brings a wealth of experience in making tech brands shine with a proven track record of in IoT and B2B sectors. Her creative marketing approach will help bring the company to the next level, delivering an outstanding experience to current and potential users and customers. Commenting on her appointment, Rebecca said, “It is a pleasure to be part of the SixSq team and Ekinops ecosystem. I am thrilled to have the opportunity of contributing to the growth and vision of the company. There is a lot of great potential ahead, and I am looking forward to working together towards the accomplishment of the company’s ambitions”. As Marketing &amp; Communications Manager Rebecca will be a major contributor to ensure our messaging continues to be clear and crisp, while translating the company’s business objectives into actionable marketing strategies. SixSq CEO, Marc-Elian Bégin said, “Rebecca is the perfect complement to the team, bringing a wealth of relevant experience and energy. She will be instrumental in forging a path towards our ambitious growth objectives”.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/rebecca-schenato.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/rebecca-schenato.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>