<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-07-22T14:47:18+00:00</updated><id>https://new-website.sixsq.ch/feed.xml</id><title type="html">SixSq Website</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">SixSq joins 5G-EMERGE project</title><link href="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/news/2022/07/05/news-5G-EMERGE.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SixSq joins 5G-EMERGE project" /><published>2022-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://new-website.sixsq.ch/news/2022/07/05/news-5G-EMERGE</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/news/2022/07/05/news-5G-EMERGE.html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Geneva, 5 July, 2022</strong> – SixSq, an <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/">Ekinops</a> company, is proud to announce its participation in the 5G-EMERGE project, which aims to develop solutions that leverage 5G technology and satellite broadcasting to put Europe at the vanguard of media delivery technology. The project is part of the <a href="https://www.esa.int/">European Space Agency</a> (ESA) programme of Advanced Research in Telecommunications Systems (<a href="https://www.esa.int/Applications/Telecommunications_Integrated_Applications/ARTES/About_ARTES">ARTES</a>) and will be led by the European Broadcasting Union (<a href="https://www.ebu.ch/home">EBU</a>).</p>

<p>The 5G-EMERGE project aims at developing an integrated satellite and terrestrial system based on open standards to enable high-quality content distribution services over multi-layer IP infra-structures. Telecommunications satellites will efficiently deliver high-demand content, including streaming of live events, as close as possible to the end user – to the ‘edge’. The project includes demonstrations in 5G base stations, users’ homes and vehicles.</p>

<p>A consortium of 20 companies from six European countries will collaborate on developing the distributed edge technology and service-delivery features.</p>

<p>SixSq’s contribution includes leading the demonstration work package and providing the edge-to-cloud software infrastructure based on its <a href="https://nuvla.io/">Nuvla.io</a> B2B SaaS platform and marketplace of containerised applications, as well as its open source NuvlaEdge software.</p>

<p>SixSq CEO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mebster/">Marc-Elian Bégin</a> said, <em>“Leveraging satellite broadcast and 5G is a great opportunity to deliver the right high-density content at the right location with the right customization. However, this requires fine-tuned orchestration of the entire value chain and this is what SixSq edge-to-cloud software provides. We are no stranger to big challenges posed by ESA and EBU and are looking forward to pushing the boundaries of edge-to-cloud, bringing together the space sector, 5G and multi-media content delivery.”</em></p>

<p><em>“The 5G-Emerge project is yet another example of Ekinops’ long commitment towards software innovation as a mean to add value to the telecommunications sector”</em>, commented <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/muniere/">Vincent Munière</a>, Group Chief Technology Officer &amp; VP R&amp;D at Ekinops. <em>“We are looking forward to helping set the bar in 5G services and content delivery.”</em></p>

<p>For SixSq, this project is a unique opportunity to showcase its edge computing software’s ability to orchestrate complex scenarios for a range of new commercial use-cases, ranging from mari-time, vehicle, public transport, 5G and building applications.  Working with market leaders in their domain, Nuvla.io will manage apps across the edge-to-cloud continuum.</p>

<h3 id="5g-emerge-consortium">5G-EMERGE Consortium</h3>

<p>Arctic Space Technologies, Arthur D. Little, Athonet, Celestia Technologies Group, EBU, Fondazione LINKS, FTA Communication Technologies, G-Core Labs, MBI, Nagravision Sàrl, Nagravision AS, Rai, RomARS, SES Techcom, SixSq, Telenor ASA, Telenor Satellite, Telenor Maritime, TNO, Varnish Software, and ViaSat Antenna Systems.</p>

<h3 id="useful-links">Useful links</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.ebu.ch/home">EBU</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.esa.int/Applications/Telecommunications_Integrated_Applications/ARTES/About_ARTES">ARTES</a></p>

<h3 id="your-contacts">Your contacts</h3>

<p><strong>SixSq</strong></p>

<p>Louise Merifield
<br />
Operations Manager and Co-founder
<br />
+41 77 44 68 170
<br />
<a href="mailto:merifield@sixsq.com">merifield@sixsq.com</a></p>

<p><strong>Ekinops</strong>
<br />
Fraser Kay
<br />
iseepr
<br />
+44(0) 113 350 1922
<br />
<a href="mailto:fraser@iseepr.co.uk">fraser@iseepr.co.uk</a>
<br /></p>

<h3 id="about-ekinops">About Ekinops</h3>

<p>Ekinops is a leading provider of open, trusted and innovative network connectivity solutions to service providers around the world. Our programmable and highly scalable solutions enable the fast, flexible, and cost-effective deployment of new services for both high-speed, high-capacity optical transport as well as virtualization-enabled managed enterprise services. Our product portfolio consists of three highly complementary product and service sets: <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/products-services/products/ekinops360">EKINOPS360</a>, <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/products-services/products/oneaccess">OneAccess</a> and <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/products-services/products/compose">Compose</a>.</p>

<ul>
  <li>EKINOPS360 provides optical transport solutions for metro, regional and long-distance networks with WDM for high-capacity point-to-point, ring, and optical mesh architectures, and OTN for improved bandwidth utilization and efficient multi-service aggregation.</li>
  <li>OneAccess offers a wide choice of physical and virtualized deployment options for Layer 2 and Layer 3 access network functions.</li>
  <li>Compose supports service providers in making their networks software-defined with a variety of software management tools and services, including the scalable SD-WAN Xpress and SixSq Edge-to-Cloud solutions.</li>
</ul>

<p>As service providers embrace SDN and NFV deployment models, Ekinops enables future-proofed deployment today, enabling operators to seamlessly migrate to an open, virtualized delivery model at a time of their choosing. A global organization, Ekinops (EKI) - a public company traded on the Euronext Paris exchange operates on four continents.</p>

<p>Name : Ekinops
ISIN Code : FR0011466069
Mnemonic code : EKI
Number of shares : 26,162,922</p>

<p>For more information, visit: <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/">ekinops.com</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Geneva, 5 July, 2022 – SixSq, an Ekinops company, is proud to announce its participation in the 5G-EMERGE project, which aims to develop solutions that leverage 5G technology and satellite broadcasting to put Europe at the vanguard of media delivery technology. The project is part of the European Space Agency (ESA) programme of Advanced Research in Telecommunications Systems (ARTES) and will be led by the European Broadcasting Union (EBU). The 5G-EMERGE project aims at developing an integrated satellite and terrestrial system based on open standards to enable high-quality content distribution services over multi-layer IP infra-structures. Telecommunications satellites will efficiently deliver high-demand content, including streaming of live events, as close as possible to the end user – to the ‘edge’. The project includes demonstrations in 5G base stations, users’ homes and vehicles. A consortium of 20 companies from six European countries will collaborate on developing the distributed edge technology and service-delivery features. SixSq’s contribution includes leading the demonstration work package and providing the edge-to-cloud software infrastructure based on its Nuvla.io B2B SaaS platform and marketplace of containerised applications, as well as its open source NuvlaEdge software. SixSq CEO Marc-Elian Bégin said, “Leveraging satellite broadcast and 5G is a great opportunity to deliver the right high-density content at the right location with the right customization. However, this requires fine-tuned orchestration of the entire value chain and this is what SixSq edge-to-cloud software provides. We are no stranger to big challenges posed by ESA and EBU and are looking forward to pushing the boundaries of edge-to-cloud, bringing together the space sector, 5G and multi-media content delivery.” “The 5G-Emerge project is yet another example of Ekinops’ long commitment towards software innovation as a mean to add value to the telecommunications sector”, commented Vincent Munière, Group Chief Technology Officer &amp; VP R&amp;D at Ekinops. “We are looking forward to helping set the bar in 5G services and content delivery.” For SixSq, this project is a unique opportunity to showcase its edge computing software’s ability to orchestrate complex scenarios for a range of new commercial use-cases, ranging from mari-time, vehicle, public transport, 5G and building applications. Working with market leaders in their domain, Nuvla.io will manage apps across the edge-to-cloud continuum. 5G-EMERGE Consortium Arctic Space Technologies, Arthur D. Little, Athonet, Celestia Technologies Group, EBU, Fondazione LINKS, FTA Communication Technologies, G-Core Labs, MBI, Nagravision Sàrl, Nagravision AS, Rai, RomARS, SES Techcom, SixSq, Telenor ASA, Telenor Satellite, Telenor Maritime, TNO, Varnish Software, and ViaSat Antenna Systems. Useful links EBU ARTES Your contacts SixSq Louise Merifield Operations Manager and Co-founder +41 77 44 68 170 merifield@sixsq.com Ekinops Fraser Kay iseepr +44(0) 113 350 1922 fraser@iseepr.co.uk About Ekinops Ekinops is a leading provider of open, trusted and innovative network connectivity solutions to service providers around the world. Our programmable and highly scalable solutions enable the fast, flexible, and cost-effective deployment of new services for both high-speed, high-capacity optical transport as well as virtualization-enabled managed enterprise services. Our product portfolio consists of three highly complementary product and service sets: EKINOPS360, OneAccess and Compose. EKINOPS360 provides optical transport solutions for metro, regional and long-distance networks with WDM for high-capacity point-to-point, ring, and optical mesh architectures, and OTN for improved bandwidth utilization and efficient multi-service aggregation. OneAccess offers a wide choice of physical and virtualized deployment options for Layer 2 and Layer 3 access network functions. Compose supports service providers in making their networks software-defined with a variety of software management tools and services, including the scalable SD-WAN Xpress and SixSq Edge-to-Cloud solutions. As service providers embrace SDN and NFV deployment models, Ekinops enables future-proofed deployment today, enabling operators to seamlessly migrate to an open, virtualized delivery model at a time of their choosing. A global organization, Ekinops (EKI) - a public company traded on the Euronext Paris exchange operates on four continents. Name : Ekinops ISIN Code : FR0011466069 Mnemonic code : EKI Number of shares : 26,162,922 For more information, visit: ekinops.com.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/5GEmerge-vignette.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/5GEmerge-vignette.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">C2RO joins App Vendor Programme</title><link href="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/news/2022/06/20/news-c2ro.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="C2RO joins App Vendor Programme" /><published>2022-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://new-website.sixsq.ch/news/2022/06/20/news-c2ro</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/news/2022/06/20/news-c2ro.html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>SixSq’s Nuvla.io ecosystem facilitates the deployment, management and update of C2RO’s ENTERA Video Analytics Agent</strong></p>

<p>SixSq, an <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/">Ekinops</a> Company, and <a href="https://www.c2ro.com/">C2RO™</a> today announced a partnership to deliver state-of-the-art GDPR-Compliant Video Analytics of large public venues via the <a href="https://nuvla.io/marketplace">Nuvla.io Marketplace</a>. This collaboration significantly simplifies the procurement, deployment, and management of C2RO™’s industry-leading <a href="https://www.c2ro.com/entera">ENTERA™</a> video analytics platform specifically designed for GDPR-compliant analysis of visitor traffic in public spaces.</p>

<p><em>“Nuvla.io allows us to streamline and automate the distribution of our ENTERA™ Edge AI components at scale. We see Nuvla.io as a strategic marketplace that facilitates broad access to our ENTERA™ AI-SaaS platform while simplifying the deployment and maintenance process for our customers and partners.” said <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/riccardo-badalone/">Riccardo Badalone</a>, Chief Executive Officer of C2RO™</em>.</p>

<p>Airports, malls, and public venue operators require an understanding of how visitors flow through their physical spaces to best optimize services and maximize return on investment. The ENTERA™ Video Analytics Platform provides the means for enterprise customers to achieve this goal via a hyper-scalable AI-SaaS architecture with powerful and intuitive analysis tools, alerting and interactive dashboards.</p>

<p><em>“Helping domain matter experts like C2RO™ accelerate and streamline their go-to-market is at the heart of why we created the Nuvla.io Marketplace. The combination of C2RO’s cutting edge Intelligent Video Analytics Platform ENTERA™ and Nuvla.io means that sectors such as airports, malls and large public venues can deploy a simple, yet secure, powerful, and scalable, solution for people tracking challenges. And in the process, customers gain a future proof shared edge infrastructure that will deliver great ROI.”</em> said <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mebster/">Marc-Elian Bégin</a>, SixSq CEO and Co-founder.</p>

<p>With the ENTERA™ Advanced Video Analytics agent available in the Nuvla.io Marketplace, companies can now deploy, manage, and update their ENTERA™ agents remotely and securely. The purchasing and deployment process is fast, simple, and robust, with the app deployed at scale in a few clicks via the Nuvla.io dashboard.</p>

<p>The service is available via a pay-as-you-go subscription. You will find C2RO’s ENTERA™ Agent Application on the Nuvla.io Marketplace <a href="https://nuvla.io/ui/apps/c2ro">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[SixSq’s Nuvla.io ecosystem facilitates the deployment, management and update of C2RO’s ENTERA Video Analytics Agent SixSq, an Ekinops Company, and C2RO™ today announced a partnership to deliver state-of-the-art GDPR-Compliant Video Analytics of large public venues via the Nuvla.io Marketplace. This collaboration significantly simplifies the procurement, deployment, and management of C2RO™’s industry-leading ENTERA™ video analytics platform specifically designed for GDPR-compliant analysis of visitor traffic in public spaces. “Nuvla.io allows us to streamline and automate the distribution of our ENTERA™ Edge AI components at scale. We see Nuvla.io as a strategic marketplace that facilitates broad access to our ENTERA™ AI-SaaS platform while simplifying the deployment and maintenance process for our customers and partners.” said Riccardo Badalone, Chief Executive Officer of C2RO™. Airports, malls, and public venue operators require an understanding of how visitors flow through their physical spaces to best optimize services and maximize return on investment. The ENTERA™ Video Analytics Platform provides the means for enterprise customers to achieve this goal via a hyper-scalable AI-SaaS architecture with powerful and intuitive analysis tools, alerting and interactive dashboards. “Helping domain matter experts like C2RO™ accelerate and streamline their go-to-market is at the heart of why we created the Nuvla.io Marketplace. The combination of C2RO’s cutting edge Intelligent Video Analytics Platform ENTERA™ and Nuvla.io means that sectors such as airports, malls and large public venues can deploy a simple, yet secure, powerful, and scalable, solution for people tracking challenges. And in the process, customers gain a future proof shared edge infrastructure that will deliver great ROI.” said Marc-Elian Bégin, SixSq CEO and Co-founder. With the ENTERA™ Advanced Video Analytics agent available in the Nuvla.io Marketplace, companies can now deploy, manage, and update their ENTERA™ agents remotely and securely. The purchasing and deployment process is fast, simple, and robust, with the app deployed at scale in a few clicks via the Nuvla.io dashboard. The service is available via a pay-as-you-go subscription. You will find C2RO’s ENTERA™ Agent Application on the Nuvla.io Marketplace here.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/app-vendor-c2ro.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/app-vendor-c2ro.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">AI EdgeLabs joins App Vendor Programme</title><link href="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/news/2022/06/13/news-aiedgelabs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AI EdgeLabs joins App Vendor Programme" /><published>2022-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://new-website.sixsq.ch/news/2022/06/13/news-aiedgelabs</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/news/2022/06/13/news-aiedgelabs.html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>SixSq’s Nuvla.io ecosystem facilitates the deployment, management, and update of AI EdgeLab’s cyber security sensors</strong></p>

<p>SixSq, an <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/">Ekinops</a> Company, and <a href="">AI EdgeLabs</a> today announced a partnership to make AI EdgeLabs cyber security sensors available via the Nuvla.io Marketplace. This collaboration significantly simplifies the integration of a complete cyber defense solution for edge/IoT/OT devices, by enabling the purchase, deployment and management of AI EdgeLabs cyber security sensors.</p>

<p>AI EdgeLabs is a powerful and autonomous cybersecurity <a href="https://edgelabs.ai/platform/">AI platform</a> that helps security teams respond immediately to ongoing attacks and protect Edge/IoT infrastructures against malware, DDoS, botnets, and other threats. AI EdgeLabs delivers cybersecurity measures by bringing network visibility, early threat detection, and automated incident response to the Edge and on-premise environments.</p>

<p>Cybersecurity is not an issue pertaining to specific industries which is why AI EdgeLabs is uniquely designed to solve the pain points of each one, from manufacturing to retail, healthcare, agriculture, telecommunications, transportation and logistics, smart cities, financial services, and more.</p>

<p><em>“To remain competitive, we believe businesses should be protected with real time, AI-powered, and accurate embedded solutions. Said solutions should be easy to deploy, fast, and ready for immediate use. Considering the level of connectivity in the field, AI is the best option to analyse data and secure the Edge and connected IoT/OT”</em> says <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/innaushakova/">Inna Ushakova</a>, CEO at AI EdgeLabs.</p>

<p>With AI EdgeLabs available in the Nuvla.io Marketplace, companies can now cyber protect their edge assets.</p>

<p><em>“EdgeLabs AI sensors can be deployed directly to the Edge Server or IoT/ OT Gateway or to the host operating system. Since we support containers deployment, our solution is ideally suited to work with the Nuvla.io Marketplace. This brings our clients a lot of flexibility and scalability. All data processing is performed at the edge, thus it doesn’t leave the industrial or critical infrastructure perimeter. Your data is your data,”</em> says <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/miggi/">Oleg Mygryn</a>, CTO at AI EdgeLabs.</p>

<p>With this partnership, it’s easier than ever for enterprise to deploy a proven cyber security solution.</p>

<p><em>“At SixSq we realise the importance of security, which is why we are delighted to be working with AI EdgeLabs to bring their cutting edge cyber security platform to all sectors via the Nuvla.io Marketplace and the App Vendor Programme.”</em> said <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mebster/">Marc-Elian Bégin</a>, SixSq CEO and Co-founder.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[SixSq’s Nuvla.io ecosystem facilitates the deployment, management, and update of AI EdgeLab’s cyber security sensors SixSq, an Ekinops Company, and AI EdgeLabs today announced a partnership to make AI EdgeLabs cyber security sensors available via the Nuvla.io Marketplace. This collaboration significantly simplifies the integration of a complete cyber defense solution for edge/IoT/OT devices, by enabling the purchase, deployment and management of AI EdgeLabs cyber security sensors. AI EdgeLabs is a powerful and autonomous cybersecurity AI platform that helps security teams respond immediately to ongoing attacks and protect Edge/IoT infrastructures against malware, DDoS, botnets, and other threats. AI EdgeLabs delivers cybersecurity measures by bringing network visibility, early threat detection, and automated incident response to the Edge and on-premise environments. Cybersecurity is not an issue pertaining to specific industries which is why AI EdgeLabs is uniquely designed to solve the pain points of each one, from manufacturing to retail, healthcare, agriculture, telecommunications, transportation and logistics, smart cities, financial services, and more. “To remain competitive, we believe businesses should be protected with real time, AI-powered, and accurate embedded solutions. Said solutions should be easy to deploy, fast, and ready for immediate use. Considering the level of connectivity in the field, AI is the best option to analyse data and secure the Edge and connected IoT/OT” says Inna Ushakova, CEO at AI EdgeLabs. With AI EdgeLabs available in the Nuvla.io Marketplace, companies can now cyber protect their edge assets. “EdgeLabs AI sensors can be deployed directly to the Edge Server or IoT/ OT Gateway or to the host operating system. Since we support containers deployment, our solution is ideally suited to work with the Nuvla.io Marketplace. This brings our clients a lot of flexibility and scalability. All data processing is performed at the edge, thus it doesn’t leave the industrial or critical infrastructure perimeter. Your data is your data,” says Oleg Mygryn, CTO at AI EdgeLabs. With this partnership, it’s easier than ever for enterprise to deploy a proven cyber security solution. “At SixSq we realise the importance of security, which is why we are delighted to be working with AI EdgeLabs to bring their cutting edge cyber security platform to all sectors via the Nuvla.io Marketplace and the App Vendor Programme.” said Marc-Elian Bégin, SixSq CEO and Co-founder.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/app-vendor-ai-edgelabs.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/app-vendor-ai-edgelabs.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Clearblade joins App Vendor Programme</title><link href="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/news/2022/06/13/news-clearblade.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Clearblade joins App Vendor Programme" /><published>2022-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://new-website.sixsq.ch/news/2022/06/13/news-clearblade</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/news/2022/06/13/news-clearblade.html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>SixSq’s Nuvla.io ecosystem facilitates the deployment, management, and update of ClearBlade’s Intelligent Asset solution.</strong></p>

<p>SixSq, an <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/">Ekinops</a> company, and <a href="https://www.clearblade.com/">ClearBlade</a> today announced a partnership to deliver <a href="https://www.clearblade.com/intelligent-assets/">Intelligent Assets</a> via the Nuvla.io Marketplace. This collaboration significantly simplifies the purchase, deployment, and management of ClearBlade’s leading agnostic hardware and sensor technology.</p>

<p>Logistics companies and train operators need to monitor and track their assets to better run their business. The ClearBlade Intelligent Assets solution and its Management Platform provide the means for customers to achieve this goal using a no-code solution, as well as powerful and intuitive analysis tools, alerting and dashboarding</p>

<p>With ClearBlade Intelligent Assets solution available in the Nuvla.io Marketplace, companies can now deploy, manage, and update their ClearBlade solution remotely and securely. The purchasing and deployment process is fast, simple, and robust, with the app deployed at scale in a few clicks via the Nuvla.io dashboard.</p>

<p><em>“From a technical perspective, Nuvla.io allows us to streamline and automate the distribution of our asset tracking agent. From a business development perspective, we see Nuvla.io as a marketplace that facilitates adoption and simplifies recurring revenue generation,”</em> said <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ericsimone/">Eric Simone</a>, CEO of ClearBlade.</p>

<p>Together, ClearBlade and SixSq provide a standard offering for low-touch, reusable edge application deployments across the enterprise. ClearBlade’s Intelligent Assets edge application is deployed in seconds with the SixSq <a href="https://nuvla.io/">Nuvla.io</a> edge management platform. The edge application instantly unlocks your business data and ensures that critical operational information is managed securely and efficiently. With the joint partner offering it’s never been simpler to start and most importantly scale your edge operations.</p>

<p><em>“Helping domain matter experts like ClearBlade accelerate and streamline their go-to-market is at the heart of why we created the Nuvla.io Marketplace. The combination of ClearBlade’s Intelligent Asset Application and Nuvla.io means that sectors such as logistics and railway can deploy a simple, yet secure, powerful, and scalable, solution for their asset tracking challenges. And in the process, customers gain a future proof shared edge infrastructure that will deliver great ROI.”</em> said <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mebster/">Marc-Elian Bégin</a>, SixSq CEO and Co-founder.</p>

<p>The service is available via a pay-as-you-go subscription. You will find ClearBlade Intelligent Asset Solution on the Nuvla.io Marketplace <a href="https://nuvla.io/ui/apps/clearblade">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[SixSq’s Nuvla.io ecosystem facilitates the deployment, management, and update of ClearBlade’s Intelligent Asset solution. SixSq, an Ekinops company, and ClearBlade today announced a partnership to deliver Intelligent Assets via the Nuvla.io Marketplace. This collaboration significantly simplifies the purchase, deployment, and management of ClearBlade’s leading agnostic hardware and sensor technology. Logistics companies and train operators need to monitor and track their assets to better run their business. The ClearBlade Intelligent Assets solution and its Management Platform provide the means for customers to achieve this goal using a no-code solution, as well as powerful and intuitive analysis tools, alerting and dashboarding With ClearBlade Intelligent Assets solution available in the Nuvla.io Marketplace, companies can now deploy, manage, and update their ClearBlade solution remotely and securely. The purchasing and deployment process is fast, simple, and robust, with the app deployed at scale in a few clicks via the Nuvla.io dashboard. “From a technical perspective, Nuvla.io allows us to streamline and automate the distribution of our asset tracking agent. From a business development perspective, we see Nuvla.io as a marketplace that facilitates adoption and simplifies recurring revenue generation,” said Eric Simone, CEO of ClearBlade. Together, ClearBlade and SixSq provide a standard offering for low-touch, reusable edge application deployments across the enterprise. ClearBlade’s Intelligent Assets edge application is deployed in seconds with the SixSq Nuvla.io edge management platform. The edge application instantly unlocks your business data and ensures that critical operational information is managed securely and efficiently. With the joint partner offering it’s never been simpler to start and most importantly scale your edge operations. “Helping domain matter experts like ClearBlade accelerate and streamline their go-to-market is at the heart of why we created the Nuvla.io Marketplace. The combination of ClearBlade’s Intelligent Asset Application and Nuvla.io means that sectors such as logistics and railway can deploy a simple, yet secure, powerful, and scalable, solution for their asset tracking challenges. And in the process, customers gain a future proof shared edge infrastructure that will deliver great ROI.” said Marc-Elian Bégin, SixSq CEO and Co-founder. The service is available via a pay-as-you-go subscription. You will find ClearBlade Intelligent Asset Solution on the Nuvla.io Marketplace here.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/app-vendor-clearblade.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/app-vendor-clearblade.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Cybus joins App Vendor Programme</title><link href="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/news/2022/06/13/news-cybus.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cybus joins App Vendor Programme" /><published>2022-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://new-website.sixsq.ch/news/2022/06/13/news-cybus</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/news/2022/06/13/news-cybus.html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>SixSq’s <a href="https://nuvla.io/">Nuvla.io</a> ecosystem facilitates the deployment, management and update of the Manufacturing Data Platform “Cybus Connectware”</strong></p>

<p>SixSq and <a href="https://www.cybus.io/en/">Cybus</a> today announced a partnership to make <a href="https://www.cybus.io/en/product/cybus-connectware/">Cybus Connectware</a> conveniently available via the <a href="https://nuvla.io/marketplace">Nuvla.io Marketplace</a>. This collaboration significantly simplifies the purchase, deployment and management of Cybus’ leading manufacturing data platform and realisation of intelligent manufacturing monitoring.</p>

<p>Manufacturing companies need to monitor and understand the state of their shop floor and array of machines to improve key performance indicators, such as their overall equipment effectiveness, reduce maintenance effort and increase production quality. With the software solution Cybus Connectware, factories establish full shop floor transparency in only a few weeks. The real-time production data is then directly distributed to built-in monitoring features for powerful and intuitive analysis tools, alerting and dashboarding.</p>

<p>With Cybus Connectware available in the Nuvla.io Marketplace, companies can now deploy, manage and update their Manufacturing Data Platform agents remotely and securely. The purchasing and deployment process is fast, simple and robust, with the app deployed at scale in a few clicks via the Nuvla.io dashboard.</p>

<p><em>“From a technical perspective, Nuvla.io allows us to streamline and automate the distribution of our Connectware agent aligned with the needs of factories for quick and compatible digitisation setups. This is an important accelerator for digital transformation in the manufacturing industry.”</em> says <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jonas-schramm-b8025315b/">Jonas Schramm</a>, Head of Product at Cybus.</p>

<p><em>“We are delighted to be working with Cybus. The combination of Cybus Connectware and Nuvla.io delivers a simple, secure, powerful and scalable solution to the manufacturing sector. Customers gain a future proof way to scale their edge operations and benefit from great ROI.”</em> said <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mebster/">Marc-Elian Bégin</a>, SixSq CEO and Co-founder.</p>

<p>The service is available via a pay-as-you-go subscription. You will find Cybus’ Manufacturing Data Platform on the <a href="https://nuvla.io/ui/sign-in?redirect=apps/cybus">Nuvla.io Marketplace</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[SixSq’s Nuvla.io ecosystem facilitates the deployment, management and update of the Manufacturing Data Platform “Cybus Connectware” SixSq and Cybus today announced a partnership to make Cybus Connectware conveniently available via the Nuvla.io Marketplace. This collaboration significantly simplifies the purchase, deployment and management of Cybus’ leading manufacturing data platform and realisation of intelligent manufacturing monitoring. Manufacturing companies need to monitor and understand the state of their shop floor and array of machines to improve key performance indicators, such as their overall equipment effectiveness, reduce maintenance effort and increase production quality. With the software solution Cybus Connectware, factories establish full shop floor transparency in only a few weeks. The real-time production data is then directly distributed to built-in monitoring features for powerful and intuitive analysis tools, alerting and dashboarding. With Cybus Connectware available in the Nuvla.io Marketplace, companies can now deploy, manage and update their Manufacturing Data Platform agents remotely and securely. The purchasing and deployment process is fast, simple and robust, with the app deployed at scale in a few clicks via the Nuvla.io dashboard. “From a technical perspective, Nuvla.io allows us to streamline and automate the distribution of our Connectware agent aligned with the needs of factories for quick and compatible digitisation setups. This is an important accelerator for digital transformation in the manufacturing industry.” says Jonas Schramm, Head of Product at Cybus. “We are delighted to be working with Cybus. The combination of Cybus Connectware and Nuvla.io delivers a simple, secure, powerful and scalable solution to the manufacturing sector. Customers gain a future proof way to scale their edge operations and benefit from great ROI.” said Marc-Elian Bégin, SixSq CEO and Co-founder. The service is available via a pay-as-you-go subscription. You will find Cybus’ Manufacturing Data Platform on the Nuvla.io Marketplace.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/app-vendor-cybus.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/app-vendor-cybus.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Securaxis joins App Vendor Programme</title><link href="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/news/2022/06/13/news-securaxis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Securaxis joins App Vendor Programme" /><published>2022-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://new-website.sixsq.ch/news/2022/06/13/news-securaxis</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/news/2022/06/13/news-securaxis.html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>SixSq, an Ekinops Company, and <a href="https://securaxis.com">Securaxis</a> today announced their continuing partnership to deliver intelligent sound embedded software that can analyse specific sounds in any environment via the Nuvla.io Marketplace.</strong> This collaboration significantly simplifies the purchase, deployment and management of Securaxis’s innovative sound processing technology.</p>

<p>Smart cities need to monitor activities in the city to better deliver a comfortable and safe urban environment for all. The Securaxis <a href="https://securaxis.com/solutions/#sonal"><strong>SONAL</strong></a> solution and its Management Platform provides the means for cities to achieve this goal using a no code solution, as well as powerful and intuitive analysis tools, alerting and dashboarding.</p>

<p>With Securaxis SONAL available in the Nuvla.io Marketplace, cities can now deploy, manage and update their Securaxis agents remotely and securely. The purchasing and deployment process is fast, simple and robust, with the app deployed at scale in a few clicks via the Nuvla.io dashboard.</p>

<p><em>“From a technical perspective, Nuvla.io allows us to streamline and automate the distribution of our SONAL agent agent. From a business development perspective, we see Nuvla.io as a marketplace that facilitates adoption and simplifies recurring revenue generation,”</em> said <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gmeleder/">Glenn Meleder</a>, CEO, Securaxis.</p>

<p><em>“I am delighted to continue our work with Securaxis and their cutting-edge sound processing solution. After several successful deployments in Switzerland, we are now ready to accelerate and streamline their go-to-market with the Nuvla.io Marketplace and our new App Vendor Programme. The combination of Securaxis’s intelligent sound processing technology and Nuvla.io means that smart cities can deploy a simple, yet secure, powerful and scalable, solution for their GDPR compliant sound analysis challenges.”</em> said <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mebster/">Marc-Elian Bégin</a>, SixSq CEO and Co-founder.</p>

<p>The service is available via a pay-as-you-go <a href="/pricing">subscription</a>. You will find Securaxis SONAL Agent on the Nuvla.io Marketplace <a href="https://nuvla.io/ui/apps/securaxis">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[SixSq, an Ekinops Company, and Securaxis today announced their continuing partnership to deliver intelligent sound embedded software that can analyse specific sounds in any environment via the Nuvla.io Marketplace. This collaboration significantly simplifies the purchase, deployment and management of Securaxis’s innovative sound processing technology. Smart cities need to monitor activities in the city to better deliver a comfortable and safe urban environment for all. The Securaxis SONAL solution and its Management Platform provides the means for cities to achieve this goal using a no code solution, as well as powerful and intuitive analysis tools, alerting and dashboarding. With Securaxis SONAL available in the Nuvla.io Marketplace, cities can now deploy, manage and update their Securaxis agents remotely and securely. The purchasing and deployment process is fast, simple and robust, with the app deployed at scale in a few clicks via the Nuvla.io dashboard. “From a technical perspective, Nuvla.io allows us to streamline and automate the distribution of our SONAL agent agent. From a business development perspective, we see Nuvla.io as a marketplace that facilitates adoption and simplifies recurring revenue generation,” said Glenn Meleder, CEO, Securaxis. “I am delighted to continue our work with Securaxis and their cutting-edge sound processing solution. After several successful deployments in Switzerland, we are now ready to accelerate and streamline their go-to-market with the Nuvla.io Marketplace and our new App Vendor Programme. The combination of Securaxis’s intelligent sound processing technology and Nuvla.io means that smart cities can deploy a simple, yet secure, powerful and scalable, solution for their GDPR compliant sound analysis challenges.” said Marc-Elian Bégin, SixSq CEO and Co-founder. The service is available via a pay-as-you-go subscription. You will find Securaxis SONAL Agent on the Nuvla.io Marketplace here.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/app-vendor-securaxis.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/app-vendor-securaxis.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">SixSq announces Nuvla.io App Vendor Programme</title><link href="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/news/2022/06/09/news-app-vendor-programme.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SixSq announces Nuvla.io App Vendor Programme" /><published>2022-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://new-website.sixsq.ch/news/2022/06/09/news-app-vendor-programme</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/news/2022/06/09/news-app-vendor-programme.html"><![CDATA[<p>Building on the success of <a href="https://nuvla.io/">Nuvla.io</a> B2B SaaS, edge solution experts SixSq SA, an <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/">Ekinops</a> company, today announced the launch of the <strong>Nuvla.io App Vendor Programme to accelerate the delivery and monetisation of edge computing applications.</strong>
<br /></p>

<p>Nuvla.io App Vendor Programme enables:
<br />
• Unprecedented agility, flexibility and scalability for app vendors and customers, without compromise on security
<br />
• Accelerated adoption of meaningful edge computing with minimum risk and a positive ROI for enterprise
<br />
• Simplified edge computing go-to-market at scale for app vendors
<br /></p>

<p>SixSq’s Nuvla.io is a proven B2B digital platform for industrialisation and automation of containerised edge applications and device management.</p>

<p>Delivering simplified go-to-market for App Vendors
<em>“Using the Nuvla.io Marketplace and App Vendor Programme we can springboard customers into adopting and deploying meaningful edge computing with minimum risk and a positive ROI,”</em> said <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mebster/">Marc-Elian Bégin</a>, SixSq CEO and Co-founder. “Both vendors and customers benefit from unprecedented agility, flexibility and scalability, with minimum complexity and without compromise on security.”</p>

<p>The App Vendor Programme gives app vendors and customers tools to interact in a seamless way, including clear <a href="https://nuvla.io/pricing">pricing</a> and contractual terms. It also provides hassle-free monetisation of business applications for telcos, service providers and system integrators.</p>

<p>App vendors can now more quickly reach their customers and at the same time benefit from a simple mechanism to deliver regular software updates. Customers can purchase their apps in a <a href="https://nuvla.io/security">secure</a> manner, at scale, using Nuvla.io.</p>

<p>Serving all sectors with Edge Apps for Business
The App Vendor Programme launches with selected innovative leaders in their fields. The first vendors bring turnkey apps in the following sectors:</p>

<p>• Logistics and railway
<br />
• Manufacturing and machine monitoring
<br />
• Next generation GDPR compliant people and crowd tracking solution
<br />
• Cyberattack detection driven from AI analysis
<br />
• Smart city audio based real-time analysis using AI</p>

<p>App vendors wishing to join the App Vendor Programme are invited to get in touch with the SixSq team.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building on the success of Nuvla.io B2B SaaS, edge solution experts SixSq SA, an Ekinops company, today announced the launch of the Nuvla.io App Vendor Programme to accelerate the delivery and monetisation of edge computing applications. Nuvla.io App Vendor Programme enables: • Unprecedented agility, flexibility and scalability for app vendors and customers, without compromise on security • Accelerated adoption of meaningful edge computing with minimum risk and a positive ROI for enterprise • Simplified edge computing go-to-market at scale for app vendors SixSq’s Nuvla.io is a proven B2B digital platform for industrialisation and automation of containerised edge applications and device management. Delivering simplified go-to-market for App Vendors “Using the Nuvla.io Marketplace and App Vendor Programme we can springboard customers into adopting and deploying meaningful edge computing with minimum risk and a positive ROI,” said Marc-Elian Bégin, SixSq CEO and Co-founder. “Both vendors and customers benefit from unprecedented agility, flexibility and scalability, with minimum complexity and without compromise on security.” The App Vendor Programme gives app vendors and customers tools to interact in a seamless way, including clear pricing and contractual terms. It also provides hassle-free monetisation of business applications for telcos, service providers and system integrators. App vendors can now more quickly reach their customers and at the same time benefit from a simple mechanism to deliver regular software updates. Customers can purchase their apps in a secure manner, at scale, using Nuvla.io. Serving all sectors with Edge Apps for Business The App Vendor Programme launches with selected innovative leaders in their fields. The first vendors bring turnkey apps in the following sectors: • Logistics and railway • Manufacturing and machine monitoring • Next generation GDPR compliant people and crowd tracking solution • Cyberattack detection driven from AI analysis • Smart city audio based real-time analysis using AI App vendors wishing to join the App Vendor Programme are invited to get in touch with the SixSq team.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/app-vendor-programme.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/app-vendor-programme.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Privacy intrusion</title><link href="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/blog/discover/2022/05/24/edge-computing-hold-all-the-cards.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Privacy intrusion" /><published>2022-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://new-website.sixsq.ch/blog/discover/2022/05/24/edge-computing-hold-all-the-cards</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/blog/discover/2022/05/24/edge-computing-hold-all-the-cards.html"><![CDATA[<p>In poker rooms around the world, players keep their cards close. It’s the only way to avoid prying eyes. There’s an important lesson here for organisations collecting data, video and audio — these inputs are your cards and absolutely no one else should see them.</p>

<p>The wealth of information from your sensors, cameras, microphones, actuators and other new digital sources should yield valuable insights without intrusion.</p>

<h3 id="privacy-intrusion-is-a-hot-topic">Privacy intrusion is a hot topic</h3>

<p>When talking with customers, partners and prospects, I’m surprised by how frequently the topic of privacy intrusion comes up, and this is usually part of a broader conversation around the importance of data sovereignty. In Europe, these discussions typically reference the data privacy and security law, the <a href="https://gdpr.eu/what-is-gdpr/?cn-reloaded=1">General Data Protection Regulation</a> (GDPR), while in the Americas and further afield, other reference points are used to understand and interpret the laws around digital privacy.</p>

<p><strong>What can you see?</strong></p>

<p>As the cost of easy-to-deploy digital source equipment is going down, technical capabilities are going up, so you can understand, see and hear much more from your input streams than ever before. For example, today’s latest video cameras deliver extremely high levels of definition. This is great for generating precise insights on, say, product quality or behavioural analysis – information that’s very valuable to your organisation and to others.</p>

<h3 id="why-keep-this-information-close">Why keep this information close?</h3>

<p>No-one else should be able to see your information, or that of your customers. There are onerous standards and regulations around the operation and management of surveillance equipment, including closed-circuit television (CCTV). These requirements represent such a burden with which most organisations are unwilling or unable to comply. But without adequate protection of the information you gather, there is a very real and growing risk of someone snooping on you.</p>

<h3 id="how-to-avoid-prying-eyes">How to avoid prying eyes?</h3>

<p>A key promise of <a href="/blog/what-is-edge-computing">edge computing</a> is that instead of sending your data, video and audio to the cloud to be processed, you keep it close. All of your input streams are processed locally, near the digital device that generates them. Here’s what you gain:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Higher-quality insights: When streams are processed in their entirety near to source, they yield the best possible results. But when streams are transported over the network to the cloud for processing, their quality is normally reduced and this can result in degraded insights.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Speedier insights: Your time to insight is faster if you process streams locally – this can be done in real time and without any delays or round trips. Instead, sending streams over the network can cause perturbations and delays, especially if connections are weak and bandwidth is limited. Also as video and audio definition increases, data size increases and journeys to the cloud take longer.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Easy data fusion: Because your data is available at the edge, analysis can be easily performed here on all different categories of data (video, audio, etc). An example is analysis both of the sound of a noisy vehicle and images as the vehicle passes, showing its brand, model and number plate. Data fusion such as this enables more powerful analytics – in this case, it could mean better predictive maintenance or regulation enforcement.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Tighter privacy: The excellent news is that all the above are achieved without privacy intrusion. Why would you want to move, process and store privacy-sensitive data in the cloud – which, by the way, additionally requires designing and managing a whole layer of cloud privacy applications? Instead with edge computing the same information stays local and is stripped from any data that might intrude on citizen or corporate privacy.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Better control: With edge computing, you call the shots. A <a href="https://nuvla.io/">well-managed edge computing solution</a> puts you in remote control, able to update the devices and apps running at the edge, aligned with your changing needs. So as your organisation evolves, so too can your edge computing strategy.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h3 id="want-to-see-more-from-us">Want to see more from us?</h3>

<p>At SixSq, we have a wealth of experience in privacy protection. So contact us today to discuss new ways of stacking the cards in your favour.</p>

<p>This post was first published on the <a href="https://www.edgeir.com/privacy-intrusion-hold-all-the-cards-with-edge-computing-20220424">EdgeIR</a> website.</p>]]></content><author><name>Marc-Elian Bégin</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="edge" /><category term="cloud" /><category term="privacy" /><category term="security" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In poker rooms around the world, players keep their cards close. It’s the only way to avoid prying eyes. There’s an important lesson here for organisations collecting data, video and audio — these inputs are your cards and absolutely no one else should see them. The wealth of information from your sensors, cameras, microphones, actuators and other new digital sources should yield valuable insights without intrusion. Privacy intrusion is a hot topic When talking with customers, partners and prospects, I’m surprised by how frequently the topic of privacy intrusion comes up, and this is usually part of a broader conversation around the importance of data sovereignty. In Europe, these discussions typically reference the data privacy and security law, the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), while in the Americas and further afield, other reference points are used to understand and interpret the laws around digital privacy. What can you see? As the cost of easy-to-deploy digital source equipment is going down, technical capabilities are going up, so you can understand, see and hear much more from your input streams than ever before. For example, today’s latest video cameras deliver extremely high levels of definition. This is great for generating precise insights on, say, product quality or behavioural analysis – information that’s very valuable to your organisation and to others. Why keep this information close? No-one else should be able to see your information, or that of your customers. There are onerous standards and regulations around the operation and management of surveillance equipment, including closed-circuit television (CCTV). These requirements represent such a burden with which most organisations are unwilling or unable to comply. But without adequate protection of the information you gather, there is a very real and growing risk of someone snooping on you. How to avoid prying eyes? A key promise of edge computing is that instead of sending your data, video and audio to the cloud to be processed, you keep it close. All of your input streams are processed locally, near the digital device that generates them. Here’s what you gain: Higher-quality insights: When streams are processed in their entirety near to source, they yield the best possible results. But when streams are transported over the network to the cloud for processing, their quality is normally reduced and this can result in degraded insights. Speedier insights: Your time to insight is faster if you process streams locally – this can be done in real time and without any delays or round trips. Instead, sending streams over the network can cause perturbations and delays, especially if connections are weak and bandwidth is limited. Also as video and audio definition increases, data size increases and journeys to the cloud take longer. Easy data fusion: Because your data is available at the edge, analysis can be easily performed here on all different categories of data (video, audio, etc). An example is analysis both of the sound of a noisy vehicle and images as the vehicle passes, showing its brand, model and number plate. Data fusion such as this enables more powerful analytics – in this case, it could mean better predictive maintenance or regulation enforcement. Tighter privacy: The excellent news is that all the above are achieved without privacy intrusion. Why would you want to move, process and store privacy-sensitive data in the cloud – which, by the way, additionally requires designing and managing a whole layer of cloud privacy applications? Instead with edge computing the same information stays local and is stripped from any data that might intrude on citizen or corporate privacy. Better control: With edge computing, you call the shots. A well-managed edge computing solution puts you in remote control, able to update the devices and apps running at the edge, aligned with your changing needs. So as your organisation evolves, so too can your edge computing strategy. Want to see more from us? At SixSq, we have a wealth of experience in privacy protection. So contact us today to discuss new ways of stacking the cards in your favour. This post was first published on the EdgeIR website.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/hold-all-the-cards.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/hold-all-the-cards.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What makes a smart city even smarter? Shared edge infrastructure</title><link href="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/blog/discover/2022/05/17/shared-edge-infrastruture.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What makes a smart city even smarter? Shared edge infrastructure" /><published>2022-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://new-website.sixsq.ch/blog/discover/2022/05/17/shared-edge-infrastruture</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/blog/discover/2022/05/17/shared-edge-infrastruture.html"><![CDATA[<h4 id="create-a-future-proof-solution-for-your-smart-city-by-implementing-a-shared-infrastructure">Create a future-proof solution for your smart city by implementing a shared infrastructure</h4>

<p>You can find many, many <a href="https://media.sixsq.com/blog/what-is-a-smart-city">smart cities</a> that share a common architecture. They have one or many sensors producing data. And this data needs to be processed in real time to provide insights, either to take action or to predict trends.</p>

<p>Let me introduce you to the fascinating work we’re doing in the Swiss city of Geneva, partnering with <a href="https://securaxis.com/">Securaxis</a>, who provide sound analytics for smart cities, <a href="https://www.hesge.ch/hepia/">HEPIA</a>, Geneva’s university of landscape, engineering and architecture, and HEG, the city’s school of business administration. In the context of the <a href="https://www.hesge.ch/hepia/recherche-developpement/projets-recherche/en-cours/medina">MEDInA</a> project, we’re using the Securaxis SONAL machine learning app to measure sound so we can monitor and categorise traffic. We’re also using cameras and more machine learning from <a href="https://www.hesge.ch/heg/">HEG</a> to understand traffic lanes. Combined, this provides valuable real-time insights into traffic flow and helps to control street lighting to provide safer streets while saving energy.</p>

<p>Another example comes from the gorgeous Italian <a href="https://www.cittametropolitana.fi.it/">City of Florence</a> where, in the context of the <a href="https://elastic-project.eu/">ELASTIC</a> project, with partners such as <a href="https://www.thalesgroup.com/en/markets/transport">Thales</a> providing smart sensors for transportation, <a href="https://www.bsc.es/">Barcelona Supercomputing Center</a>, <a href="https://informationcatalyst.com/">ICE</a> and <a href="https://www.ikerlan.es/en/">Ikerlan</a>, we are providing a range of new services on the city’s tram network. One of these services is predictive maintenance – we use laser scanners on the rails to monitor rail profile degradation to predict the need for maintenance operations. Another is synchronisation of traffic intersections to favour public transport traffic while minimising impact on all other traffic. And a third is providing proactive driver assistance with real-time emergency alerts in case of intrusion onto the tram path.</p>

<h2 id="but-what-are-the-really-smart-cities-doing">But what are the really smart cities doing?</h2>

<p>The really smart cities do more than share a common architecture. The also share edge infrastructure.</p>

<p>Their IT architectural anatomy includes:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Sensors</li>
  <li>Processing unit (an edge device)</li>
  <li>Communication (to enable edge-to-cloud and/or edge-to-edge)</li>
  <li>Cloud (to aggregate information)</li>
  <li>And of course apps or algorithms (to process data and take actions)</li>
</ol>

<p>It is extremely wasteful to replicate this architecture for each and every use case – all the applications mentioned above plus many more, such as measuring air quality and monitoring temperature and sound pollution.</p>

<p>Think of the energy consumed in manufacturing all this redundant hardware… and the energy needed to power it. And what if new use cases come along that require mixing or fusing different data (say, audio and video to identify the source of traffic accidents or noisy or polluting vehicles)? If everything is built in silos, interoperability is much harder, and with independent systems there can be no cost sharing and only limited economies of scale to improve the ROI.</p>

<h2 id="sharing-edge-infrastructure-to-take-actions-in-real-time">Sharing edge infrastructure to take actions in real time</h2>
<p>Instead, what makes much more sense is to use a shared edge infrastructure. This means that sensors are connected to a multi-tenant edge computing unit, able to host several apps or algorithms, connected to a range of sensors. It also means the unit can create many insights which enable the city to take actions in real time.</p>

<p>Further, once smart city operators are able to remotely control this architecture it becomes much more future proof. Updates, upgrades and even new use cases can be deployed with minimal, if any, intrusion into the smart city physical infrastructure.</p>

<h2 id="intelligent-infrastructure--common-sense">Intelligent Infrastructure = common sense</h2>
<p>In North America, people are starting to describe this type of shared edge infrastructure for smart cities as ‘Intelligent Infrastructure’. I call it common sense, since cities must evolve quickly to provide citizens with the level of services they require.</p>

<p>The climate emergency is also accelerating the need for such architecture, since public transport systems must become more inclusive, delivering a greater sense of security along with higher performance. Understanding the impact of inescapable rising temperatures is also essential and, for this, situational awareness and behaviour trend analysis are key. As discussed in previous blogs, only edge computing is capable of doing all this while also protecting citizen privacy.</p>

<p>We at SixSq have the technology and a growing ecosystem to address these challenges. Get in touch if you want to better understand what benefits a shared edge infrastructure can bring to your community. .</p>]]></content><author><name>Marc-Elian Bégin</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="edge" /><category term="cloud" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Create a future-proof solution for your smart city by implementing a shared infrastructure You can find many, many smart cities that share a common architecture. They have one or many sensors producing data. And this data needs to be processed in real time to provide insights, either to take action or to predict trends. Let me introduce you to the fascinating work we’re doing in the Swiss city of Geneva, partnering with Securaxis, who provide sound analytics for smart cities, HEPIA, Geneva’s university of landscape, engineering and architecture, and HEG, the city’s school of business administration. In the context of the MEDInA project, we’re using the Securaxis SONAL machine learning app to measure sound so we can monitor and categorise traffic. We’re also using cameras and more machine learning from HEG to understand traffic lanes. Combined, this provides valuable real-time insights into traffic flow and helps to control street lighting to provide safer streets while saving energy. Another example comes from the gorgeous Italian City of Florence where, in the context of the ELASTIC project, with partners such as Thales providing smart sensors for transportation, Barcelona Supercomputing Center, ICE and Ikerlan, we are providing a range of new services on the city’s tram network. One of these services is predictive maintenance – we use laser scanners on the rails to monitor rail profile degradation to predict the need for maintenance operations. Another is synchronisation of traffic intersections to favour public transport traffic while minimising impact on all other traffic. And a third is providing proactive driver assistance with real-time emergency alerts in case of intrusion onto the tram path. But what are the really smart cities doing? The really smart cities do more than share a common architecture. The also share edge infrastructure. Their IT architectural anatomy includes: Sensors Processing unit (an edge device) Communication (to enable edge-to-cloud and/or edge-to-edge) Cloud (to aggregate information) And of course apps or algorithms (to process data and take actions) It is extremely wasteful to replicate this architecture for each and every use case – all the applications mentioned above plus many more, such as measuring air quality and monitoring temperature and sound pollution. Think of the energy consumed in manufacturing all this redundant hardware… and the energy needed to power it. And what if new use cases come along that require mixing or fusing different data (say, audio and video to identify the source of traffic accidents or noisy or polluting vehicles)? If everything is built in silos, interoperability is much harder, and with independent systems there can be no cost sharing and only limited economies of scale to improve the ROI. Sharing edge infrastructure to take actions in real time Instead, what makes much more sense is to use a shared edge infrastructure. This means that sensors are connected to a multi-tenant edge computing unit, able to host several apps or algorithms, connected to a range of sensors. It also means the unit can create many insights which enable the city to take actions in real time. Further, once smart city operators are able to remotely control this architecture it becomes much more future proof. Updates, upgrades and even new use cases can be deployed with minimal, if any, intrusion into the smart city physical infrastructure. Intelligent Infrastructure = common sense In North America, people are starting to describe this type of shared edge infrastructure for smart cities as ‘Intelligent Infrastructure’. I call it common sense, since cities must evolve quickly to provide citizens with the level of services they require. The climate emergency is also accelerating the need for such architecture, since public transport systems must become more inclusive, delivering a greater sense of security along with higher performance. Understanding the impact of inescapable rising temperatures is also essential and, for this, situational awareness and behaviour trend analysis are key. As discussed in previous blogs, only edge computing is capable of doing all this while also protecting citizen privacy. We at SixSq have the technology and a growing ecosystem to address these challenges. Get in touch if you want to better understand what benefits a shared edge infrastructure can bring to your community. .]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/shared_infrastructure.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/shared_infrastructure.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Taking off with edge computing? Don’t clip your own wings</title><link href="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/blog/discover/2022/05/17/taking-off-with-edge-computing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Taking off with edge computing? Don’t clip your own wings" /><published>2022-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://new-website.sixsq.ch/blog/discover/2022/05/17/taking-off-with-edge-computing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/blog/discover/2022/05/17/taking-off-with-edge-computing.html"><![CDATA[<h4 id="considering-an-edge-solution-read-on-for-tips-and-potential-pitfalls">Considering an edge solution? Read on for tips and potential pitfalls.</h4>

<p>A pilot entering cloudy, turbulent skies is effectively flying blind. It’s a critical situation. Every moment that ticks by without clear visibility means things can change and danger levels increase. It may become impossible to reach the destination airport. Data is needed immediately – facts about the aircraft, its status, position, nearby hazards, and weather conditions – so the pilot is able to proceed without guesswork and regain full control.</p>

<p>As a private pilot, I know a lot about airplanes but I’d never trust myself to build one and take to the skies! A do-it-yourself (DIY) solution – even one made from excellent parts – carries too much risk. I feel the same is true for edge computing.</p>

<p>Too many times, I’ve seen DIY edge solutions fail. Companies realise too late the downsides of unbudgeted cost, protracted time to readiness and operational complexity. And they clip their own wings by sacrificing system reliability and evolvability.</p>

<p>I guess people are tempted to self-build because edge computing seems similar to cloud computing. Sure, they share several attributes but they’re also very different.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/blog/airplanes.png" alt="airplanes" /></p>

<p class="caption">Through my aeroclub, I’m not limited to flying just one type of aircraft. I like to keep my options open.</p>

<p>Take, for example, the physical environment. Cloud computing happens in highly controlled locations with easy-to-access servers. But the edge is challenged by temperature and humidity changes, dust and vibration. Unregulated settings get power and network jitters, have more cyber-security risk and can be complex to access.</p>

<p>Instead of a DIY edge solution, some organisations ask a vertical solution provider to solve a specific use case. The danger here is a significant investment with little flexibility in the future. As business needs evolve, the original solution may not adapt. A flexibility promise might be made but it will be on the provider’s terms, with limited powers of negotiation.</p>

<p>An obvious alternative is a cloud-first approach. Start with a cloud from one of the hyperscalers (Amazon, Microsoft Azure or Google) or a private cloud, and deploy at the edge as mandated. <strong>Warning!</strong> There is a conflict of interest. While you seek the best possible edge outcomes, these providers are in the business of selling compute and storage. They want you to pump as much data as possible to the cloud. So you’ll miss what’s arguably the <a href="/blog/free-your-business-critical-data-from-the-cloud">No.1 benefit of edge computing</a>: processing raw data near its source.</p>

<p>Cloud-first can work for simple deployments but – once again – you risk clipping your own wings. As your business needs grow in scale and sophistication (trust me, they will), a cloud approach quickly limits your ability to expand. At which point, you may regret putting all your eggs in the same cloud basket.</p>

<p>So the optimal approach is edge-first and cloud-neutral. This aims to privilege the edge (instead of the cloud) because this is where you act on your data. An edge-first solution does not limit your ability to process, transform, aggregate and anonymise the data. On the contrary, it generally empowers developers with a wide range of tools (including machine learning) to take full advantage of the data produced at the edge and act on it. And you do all this on your own terms while also leveraging the unlimited processing power and storage of the cloud. You get the best of both worlds – edge and cloud.</p>

<p>Another way to keep your options open, ensuring the most future-proof edge experience, is to select a provider offering <a href="https://nuvla.io">OPEX</a> over CAPEX. Added to this, edge-first providers are likely to help you deploy a shared infrastructure strategy. This allows several old and new apps from different sources to run alongside each other at the edge, which is likely to generate a very attractive return on investment.</p>

<p>One final thought. <strong>Data sovereignty</strong> matters. Keeping tight control of where your data gets processed is strategic for many organisations. A key decision is which parts of your data will be processed at the edge and which in the cloud. The solution you select must give you the right level of control over your data flows.</p>

<p>An edge-first, cloud-neutral approach means you won’t clip your own wings. We will be happy to help you on your journey to the edge. So please get in touch for lock-in free, future-proofed advice.</p>]]></content><author><name>Marc-Elian Bégin</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="edge" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Considering an edge solution? Read on for tips and potential pitfalls. A pilot entering cloudy, turbulent skies is effectively flying blind. It’s a critical situation. Every moment that ticks by without clear visibility means things can change and danger levels increase. It may become impossible to reach the destination airport. Data is needed immediately – facts about the aircraft, its status, position, nearby hazards, and weather conditions – so the pilot is able to proceed without guesswork and regain full control. As a private pilot, I know a lot about airplanes but I’d never trust myself to build one and take to the skies! A do-it-yourself (DIY) solution – even one made from excellent parts – carries too much risk. I feel the same is true for edge computing. Too many times, I’ve seen DIY edge solutions fail. Companies realise too late the downsides of unbudgeted cost, protracted time to readiness and operational complexity. And they clip their own wings by sacrificing system reliability and evolvability. I guess people are tempted to self-build because edge computing seems similar to cloud computing. Sure, they share several attributes but they’re also very different. Through my aeroclub, I’m not limited to flying just one type of aircraft. I like to keep my options open. Take, for example, the physical environment. Cloud computing happens in highly controlled locations with easy-to-access servers. But the edge is challenged by temperature and humidity changes, dust and vibration. Unregulated settings get power and network jitters, have more cyber-security risk and can be complex to access. Instead of a DIY edge solution, some organisations ask a vertical solution provider to solve a specific use case. The danger here is a significant investment with little flexibility in the future. As business needs evolve, the original solution may not adapt. A flexibility promise might be made but it will be on the provider’s terms, with limited powers of negotiation. An obvious alternative is a cloud-first approach. Start with a cloud from one of the hyperscalers (Amazon, Microsoft Azure or Google) or a private cloud, and deploy at the edge as mandated. Warning! There is a conflict of interest. While you seek the best possible edge outcomes, these providers are in the business of selling compute and storage. They want you to pump as much data as possible to the cloud. So you’ll miss what’s arguably the No.1 benefit of edge computing: processing raw data near its source. Cloud-first can work for simple deployments but – once again – you risk clipping your own wings. As your business needs grow in scale and sophistication (trust me, they will), a cloud approach quickly limits your ability to expand. At which point, you may regret putting all your eggs in the same cloud basket. So the optimal approach is edge-first and cloud-neutral. This aims to privilege the edge (instead of the cloud) because this is where you act on your data. An edge-first solution does not limit your ability to process, transform, aggregate and anonymise the data. On the contrary, it generally empowers developers with a wide range of tools (including machine learning) to take full advantage of the data produced at the edge and act on it. And you do all this on your own terms while also leveraging the unlimited processing power and storage of the cloud. You get the best of both worlds – edge and cloud. Another way to keep your options open, ensuring the most future-proof edge experience, is to select a provider offering OPEX over CAPEX. Added to this, edge-first providers are likely to help you deploy a shared infrastructure strategy. This allows several old and new apps from different sources to run alongside each other at the edge, which is likely to generate a very attractive return on investment. One final thought. Data sovereignty matters. Keeping tight control of where your data gets processed is strategic for many organisations. A key decision is which parts of your data will be processed at the edge and which in the cloud. The solution you select must give you the right level of control over your data flows. An edge-first, cloud-neutral approach means you won’t clip your own wings. We will be happy to help you on your journey to the edge. So please get in touch for lock-in free, future-proofed advice.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/featured-image-blog-wings.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://new-website.sixsq.ch/featured-image-blog-wings.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>