<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://sixsq.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://sixsq.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-05-05T12:04:57+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">SixSq Website</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Introducing our new Marketing &amp;amp; Communications Manager</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/03/27/news-rebecca-schenato.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing our new Marketing &amp;amp; Communications Manager" /><published>2023-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/news/2023/03/27/news-rebecca-schenato</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/03/27/news-rebecca-schenato.html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>On 13 March 2023, Rebecca Schenato took up her role as Marketing &amp; Communications Manager in Geneva</strong></p>

<p>SixSq is excited to announce that Rebecca Schenato has joined the team as Marketing &amp; Communications Manager. Rebecca brings a wealth of experience in making tech brands shine with a proven track record of in IoT and B2B sectors. Her creative marketing approach will help bring the company to the next level, delivering an outstanding experience to current and potential users and customers.</p>

<p>Commenting on her appointment, Rebecca said, <em>“It is a pleasure to be part of the SixSq team and Ekinops ecosystem.  I am thrilled to have the opportunity of contributing to the growth and vision of the company. There is a lot of great potential ahead, and I am looking forward to working together towards the accomplishment of the company’s ambitions”</em>.</p>

<p>As Marketing &amp; Communications Manager Rebecca will be a major contributor to ensure our messaging continues to be clear and crisp, while translating the company’s business objectives into actionable marketing strategies.</p>

<p>SixSq CEO, Marc-Elian Bégin said, <em>“Rebecca is the perfect complement to the team, bringing a wealth of relevant experience and energy. She will be instrumental in forging a path towards our ambitious growth objectives”</em>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[On 13 March 2023, Rebecca Schenato took up her role as Marketing &amp; Communications Manager in Geneva SixSq is excited to announce that Rebecca Schenato has joined the team as Marketing &amp; Communications Manager. Rebecca brings a wealth of experience in making tech brands shine with a proven track record of in IoT and B2B sectors. Her creative marketing approach will help bring the company to the next level, delivering an outstanding experience to current and potential users and customers. Commenting on her appointment, Rebecca said, “It is a pleasure to be part of the SixSq team and Ekinops ecosystem. I am thrilled to have the opportunity of contributing to the growth and vision of the company. There is a lot of great potential ahead, and I am looking forward to working together towards the accomplishment of the company’s ambitions”. As Marketing &amp; Communications Manager Rebecca will be a major contributor to ensure our messaging continues to be clear and crisp, while translating the company’s business objectives into actionable marketing strategies. SixSq CEO, Marc-Elian Bégin said, “Rebecca is the perfect complement to the team, bringing a wealth of relevant experience and energy. She will be instrumental in forging a path towards our ambitious growth objectives”.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/rebecca-schenato.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/rebecca-schenato.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Varnish Software now available on SixSq’s Nuvla Marketplace</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/01/25/news-varnish.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Varnish Software now available on SixSq’s Nuvla Marketplace" /><published>2023-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/news/2023/01/25/news-varnish</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/01/25/news-varnish.html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>SixSq Users Now Have Access to Varnish Software’s Most Powerful Caching and CDN Solutions Via the Nuvla Marketplace</strong></p>

<p><strong>Geneva and Los Angeles - 25 January 2023</strong> SixSq, an <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/">Ekinops</a> Company, and <a href="https://www.varnish-software.com/">Varnish Software</a>, a leader in caching, streaming and content delivery software solutions,  today announced a partnership to integrate and deliver Varnish Software’s feature-rich suite of web cache and HTTP accelerator solutions - <a href="https://www.varnish-software.com/solutions/varnish-enterprise/">Varnish Enterprise</a> - via the Nuvla platform and marketplace. This integration significantly simplifies the procurement, deployment and management of Varnish Software’s technology, enabling new capabilities and unparalleled performance for SixSq customers and their users at the edge.</p>

<p>By utilizing the <a href="https://sixsq.com/marketplace">Nuvla Marketplace</a> to deploy Varnish Software, telecom operators and CSPs in any location can now flawlessly deliver lightning-fast, high-quality web and streaming experiences while significantly lowering costs and hardware requirements across an entire ecosystem of distributed edges.</p>

<p><em>“Service providers require consistent and reliable speed and performance to deliver excellent web experiences for users, at scale,”</em> said Irene Lundin, Chief Delivery Officer at Varnish Software. <em>“Nuvla speeds up the way we can deliver Varnish Software by simplifying the deployment and maintenance process. We are now better equipped to deliver next-gen connectivity wherever it is needed, anywhere in the world.”</em></p>

<p>The new integration is part of a broader collaboration between the two companies to bridge 5G satellite communications with advanced web caching and content delivery at the edge, which includes contributions to the European Broadcasting Union (EBU)’s <a href="https://www.ebu.ch/news/2022/06/esa-and-ebu-to-build-solutions-for-emerging-satellite-enabled-5g-media-market">5G-EMERGE consortium</a>.</p>

<p><em>“Our partnership with Varnish Software perfectly demonstrates the value of app delivery using the Nuvla Marketplace,”</em> said Marc-Elian Bégin, SixSq CEO and Co-founder. <em>“Customers from any business sector can now deploy Varnish Software’s caching app at the telco edge, near edge as well as far edge, with a direct and measurable positive impact on the digital experience of users.”</em></p>

<p>Importantly, Varnish Enterprise is the only software that can provide an edge runtime environment, enabling operators to write and execute compute logic as close to the end user as possible in mere microseconds. It can be installed in front of any server that accepts requests via HTTP/HTTPS to significantly speed up response time by an impressive 300 – 1000%, and reduce backend server load by up to 99%.</p>

<p>SixSq’s Nuvla is a proven B2B digital platform for industrialization and automation of containerized edge applications and device management. The Nuvla app vendor program gives app vendors and customers tools to interact in a seamless way, including clear pricing and contractual terms. It also provides hassle-free monetization of business applications for telcos, service providers and system integrators.</p>

<p>With Varnish Enterprise available on the Nuvla Marketplace, companies can now deploy, manage and update an enterprise-grade caching solution to deliver a high-quality digital experience, remotely and securely. The purchasing and deployment process is fast, simple and robust, with the app deployed at scale in a few clicks via the Nuvla dashboard.</p>

<p>The service is available via a pay-as-you-go subscription. Varnish Enterprise can be found on the Nuvla Marketplace <a href="https://nuvla.io/ui/apps/varnish">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[SixSq Users Now Have Access to Varnish Software’s Most Powerful Caching and CDN Solutions Via the Nuvla Marketplace Geneva and Los Angeles - 25 January 2023 SixSq, an Ekinops Company, and Varnish Software, a leader in caching, streaming and content delivery software solutions, today announced a partnership to integrate and deliver Varnish Software’s feature-rich suite of web cache and HTTP accelerator solutions - Varnish Enterprise - via the Nuvla platform and marketplace. This integration significantly simplifies the procurement, deployment and management of Varnish Software’s technology, enabling new capabilities and unparalleled performance for SixSq customers and their users at the edge. By utilizing the Nuvla Marketplace to deploy Varnish Software, telecom operators and CSPs in any location can now flawlessly deliver lightning-fast, high-quality web and streaming experiences while significantly lowering costs and hardware requirements across an entire ecosystem of distributed edges. “Service providers require consistent and reliable speed and performance to deliver excellent web experiences for users, at scale,” said Irene Lundin, Chief Delivery Officer at Varnish Software. “Nuvla speeds up the way we can deliver Varnish Software by simplifying the deployment and maintenance process. We are now better equipped to deliver next-gen connectivity wherever it is needed, anywhere in the world.” The new integration is part of a broader collaboration between the two companies to bridge 5G satellite communications with advanced web caching and content delivery at the edge, which includes contributions to the European Broadcasting Union (EBU)’s 5G-EMERGE consortium. “Our partnership with Varnish Software perfectly demonstrates the value of app delivery using the Nuvla Marketplace,” said Marc-Elian Bégin, SixSq CEO and Co-founder. “Customers from any business sector can now deploy Varnish Software’s caching app at the telco edge, near edge as well as far edge, with a direct and measurable positive impact on the digital experience of users.” Importantly, Varnish Enterprise is the only software that can provide an edge runtime environment, enabling operators to write and execute compute logic as close to the end user as possible in mere microseconds. It can be installed in front of any server that accepts requests via HTTP/HTTPS to significantly speed up response time by an impressive 300 – 1000%, and reduce backend server load by up to 99%. SixSq’s Nuvla is a proven B2B digital platform for industrialization and automation of containerized edge applications and device management. The Nuvla app vendor program gives app vendors and customers tools to interact in a seamless way, including clear pricing and contractual terms. It also provides hassle-free monetization of business applications for telcos, service providers and system integrators. With Varnish Enterprise available on the Nuvla Marketplace, companies can now deploy, manage and update an enterprise-grade caching solution to deliver a high-quality digital experience, remotely and securely. The purchasing and deployment process is fast, simple and robust, with the app deployed at scale in a few clicks via the Nuvla dashboard. The service is available via a pay-as-you-go subscription. Varnish Enterprise can be found on the Nuvla Marketplace here.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/app-vendor-varnish.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/app-vendor-varnish.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">LatenceTech now available on SixSq’s Nuvla Marketplace</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/01/12/news-latencetech.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LatenceTech now available on SixSq’s Nuvla Marketplace" /><published>2023-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/news/2023/01/12/news-latencetech</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/news/2023/01/12/news-latencetech.html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>SixSq’s Nuvla ecosystem facilitates the deployment, management and update of LatenceTech quality of service measurement solution at the edge and in the cloud</strong></p>

<p>Geneva, 12 January 2023. SixSq, an <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/">Ekinops</a> Company, and <a href="https://latencetech.com/">LatenceTech</a> today announced a partnership to deliver LatenceTech QoS via the<a href="/marketplace"> Nuvla Marketplace</a>. This collaboration will allow LatenceTech to quickly and easily market and deploy its technology to service and network providers.</p>

<p>With LatenceTech available in the Nuvla Marketplace, it is now easier for companies to track, predict and deploy latency-optimized 5G and private LTE networks remotely and securely. The purchasing and deployment process is fast, simple, and robust, with the app deployed at scale in a few clicks via the Nuvla dashboard.</p>

<p>SixSq’s Nuvla is a proven B2B digital platform for industrialization and automation of containerized edge applications and device management. The <a href="/news/2022/06/09/news-app-vendor-programme.html">Nuvla App Vendor Program</a> gives app vendors and customers tools to interact in a seamless way, including clear pricing and contractual terms. It also provides hassle-free monetization of business applications for telcos, service providers and system integrators.</p>

<p><em>“Our agreement with SixSq is an important milestone for LatenceTech as it allows our company to market our technology on a large scale on an efficient and well-established platform to our target audiences. We believe that the Nuvla platform is an excellent fit for our technology and business model. We are confident that this partnership between SixSq and LatenceTech will be mutually beneficial, and that it will allow our future customers to benefit from the high value-added advantages of our technology in a simple and quick manner,”</em> said <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/benoitgendron/">Benoit Gendron</a>, President and CEO of LatenceTech.</p>

<p><em>“This partnership with LatenceTech fills an important gap in the ability for service providers to monetize 5G. Now users can accurately and easily measure SLA compliance, something that is paramount when selling high quality services, without taking risks. And all this is a few clicks away using Nuvla”</em> said <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mebster/">Marc-Elian Bégin</a>, SixSq CEO and Co-founder.</p>

<p>The service is available via a pay-as-you-go subscription. You will find LatenceTech on the Nuvla Marketplace <a href="https://nuvla.io/ui/apps/latencetech">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[SixSq’s Nuvla ecosystem facilitates the deployment, management and update of LatenceTech quality of service measurement solution at the edge and in the cloud Geneva, 12 January 2023. SixSq, an Ekinops Company, and LatenceTech today announced a partnership to deliver LatenceTech QoS via the Nuvla Marketplace. This collaboration will allow LatenceTech to quickly and easily market and deploy its technology to service and network providers. With LatenceTech available in the Nuvla Marketplace, it is now easier for companies to track, predict and deploy latency-optimized 5G and private LTE networks remotely and securely. The purchasing and deployment process is fast, simple, and robust, with the app deployed at scale in a few clicks via the Nuvla dashboard. SixSq’s Nuvla is a proven B2B digital platform for industrialization and automation of containerized edge applications and device management. The Nuvla App Vendor Program gives app vendors and customers tools to interact in a seamless way, including clear pricing and contractual terms. It also provides hassle-free monetization of business applications for telcos, service providers and system integrators. “Our agreement with SixSq is an important milestone for LatenceTech as it allows our company to market our technology on a large scale on an efficient and well-established platform to our target audiences. We believe that the Nuvla platform is an excellent fit for our technology and business model. We are confident that this partnership between SixSq and LatenceTech will be mutually beneficial, and that it will allow our future customers to benefit from the high value-added advantages of our technology in a simple and quick manner,” said Benoit Gendron, President and CEO of LatenceTech. “This partnership with LatenceTech fills an important gap in the ability for service providers to monetize 5G. Now users can accurately and easily measure SLA compliance, something that is paramount when selling high quality services, without taking risks. And all this is a few clicks away using Nuvla” said Marc-Elian Bégin, SixSq CEO and Co-founder. The service is available via a pay-as-you-go subscription. You will find LatenceTech on the Nuvla Marketplace here.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/app-vendor-latencetech.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/app-vendor-latencetech.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Killer App For The Edge</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/blog/marketplace/2022/11/25/killer-app-for-the-edge.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Killer App For The Edge" /><published>2022-11-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-11-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/blog/marketplace/2022/11/25/killer-app-for-the-edge</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/blog/marketplace/2022/11/25/killer-app-for-the-edge.html"><![CDATA[<p>For some time, analysts and industry experts have been heralding <a href="/blog/discover/2019/11/08/what-is-edge-computing.html">edge computing</a> as the next big thing that will revolutionise the IT and telecom industries. But for industries to move, there needs to be real and meaningful benefits, achievable within reasonable investment and at an acceptable risk.  It would indeed therefore be great to identify the ‘killer app’ for edge computing – a single heroic app to unlock the full potential of this promising distributed computing paradigm, one that’s capable of fulfilling the level of world domination predicted by analysts. So where is it?</p>

<p>Perhaps this is the wrong question. If we stand back, the edge is not there to run a single all-encompassing, killer app, but to enable an ecosystem of applications that allows organisations to better extract value from data near its source. And this objective is neither simple nor standard, since, like us humans, every business is different, with different goals, constraints and assets. However, edge computing will not succeed if all its implementations are bespoke. The good news is that there is an existing ecosystem that exhibits a similar need for wide and wild variety, yet is based on standardised building blocks that tech companies can provide at affordable pricing, thanks to economy of scale.</p>

<p>Where is this ecosystem? I suggest looking in your pocket. The dominance of the smartphone appliance is no longer questioned today… yet what about all those apps? Your mobile device is not satisfied with a one-size-fits-all killer app, so why should your edge infrastructure be any different?</p>

<h3 id="learning-from-the-apple-app-store">Learning from the Apple® App Store</h3>

<p>Apparently, even the mighty Steve Jobs didn’t initially foresee the rise of the App Store as a key part of the iPhone®’s success story, instead expecting web apps to be the next big thing. Apple® had to move quickly to meet developer demands, opening up the iPhone® ecosystem to allow these people to create native iOS apps and this, in turn, led to the creation of the App Store to monetise these apps and make them available to customers.</p>

<h3 id="the-first-marketplace-for-edge-apps">The first marketplace for edge apps</h3>

<p>For edge computing to work well, businesses need a simple and scalable way to purchase apps and immediately deploy them where their data is. But of course no-one needs integration complexity, complicated contractual negotiations and operational risk.</p>

<p>Here at SixSq we’re now on a similar path to Apple®, building the world’s first repository of edge apps, the Nuvla Marketplace, usefully informed by the experiences of the App Store, Google Play® and other digital distribution platforms.</p>

<h3 id="app-vendors">App vendors</h3>

<p>Since June 2022, we’ve been fostering strong relationships with some of the best creative minds in edge computing app development through the SixSq App Vendor Programme. These specialists don’t pull any punches – their powerful apps are oriented to omnipresent AI, steely <a href="https://sixsq.com/news/2022/06/13/news-aiedgelabs.html">cyber defence</a>, operational optimisation and predictive analytics to meet business challenges head on. I’m talking about reducing latency, overcoming bandwidth challenges, increasing autonomy, ensuring data sovereignty, cutting the carbon footprint and more.</p>

<p>To de-risk projects and ensure future-proofed solutions, we’re all about standardised operational, technical and contractual app development within a systematic framework for an open, frictionless ecosystem.</p>

<h3 id="the-source-of-killer-apps-for-the-edge">The source of killer apps for the edge</h3>

<p>Together this makes the <a href="/marketplace">Nuvla Marketplace</a> the go-to source of business-ready apps, provided and maintained by domain experts. If you like a dubious metaphor, we at SixSq provide the Tinder app for edge computing and, as the platform operator, we also come on your date as chaperone!</p>

<p>With our approach, vendors can register new apps on the Nuvla Marketplace in a few hours, while you can deploy these apps in seconds and enable your edge devices in minutes. The potential for our edge marketplace to deliver multiple killer apps is real. Of course time will tell, but the telling is already starting. Don’t wait for the killer app, the marketplace delivers a suite of readily-available apps to deliver your business outcomes.</p>]]></content><author><name>Marc-Elian Bégin</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="edge" /><category term="cloud" /><category term="privacy" /><category term="security" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[For some time, analysts and industry experts have been heralding edge computing as the next big thing that will revolutionise the IT and telecom industries. But for industries to move, there needs to be real and meaningful benefits, achievable within reasonable investment and at an acceptable risk. It would indeed therefore be great to identify the ‘killer app’ for edge computing – a single heroic app to unlock the full potential of this promising distributed computing paradigm, one that’s capable of fulfilling the level of world domination predicted by analysts. So where is it? Perhaps this is the wrong question. If we stand back, the edge is not there to run a single all-encompassing, killer app, but to enable an ecosystem of applications that allows organisations to better extract value from data near its source. And this objective is neither simple nor standard, since, like us humans, every business is different, with different goals, constraints and assets. However, edge computing will not succeed if all its implementations are bespoke. The good news is that there is an existing ecosystem that exhibits a similar need for wide and wild variety, yet is based on standardised building blocks that tech companies can provide at affordable pricing, thanks to economy of scale. Where is this ecosystem? I suggest looking in your pocket. The dominance of the smartphone appliance is no longer questioned today… yet what about all those apps? Your mobile device is not satisfied with a one-size-fits-all killer app, so why should your edge infrastructure be any different? Learning from the Apple® App Store Apparently, even the mighty Steve Jobs didn’t initially foresee the rise of the App Store as a key part of the iPhone®’s success story, instead expecting web apps to be the next big thing. Apple® had to move quickly to meet developer demands, opening up the iPhone® ecosystem to allow these people to create native iOS apps and this, in turn, led to the creation of the App Store to monetise these apps and make them available to customers. The first marketplace for edge apps For edge computing to work well, businesses need a simple and scalable way to purchase apps and immediately deploy them where their data is. But of course no-one needs integration complexity, complicated contractual negotiations and operational risk. Here at SixSq we’re now on a similar path to Apple®, building the world’s first repository of edge apps, the Nuvla Marketplace, usefully informed by the experiences of the App Store, Google Play® and other digital distribution platforms. App vendors Since June 2022, we’ve been fostering strong relationships with some of the best creative minds in edge computing app development through the SixSq App Vendor Programme. These specialists don’t pull any punches – their powerful apps are oriented to omnipresent AI, steely cyber defence, operational optimisation and predictive analytics to meet business challenges head on. I’m talking about reducing latency, overcoming bandwidth challenges, increasing autonomy, ensuring data sovereignty, cutting the carbon footprint and more. To de-risk projects and ensure future-proofed solutions, we’re all about standardised operational, technical and contractual app development within a systematic framework for an open, frictionless ecosystem. The source of killer apps for the edge Together this makes the Nuvla Marketplace the go-to source of business-ready apps, provided and maintained by domain experts. If you like a dubious metaphor, we at SixSq provide the Tinder app for edge computing and, as the platform operator, we also come on your date as chaperone! With our approach, vendors can register new apps on the Nuvla Marketplace in a few hours, while you can deploy these apps in seconds and enable your edge devices in minutes. The potential for our edge marketplace to deliver multiple killer apps is real. Of course time will tell, but the telling is already starting. Don’t wait for the killer app, the marketplace delivers a suite of readily-available apps to deliver your business outcomes.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/marketplace.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/marketplace.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">ICOS; Removing boundaries between IoT, Edge and Cloud</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2022/11/16/icos-remove-boundaries-between-iot-edge-cloud.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ICOS; Removing boundaries between IoT, Edge and Cloud" /><published>2022-11-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-11-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2022/11/16/icos-remove-boundaries-between-iot-edge-cloud</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2022/11/16/icos-remove-boundaries-between-iot-edge-cloud.html"><![CDATA[<p>The first <a href="/rd/icos.html">ICOS</a> face-to-face meeting took place earlier this month in sunny Vilanova I la Geltru, Catalunya, Spain, uniting more than 20 Consortium partners including SixSq. This <a href="https://research-and-innovation.ec.europa.eu/funding/funding-opportunities/funding-programmes-and-open-calls/horizon-europe_en">Horizon Europe</a> project has the ambition of delivering a Meta-Operating System within 3 years, bridging IoT devices to the cloud through <a href="https://sixsq.com/blog/discover/2019/11/08/what-is-edge-computing.html">edge computing</a> devices.</p>

<p>ICOS, code name for ‘IoT2Cloud Operating System’, is a unique computing system supporting the interconnection of IoT, edge and cloud resources.</p>

<p>The concept of a continuum between IoT, edge and cloud aims to tackle the challenges linked to the ever-growing sector of computing and sensing devices, and to the increasing demand for data-intensive applications, especially at the edge and in the cloud.</p>

<p>By enabling this continuum, in a way which is both technology and device-agnostic, ICOS will facilitate data generation, transfer, and processing - thanks to AI.</p>

<p>ICOS System architecture, functional requirements and use cases were at the heart of the discussions during this 2-day meeting. Indeed, ICOS will address real-life challenges in various fields, with a positive impact on reliability and sustainability.</p>

<p>4 relevant <a href="https://www.icos-project.eu/use-cases">use cases</a> were brought by project partners:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Bring precision agriculture to the next step by embarking ICOS into agricultural robots, or agrobots, in the fields. Thanks to AI modules, the robots will be able to detect a disease among a plantation, calculate the real amount of fertiliser needed by each plant, etc.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Improve railway maintenance thanks to a combination of IoT sensors and edge devices, enabling real-time monitoring of the infrastructure metrics and optimising decision-making process.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Enhance “in-car” user experience thanks to immersive content display linked to touristic trips, and shared media streaming.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Optimise household energy consumption thanks to an autonomous system based on continuum management.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Fruitful interactions took place during the “ICOS match” workshop between technologies and user stories. The SixSq team was glad to see that <a href="/platform">Nuvla</a>/<a href="https://sixsq.com/nuvlaedge">NuvlaEdge</a> had a lot of matches and will bring value to all of the use cases in the project by facilitating management of IoT devices and applications.</p>

<p>Thanks to this working group, all Consortium members (technology and use cases providers) had a chance to draw a mental map of the combination of technologies needed to perform each use case.</p>

<p>Finally, these two days were a great opportunity for partners to meet in-person, but also to taste Catalan gastronomy – especially tapas!</p>

<p>Next step from our side: start working on the component that will be used to manage edge devices, and data flow through the IoT to cloud continuum. We are looking forward to bringing further updates during the life of the project.</p>]]></content><author><name>Agathe Veillon</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="edge" /><category term="cloud" /><category term="iot" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first ICOS face-to-face meeting took place earlier this month in sunny Vilanova I la Geltru, Catalunya, Spain, uniting more than 20 Consortium partners including SixSq. This Horizon Europe project has the ambition of delivering a Meta-Operating System within 3 years, bridging IoT devices to the cloud through edge computing devices. ICOS, code name for ‘IoT2Cloud Operating System’, is a unique computing system supporting the interconnection of IoT, edge and cloud resources. The concept of a continuum between IoT, edge and cloud aims to tackle the challenges linked to the ever-growing sector of computing and sensing devices, and to the increasing demand for data-intensive applications, especially at the edge and in the cloud. By enabling this continuum, in a way which is both technology and device-agnostic, ICOS will facilitate data generation, transfer, and processing - thanks to AI. ICOS System architecture, functional requirements and use cases were at the heart of the discussions during this 2-day meeting. Indeed, ICOS will address real-life challenges in various fields, with a positive impact on reliability and sustainability. 4 relevant use cases were brought by project partners: Bring precision agriculture to the next step by embarking ICOS into agricultural robots, or agrobots, in the fields. Thanks to AI modules, the robots will be able to detect a disease among a plantation, calculate the real amount of fertiliser needed by each plant, etc. Improve railway maintenance thanks to a combination of IoT sensors and edge devices, enabling real-time monitoring of the infrastructure metrics and optimising decision-making process. Enhance “in-car” user experience thanks to immersive content display linked to touristic trips, and shared media streaming. Optimise household energy consumption thanks to an autonomous system based on continuum management. Fruitful interactions took place during the “ICOS match” workshop between technologies and user stories. The SixSq team was glad to see that Nuvla/NuvlaEdge had a lot of matches and will bring value to all of the use cases in the project by facilitating management of IoT devices and applications. Thanks to this working group, all Consortium members (technology and use cases providers) had a chance to draw a mental map of the combination of technologies needed to perform each use case. Finally, these two days were a great opportunity for partners to meet in-person, but also to taste Catalan gastronomy – especially tapas! Next step from our side: start working on the component that will be used to manage edge devices, and data flow through the IoT to cloud continuum. We are looking forward to bringing further updates during the life of the project.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/logo-ICOS.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/logo-ICOS.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Relimetrics joins app vendor programme</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/news/2022/09/29/news-relimetrics.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Relimetrics joins app vendor programme" /><published>2022-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/news/2022/09/29/news-relimetrics</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/news/2022/09/29/news-relimetrics.html"><![CDATA[<p>SixSq, an <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/">Ekinops</a> Company, and <a href="https://www.relimetrics.com/">Relimetrics</a> today announced a partnership to deliver <a href="https://www.relimetrics.com/applications">ReliVision</a> via the <a href="/marketplace">Nuvla Marketplace</a>. This collaboration significantly simplifies the procurement, deployment, and management of Relimetric’s ReliVision on the factory floor.</p>

<p>Relimetrics helps companies transform how they design and build products by using cutting edge technologies such as computer vision, machine learning, AI and edge computing. The result is a level of quality control automation that is unmatched in the market today, which is quick, simple and cheap to configure and enable. Once in place, users take advantage of the no-code ReliVision solution to enable quality automation for their assembly.</p>

<p><em>“Nuvla allows ReliVision to be offered to manufacturers using a simple pay-as-you-go model. This means customers can choose when to use ReliVision and get Nuvla to quickly deploy ReliVision modules on the shop floor, leveraging existing hardware.”</em> said <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kemallevi/">Kemal Levi</a>, CEO and Founder of Relimetrics.</p>

<p>With Relimetrics’ ReliVision made available in the Nuvla Marketplace, companies can deploy, manage, and update their quality automation application remotely and securely. The purchasing and deployment process is fast, simple and robust, with the app deployed at scale in a few clicks via the <a href="/platform">Nuvla</a> dashboard.</p>

<p><em>“Helping domain matter experts like Relimetrics to scale across industries is why we created Nuvla. Once the <a href="/nuvlaedge">NuvlaEdge</a> software is installed on the edge infrastructure, customers can deploy the most advanced quality automation solution for assembly lines with Relimetrics’s ReliVision”</em> said <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mebster/">Marc-Elian Bégin</a>, SixSq CEO and Co-founder.</p>

<p>This announcement enriches the <a href="/news/2022/06/09/news-app-vendor-programme.html">Nuvla App Vendor Programme</a>, announced earlier this year. The service is available via a pay-as-you-go subscription. You will find Relimetric’s ReliVision edge application on the Nuvla Marketplace <a href="https://nuvla.io/ui/apps/relimetrics">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[SixSq, an Ekinops Company, and Relimetrics today announced a partnership to deliver ReliVision via the Nuvla Marketplace. This collaboration significantly simplifies the procurement, deployment, and management of Relimetric’s ReliVision on the factory floor. Relimetrics helps companies transform how they design and build products by using cutting edge technologies such as computer vision, machine learning, AI and edge computing. The result is a level of quality control automation that is unmatched in the market today, which is quick, simple and cheap to configure and enable. Once in place, users take advantage of the no-code ReliVision solution to enable quality automation for their assembly. “Nuvla allows ReliVision to be offered to manufacturers using a simple pay-as-you-go model. This means customers can choose when to use ReliVision and get Nuvla to quickly deploy ReliVision modules on the shop floor, leveraging existing hardware.” said Kemal Levi, CEO and Founder of Relimetrics. With Relimetrics’ ReliVision made available in the Nuvla Marketplace, companies can deploy, manage, and update their quality automation application remotely and securely. The purchasing and deployment process is fast, simple and robust, with the app deployed at scale in a few clicks via the Nuvla dashboard. “Helping domain matter experts like Relimetrics to scale across industries is why we created Nuvla. Once the NuvlaEdge software is installed on the edge infrastructure, customers can deploy the most advanced quality automation solution for assembly lines with Relimetrics’s ReliVision” said Marc-Elian Bégin, SixSq CEO and Co-founder. This announcement enriches the Nuvla App Vendor Programme, announced earlier this year. The service is available via a pay-as-you-go subscription. You will find Relimetric’s ReliVision edge application on the Nuvla Marketplace here.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/app-vendor-relimetrics.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/app-vendor-relimetrics.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Kadiska joins app vendor programme</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/news/2022/09/13/news-kadiska.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kadiska joins app vendor programme" /><published>2022-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/news/2022/09/13/news-kadiska</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/news/2022/09/13/news-kadiska.html"><![CDATA[<p>SixSq, an <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/">Ekinops</a> company that provides the <a href="https://sixsq.com/platform">Nuvla</a> edge-to-cloud management platform, and <a href="https://kadiska.com/">Kadiska</a>, the SaaS platform for digital experience monitoring, today announced a partnership that allows enterprises to instantly gain performance visibility into networks connecting their sites, clouds and business-critical web and SaaS applications.</p>

<p>SD WAN, hybrid and cloud networks now account for the majority of business connections, while two-thirds of IT organizations report that existing monitoring tools are incapable of detecting and diagnosing issues across these complex, internet-based networks. The result is not only degraded application performance, but also inferior customer digital experience and reduced employee productivity.</p>

<p>Until now, the sheer variety of network appliances, SD-WAN solutions and hybrid connectivity options available have prevented the deployment of network monitoring capabilities that span enterprise edge locations, private and public clouds, and highly distributed cloud-hosted applications. By integrating <a href="https://kadiska.com/products/net-tracer/">Kadiska’s Net-Tracer</a> app into the SixSq Nuvla marketplace, organizations can now immediately deploy in-depth network path and performance monitoring across their entire infrastructure.</p>

<p>The Net-Tracer app is a containerized agent that Nuvla can deploy on edge nodes, clouds, white boxes and SD-WAN devices, including any uCPE powered by Ekinops’ popular <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/products-services/products/compose/oneos6">OneOS6</a> middleware. Once deployed, Net-Tracer continuously maps and monitors all network routes and reports performance degradations, their origin and impact. Users connect to the Kadiska platform to access analytics that correlate network, infrastructure and application performance with users’ digital experience.</p>

<p><em>“Our customers need network performance monitoring, and being able to deploy such capability via an app on
the Nuvla marketplace will be be natural for them. This allows users to quickly identify when and how the
network impacts application performance. The combination of Kadiska’s Net-Tracer app and our zero-touch,
container-based orchestration capabilities allow us to offer a convenient solution to solve this critical challenge
facing IT operations and network teams,”</em> explained <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mebster/">Marc-Elian Bégin</a>, CEO and co-founder at SixSq.</p>

<p><em>“We designed Net-Tracer to fill this specific visibility gap“, added <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gilleshuguenin/">Gilles Huguenin</a>, CEO at Kadiska. “Its
cloud-native implementation makes it simple to deploy across managed clouds and devices. SixSq’s vendor
agnostic orchestration capabilities and popular marketplace was a natural fit for our solution. We look forward
to helping enterprises gain complete control over their modern networks, deliver an amazing digital
experience, and fully profit from their digital platform.”</em></p>

<p>The service is available via a pay-as-you-go subscription. You will find Kadiska’s Net-Tracer Application on the
Nuvla Marketplace <a href="https://nuvla.io/ui/apps/kadiska">here</a>. Learn more about Kadiska’s SixSq integration in <a href="https://kadiska.com/network-performance-monitoring-from-enterprise-edge-to-cloud-web-and-saas-applications-with-sixsq-and-kadiska/">this article</a>.</p>

<p>References:</p>
<p>Enterprise Management Associates (EMA) 2020<p>
<p>NTT Global Services report and Versa 2021<p>
</p></p></p></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[SixSq, an Ekinops company that provides the Nuvla edge-to-cloud management platform, and Kadiska, the SaaS platform for digital experience monitoring, today announced a partnership that allows enterprises to instantly gain performance visibility into networks connecting their sites, clouds and business-critical web and SaaS applications. SD WAN, hybrid and cloud networks now account for the majority of business connections, while two-thirds of IT organizations report that existing monitoring tools are incapable of detecting and diagnosing issues across these complex, internet-based networks. The result is not only degraded application performance, but also inferior customer digital experience and reduced employee productivity. Until now, the sheer variety of network appliances, SD-WAN solutions and hybrid connectivity options available have prevented the deployment of network monitoring capabilities that span enterprise edge locations, private and public clouds, and highly distributed cloud-hosted applications. By integrating Kadiska’s Net-Tracer app into the SixSq Nuvla marketplace, organizations can now immediately deploy in-depth network path and performance monitoring across their entire infrastructure. The Net-Tracer app is a containerized agent that Nuvla can deploy on edge nodes, clouds, white boxes and SD-WAN devices, including any uCPE powered by Ekinops’ popular OneOS6 middleware. Once deployed, Net-Tracer continuously maps and monitors all network routes and reports performance degradations, their origin and impact. Users connect to the Kadiska platform to access analytics that correlate network, infrastructure and application performance with users’ digital experience. “Our customers need network performance monitoring, and being able to deploy such capability via an app on the Nuvla marketplace will be be natural for them. This allows users to quickly identify when and how the network impacts application performance. The combination of Kadiska’s Net-Tracer app and our zero-touch, container-based orchestration capabilities allow us to offer a convenient solution to solve this critical challenge facing IT operations and network teams,” explained Marc-Elian Bégin, CEO and co-founder at SixSq. “We designed Net-Tracer to fill this specific visibility gap“, added Gilles Huguenin, CEO at Kadiska. “Its cloud-native implementation makes it simple to deploy across managed clouds and devices. SixSq’s vendor agnostic orchestration capabilities and popular marketplace was a natural fit for our solution. We look forward to helping enterprises gain complete control over their modern networks, deliver an amazing digital experience, and fully profit from their digital platform.” The service is available via a pay-as-you-go subscription. You will find Kadiska’s Net-Tracer Application on the Nuvla Marketplace here. Learn more about Kadiska’s SixSq integration in this article. References: Enterprise Management Associates (EMA) 2020 NTT Global Services report and Versa 2021]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/app-vendor-kadiska.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/app-vendor-kadiska.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to protect manufacturing from cyber security threats</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/blog/marketplace/2022/08/23/how-to-protect-manufacturing-from-cybersecurity-threats.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to protect manufacturing from cyber security threats" /><published>2022-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/blog/marketplace/2022/08/23/how-to-protect-manufacturing-from-cybersecurity-threats</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/blog/marketplace/2022/08/23/how-to-protect-manufacturing-from-cybersecurity-threats.html"><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to guest author <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/innaushakova/">Inna Ushakova</a> for sharing her valuable insights into the state of cyber security in the manufacturing industry.</p>

<p>Now more than ever, cybersecurity is extremely relevant for the manufacturing industry. IBM’s X-Force Threat Intelligence Index 2022 report found that manufacturing is the most attacked industry as of 2021, receiving the brunt of 23.2% of the attacks and reaching a global average of <strong>$4.24M in data breach costs</strong>.</p>

<p>The manufacturing industry lacks cybersecurity maturity, a fact that criminals exploit relentlessly. This is evidenced by the high-stakes burdens placed on supply chains wreaking havoc on the manufacturing industry, which is still recovering from losses caused by the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>

<p>Instrumental to the wellbeing and healthy performance of any manufacturing company, operational technology (OT) supports core-business operations and its safety is essential to ensure sustainable growth and effective means of innovation. For that to happen, cybersecurity needs to be a key, foundational element of any company’s core strategy. High, rigorous security standards and protocols in data, software, and infrastructure coupled with AI-powered solutions allows for process agility and transparency.</p>

<p>Below,  we detail one of the most high-profile cybersecurity attacks of recent years to illustrate how severe and crucial it is for manufacturing companies to take their security environment seriously.</p>

<h3 id="manufacturing-under-threat">Manufacturing under threat</h3>

<p>The manufacturing industry is victim to ransomware, server access, BEC and data theft, distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attacks, credential harvesting, and more.</p>

<p>Next, let’s see a high profile case of an attack in action. As the result of a devastating cyberattack involving the LockerGoga ransomware, Norsk Hydro, a multinational aluminum manufacturer with operations in 40 countries, closed many of its plants and was forced to move others offline. The attack compromised the firm’s IT systems across multiple business functions, including the company’s smelting plants in Norway, Qatar, and Brazil. The total cost is estimated at <strong>$75 million</strong>.</p>

<p>As exemplified by the Norsk Hydro case, cybersecurity experts assert that cyber criminals are using more ruthless methods to achieve their objectives and the proficiency of attacks is expected to advance as they continue to develop new methods for cyber attacks. For all industries with OT networks ransomware again led the charge for attack types, accounting for 36% of all attacks and echoing the overall attack trend across all industries. While the IT networks were compromised in the vast majority of these attacks, the impact carried over to victims’ operational technology in many of these instances.</p>

<p>Looking at the variety of attacks and the latest cyber criminal developments, the manufacturing industry remains a high-interest target for cybercriminals looking to deploy well-crafted attacks. Cyber attacks are relatively easy for criminals to conduct and are hard to protect against using traditional security technologies.</p>

<h2 id="how-can-an-ai-powered-solution-advance-your-edgeiot-cyber-security">How can an AI-powered solution advance your Edge/IoT cyber security?</h2>

<p>Cyber security is more important than ever before, as the attack surface area has increased due to the latest wave of digital transformation that is enhancing business agility and developing new customer experiences. When it comes to the security of Edge and IoT infrastructures, Artificial Intelligence (AI) and deep reinforcement learning are unmatched.</p>

<p>The <a href="https://edgelabs.ai/platform/">AI EdgeLabs platform</a> is embedded with a proprietary network telemetry and monitoring sensor that protects every layer of an Edge and IoT architecture. The AI-powered solution delivers smart means to detect anomalies that signal the presence of threats, threat intelligence software with powerful analytics tools for robust traffic inspection, and swift incident response and remediation.</p>

<p>During its deployment on-premises (on the factory side), the AI EdgeLabs Sensor runs a configurable set of security checks and topology research to collect the initial context of your environment. Data collected from the sensor is analyzed by the AI EdgeLabs platform that provides a set of AI-based models that are pre-trained on the existing knowledge base of threat patterns and attack signatures.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/blog/Manufacturing scheme.png" alt="AI EdgeLabs platform" style="max-width: 100%" /></p>

<p>Looking at the graph above, we can see the SCADA power system. The electrical distribution system consists of controllers, sensors, and operator-interface points.</p>

<p>For real-time monitoring and controlling of Programmable Logic Controllers (PLCs), the system uses circuit breakers and power monitors. Data is transmitted from PLCs and other devices to a computer-based SCADA node located on each sub-station.</p>

<p>One or more computers can be located on different points. The AI EdgeLabs Sensor can be implemented on each computer-based SCADA node to protect the whole system. This includes factory machines, HMIs, sensors, and end devices, protecting them from malfunctioning, data modifying, injection attacks such as SQL injection and other forms of advanced malware.</p>

<p>The EdgeLabs Sensor helps:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Generate near-realtime visibility of infrastructure and application performance;</li>
  <li>Prevent and block threat sources in real-time;</li>
  <li>Integrate cloud-based and on-premises application performance monitoring;</li>
  <li>Monitor SaaS applications from your users’ vantage point;</li>
  <li>Monitor IaaS resources from your users’ vantage point.</li>
</ul>

<p>The AI EdgeLabs platform equips your security teams with multi-layered threat intelligence software, advanced network visibility, and automated remediation to protect every asset, device, server, or network element of your manufacturing environment.</p>

<p>With AI EdgeLabs available in the <a href="https://sixsq.com/marketplace">Nuvla Marketplace</a>, companies now have an easier way to cyber protect their edge assets. Indeed all edge devices, servers and virtual machines running the NuvleEdge software can now be protected using the AI EdgeLabs software, providing a 1-click cyber protection to all sectors of the economy concerned by edge computing. Find out more <a href="https://sixsq.com/news/2022/06/13/news-aiedgelabs.html">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Inna Ushakova</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="edge" /><category term="cloud" /><category term="security" /><category term="cyber-security" /><category term="manufacturing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thanks to guest author Inna Ushakova for sharing her valuable insights into the state of cyber security in the manufacturing industry. Now more than ever, cybersecurity is extremely relevant for the manufacturing industry. IBM’s X-Force Threat Intelligence Index 2022 report found that manufacturing is the most attacked industry as of 2021, receiving the brunt of 23.2% of the attacks and reaching a global average of $4.24M in data breach costs. The manufacturing industry lacks cybersecurity maturity, a fact that criminals exploit relentlessly. This is evidenced by the high-stakes burdens placed on supply chains wreaking havoc on the manufacturing industry, which is still recovering from losses caused by the COVID-19 pandemic. Instrumental to the wellbeing and healthy performance of any manufacturing company, operational technology (OT) supports core-business operations and its safety is essential to ensure sustainable growth and effective means of innovation. For that to happen, cybersecurity needs to be a key, foundational element of any company’s core strategy. High, rigorous security standards and protocols in data, software, and infrastructure coupled with AI-powered solutions allows for process agility and transparency. Below, we detail one of the most high-profile cybersecurity attacks of recent years to illustrate how severe and crucial it is for manufacturing companies to take their security environment seriously. Manufacturing under threat The manufacturing industry is victim to ransomware, server access, BEC and data theft, distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attacks, credential harvesting, and more. Next, let’s see a high profile case of an attack in action. As the result of a devastating cyberattack involving the LockerGoga ransomware, Norsk Hydro, a multinational aluminum manufacturer with operations in 40 countries, closed many of its plants and was forced to move others offline. The attack compromised the firm’s IT systems across multiple business functions, including the company’s smelting plants in Norway, Qatar, and Brazil. The total cost is estimated at $75 million. As exemplified by the Norsk Hydro case, cybersecurity experts assert that cyber criminals are using more ruthless methods to achieve their objectives and the proficiency of attacks is expected to advance as they continue to develop new methods for cyber attacks. For all industries with OT networks ransomware again led the charge for attack types, accounting for 36% of all attacks and echoing the overall attack trend across all industries. While the IT networks were compromised in the vast majority of these attacks, the impact carried over to victims’ operational technology in many of these instances. Looking at the variety of attacks and the latest cyber criminal developments, the manufacturing industry remains a high-interest target for cybercriminals looking to deploy well-crafted attacks. Cyber attacks are relatively easy for criminals to conduct and are hard to protect against using traditional security technologies. How can an AI-powered solution advance your Edge/IoT cyber security? Cyber security is more important than ever before, as the attack surface area has increased due to the latest wave of digital transformation that is enhancing business agility and developing new customer experiences. When it comes to the security of Edge and IoT infrastructures, Artificial Intelligence (AI) and deep reinforcement learning are unmatched. The AI EdgeLabs platform is embedded with a proprietary network telemetry and monitoring sensor that protects every layer of an Edge and IoT architecture. The AI-powered solution delivers smart means to detect anomalies that signal the presence of threats, threat intelligence software with powerful analytics tools for robust traffic inspection, and swift incident response and remediation. During its deployment on-premises (on the factory side), the AI EdgeLabs Sensor runs a configurable set of security checks and topology research to collect the initial context of your environment. Data collected from the sensor is analyzed by the AI EdgeLabs platform that provides a set of AI-based models that are pre-trained on the existing knowledge base of threat patterns and attack signatures. Looking at the graph above, we can see the SCADA power system. The electrical distribution system consists of controllers, sensors, and operator-interface points. For real-time monitoring and controlling of Programmable Logic Controllers (PLCs), the system uses circuit breakers and power monitors. Data is transmitted from PLCs and other devices to a computer-based SCADA node located on each sub-station. One or more computers can be located on different points. The AI EdgeLabs Sensor can be implemented on each computer-based SCADA node to protect the whole system. This includes factory machines, HMIs, sensors, and end devices, protecting them from malfunctioning, data modifying, injection attacks such as SQL injection and other forms of advanced malware. The EdgeLabs Sensor helps: Generate near-realtime visibility of infrastructure and application performance; Prevent and block threat sources in real-time; Integrate cloud-based and on-premises application performance monitoring; Monitor SaaS applications from your users’ vantage point; Monitor IaaS resources from your users’ vantage point. The AI EdgeLabs platform equips your security teams with multi-layered threat intelligence software, advanced network visibility, and automated remediation to protect every asset, device, server, or network element of your manufacturing environment. With AI EdgeLabs available in the Nuvla Marketplace, companies now have an easier way to cyber protect their edge assets. Indeed all edge devices, servers and virtual machines running the NuvleEdge software can now be protected using the AI EdgeLabs software, providing a 1-click cyber protection to all sectors of the economy concerned by edge computing. Find out more here.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/cyber-secrurity-for-manufacturing.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/cyber-secrurity-for-manufacturing.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">SixSq joins 5G-EMERGE project</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/news/2022/07/05/news-5G-EMERGE.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SixSq joins 5G-EMERGE project" /><published>2022-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/news/2022/07/05/news-5G-EMERGE</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/news/2022/07/05/news-5G-EMERGE.html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Geneva, 5 July, 2022</strong> – SixSq, an <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/">Ekinops</a> company, is proud to announce its participation in the 5G-EMERGE project, which aims to develop solutions that leverage 5G technology and satellite broadcasting to put Europe at the vanguard of media delivery technology. The project is part of the <a href="https://www.esa.int/">European Space Agency</a> (ESA) programme of Advanced Research in Telecommunications Systems (<a href="https://www.esa.int/Applications/Telecommunications_Integrated_Applications/ARTES/About_ARTES">ARTES</a>) and will be led by the European Broadcasting Union (<a href="https://www.ebu.ch/home">EBU</a>).</p>

<p>The 5G-EMERGE project aims at developing an integrated satellite and terrestrial system based on open standards to enable high-quality content distribution services over multi-layer IP infra-structures. Telecommunications satellites will efficiently deliver high-demand content, including streaming of live events, as close as possible to the end user – to the ‘edge’. The project includes demonstrations in 5G base stations, users’ homes and vehicles.</p>

<p>A consortium of 20 companies from six European countries will collaborate on developing the distributed edge technology and service-delivery features.</p>

<p>SixSq’s contribution includes leading the demonstration work package and providing the edge-to-cloud software infrastructure based on its <a href="https://nuvla.io/">Nuvla</a> B2B SaaS platform and marketplace of containerised applications, as well as its open source NuvlaEdge software.</p>

<p>SixSq CEO <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mebster/">Marc-Elian Bégin</a> said, <em>“Leveraging satellite broadcast and 5G is a great opportunity to deliver the right high-density content at the right location with the right customization. However, this requires fine-tuned orchestration of the entire value chain and this is what SixSq edge-to-cloud software provides. We are no stranger to big challenges posed by ESA and EBU and are looking forward to pushing the boundaries of edge-to-cloud, bringing together the space sector, 5G and multi-media content delivery.”</em></p>

<p><em>“The 5G-Emerge project is yet another example of Ekinops’ long commitment towards software innovation as a mean to add value to the telecommunications sector”</em>, commented <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/muniere/">Vincent Munière</a>, Group Chief Technology Officer &amp; VP R&amp;D at Ekinops. <em>“We are looking forward to helping set the bar in 5G services and content delivery.”</em></p>

<p>For SixSq, this project is a unique opportunity to showcase its edge computing software’s ability to orchestrate complex scenarios for a range of new commercial use-cases, ranging from mari-time, vehicle, public transport, 5G and building applications.  Working with market leaders in their domain, Nuvla will manage apps across the edge-to-cloud continuum.</p>

<h3 id="5g-emerge-consortium">5G-EMERGE Consortium</h3>

<p>Arctic Space Technologies, Arthur D. Little, Athonet, Celestia Technologies Group, EBU, Fondazione LINKS, FTA Communication Technologies, G-Core Labs, MBI, Nagravision Sàrl, Nagravision AS, Rai, RomARS, SES Techcom, SixSq, Telenor ASA, Telenor Satellite, Telenor Maritime, TNO, Varnish Software, and ViaSat Antenna Systems.</p>

<h3 id="useful-links">Useful links</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.ebu.ch/home">EBU</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.esa.int/Applications/Telecommunications_Integrated_Applications/ARTES/About_ARTES">ARTES</a></p>

<h3 id="your-contacts">Your contacts</h3>

<p><strong>SixSq</strong></p>

<p>Louise Merifield
<br />
Operations Manager and Co-founder
<br />
+41 77 44 68 170
<br />
<a href="mailto:merifield@sixsq.com">merifield@sixsq.com</a></p>

<p><strong>Ekinops</strong>
<br />
Fraser Kay
<br />
iseepr
<br />
+44(0) 113 350 1922
<br />
<a href="mailto:fraser@iseepr.co.uk">fraser@iseepr.co.uk</a>
<br /></p>

<h3 id="about-ekinops">About Ekinops</h3>

<p>Ekinops is a leading provider of open, trusted and innovative network connectivity solutions to service providers around the world. Our programmable and highly scalable solutions enable the fast, flexible, and cost-effective deployment of new services for both high-speed, high-capacity optical transport as well as virtualization-enabled managed enterprise services. Our product portfolio consists of three highly complementary product and service sets: <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/products-services/products/ekinops360">EKINOPS360</a>, <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/products-services/products/oneaccess">OneAccess</a> and <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/products-services/products/compose">Compose</a>.</p>

<ul>
  <li>EKINOPS360 provides optical transport solutions for metro, regional and long-distance networks with WDM for high-capacity point-to-point, ring, and optical mesh architectures, and OTN for improved bandwidth utilization and efficient multi-service aggregation.</li>
  <li>OneAccess offers a wide choice of physical and virtualized deployment options for Layer 2 and Layer 3 access network functions.</li>
  <li>Compose supports service providers in making their networks software-defined with a variety of software management tools and services, including the scalable SD-WAN Xpress and SixSq Edge-to-Cloud solutions.</li>
</ul>

<p>As service providers embrace SDN and NFV deployment models, Ekinops enables future-proofed deployment today, enabling operators to seamlessly migrate to an open, virtualized delivery model at a time of their choosing. A global organization, Ekinops (EKI) - a public company traded on the Euronext Paris exchange operates on four continents.</p>

<p>Name : Ekinops
ISIN Code : FR0011466069
Mnemonic code : EKI
Number of shares : 26,162,922</p>

<p>For more information, visit: <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/">ekinops.com</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Geneva, 5 July, 2022 – SixSq, an Ekinops company, is proud to announce its participation in the 5G-EMERGE project, which aims to develop solutions that leverage 5G technology and satellite broadcasting to put Europe at the vanguard of media delivery technology. The project is part of the European Space Agency (ESA) programme of Advanced Research in Telecommunications Systems (ARTES) and will be led by the European Broadcasting Union (EBU). The 5G-EMERGE project aims at developing an integrated satellite and terrestrial system based on open standards to enable high-quality content distribution services over multi-layer IP infra-structures. Telecommunications satellites will efficiently deliver high-demand content, including streaming of live events, as close as possible to the end user – to the ‘edge’. The project includes demonstrations in 5G base stations, users’ homes and vehicles. A consortium of 20 companies from six European countries will collaborate on developing the distributed edge technology and service-delivery features. SixSq’s contribution includes leading the demonstration work package and providing the edge-to-cloud software infrastructure based on its Nuvla B2B SaaS platform and marketplace of containerised applications, as well as its open source NuvlaEdge software. SixSq CEO Marc-Elian Bégin said, “Leveraging satellite broadcast and 5G is a great opportunity to deliver the right high-density content at the right location with the right customization. However, this requires fine-tuned orchestration of the entire value chain and this is what SixSq edge-to-cloud software provides. We are no stranger to big challenges posed by ESA and EBU and are looking forward to pushing the boundaries of edge-to-cloud, bringing together the space sector, 5G and multi-media content delivery.” “The 5G-Emerge project is yet another example of Ekinops’ long commitment towards software innovation as a mean to add value to the telecommunications sector”, commented Vincent Munière, Group Chief Technology Officer &amp; VP R&amp;D at Ekinops. “We are looking forward to helping set the bar in 5G services and content delivery.” For SixSq, this project is a unique opportunity to showcase its edge computing software’s ability to orchestrate complex scenarios for a range of new commercial use-cases, ranging from mari-time, vehicle, public transport, 5G and building applications. Working with market leaders in their domain, Nuvla will manage apps across the edge-to-cloud continuum. 5G-EMERGE Consortium Arctic Space Technologies, Arthur D. Little, Athonet, Celestia Technologies Group, EBU, Fondazione LINKS, FTA Communication Technologies, G-Core Labs, MBI, Nagravision Sàrl, Nagravision AS, Rai, RomARS, SES Techcom, SixSq, Telenor ASA, Telenor Satellite, Telenor Maritime, TNO, Varnish Software, and ViaSat Antenna Systems. Useful links EBU ARTES Your contacts SixSq Louise Merifield Operations Manager and Co-founder +41 77 44 68 170 merifield@sixsq.com Ekinops Fraser Kay iseepr +44(0) 113 350 1922 fraser@iseepr.co.uk About Ekinops Ekinops is a leading provider of open, trusted and innovative network connectivity solutions to service providers around the world. Our programmable and highly scalable solutions enable the fast, flexible, and cost-effective deployment of new services for both high-speed, high-capacity optical transport as well as virtualization-enabled managed enterprise services. Our product portfolio consists of three highly complementary product and service sets: EKINOPS360, OneAccess and Compose. EKINOPS360 provides optical transport solutions for metro, regional and long-distance networks with WDM for high-capacity point-to-point, ring, and optical mesh architectures, and OTN for improved bandwidth utilization and efficient multi-service aggregation. OneAccess offers a wide choice of physical and virtualized deployment options for Layer 2 and Layer 3 access network functions. Compose supports service providers in making their networks software-defined with a variety of software management tools and services, including the scalable SD-WAN Xpress and SixSq Edge-to-Cloud solutions. As service providers embrace SDN and NFV deployment models, Ekinops enables future-proofed deployment today, enabling operators to seamlessly migrate to an open, virtualized delivery model at a time of their choosing. A global organization, Ekinops (EKI) - a public company traded on the Euronext Paris exchange operates on four continents. Name : Ekinops ISIN Code : FR0011466069 Mnemonic code : EKI Number of shares : 26,162,922 For more information, visit: ekinops.com.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/5GEmerge-vignette.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/5GEmerge-vignette.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">C2RO joins App Vendor Programme</title><link href="https://sixsq.com/news/2022/06/20/news-c2ro.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="C2RO joins App Vendor Programme" /><published>2022-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sixsq.com/news/2022/06/20/news-c2ro</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sixsq.com/news/2022/06/20/news-c2ro.html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>SixSq’s Nuvla ecosystem facilitates the deployment, management and update of C2RO’s ENTERA Video Analytics Agent</strong></p>

<p>SixSq, an <a href="https://www.ekinops.com/">Ekinops</a> Company, and <a href="https://www.c2ro.com/">C2RO™</a> today announced a partnership to deliver state-of-the-art GDPR-Compliant Video Analytics of large public venues via the <a href="/marketplace">Nuvla Marketplace</a>. This collaboration significantly simplifies the procurement, deployment, and management of C2RO™’s industry-leading <a href="https://www.c2ro.com/entera">ENTERA™</a> video analytics platform specifically designed for GDPR-compliant analysis of visitor traffic in public spaces.</p>

<p><em>“Nuvla allows us to streamline and automate the distribution of our ENTERA™ Edge AI components at scale. We see Nuvla as a strategic marketplace that facilitates broad access to our ENTERA™ AI-SaaS platform while simplifying the deployment and maintenance process for our customers and partners.”</em>  said <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/riccardo-badalone/">Riccardo Badalone</a>, Chief Executive Officer of C2RO™.</p>

<p>Airports, malls, and public venue operators require an understanding of how visitors flow through their physical spaces to best optimize services and maximize return on investment. The ENTERA™ Video Analytics Platform provides the means for enterprise customers to achieve this goal via a hyper-scalable AI-SaaS architecture with powerful and intuitive analysis tools, alerting and interactive dashboards.</p>

<p><em>“Helping domain matter experts like C2RO™ accelerate and streamline their go-to-market is at the heart of why we created the Nuvla Marketplace. The combination of C2RO’s cutting edge Intelligent Video Analytics Platform ENTERA™ and Nuvla means that sectors such as airports, malls and large public venues can deploy a simple, yet secure, powerful, and scalable, solution for people tracking challenges. And in the process, customers gain a future proof shared edge infrastructure that will deliver great ROI.”</em> said <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mebster/">Marc-Elian Bégin</a>, SixSq CEO and Co-founder.</p>

<p>With the ENTERA™ Advanced Video Analytics agent available in the Nuvla Marketplace, companies can now deploy, manage, and update their ENTERA™ agents remotely and securely. The purchasing and deployment process is fast, simple, and robust, with the app deployed at scale in a few clicks via the Nuvla dashboard.</p>

<p>The service is available via a pay-as-you-go subscription. You will find C2RO’s ENTERA™ Agent Application on the Nuvla Marketplace <a href="https://nuvla.io/ui/apps/c2ro">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[SixSq’s Nuvla ecosystem facilitates the deployment, management and update of C2RO’s ENTERA Video Analytics Agent SixSq, an Ekinops Company, and C2RO™ today announced a partnership to deliver state-of-the-art GDPR-Compliant Video Analytics of large public venues via the Nuvla Marketplace. This collaboration significantly simplifies the procurement, deployment, and management of C2RO™’s industry-leading ENTERA™ video analytics platform specifically designed for GDPR-compliant analysis of visitor traffic in public spaces. “Nuvla allows us to streamline and automate the distribution of our ENTERA™ Edge AI components at scale. We see Nuvla as a strategic marketplace that facilitates broad access to our ENTERA™ AI-SaaS platform while simplifying the deployment and maintenance process for our customers and partners.” said Riccardo Badalone, Chief Executive Officer of C2RO™. Airports, malls, and public venue operators require an understanding of how visitors flow through their physical spaces to best optimize services and maximize return on investment. The ENTERA™ Video Analytics Platform provides the means for enterprise customers to achieve this goal via a hyper-scalable AI-SaaS architecture with powerful and intuitive analysis tools, alerting and interactive dashboards. “Helping domain matter experts like C2RO™ accelerate and streamline their go-to-market is at the heart of why we created the Nuvla Marketplace. The combination of C2RO’s cutting edge Intelligent Video Analytics Platform ENTERA™ and Nuvla means that sectors such as airports, malls and large public venues can deploy a simple, yet secure, powerful, and scalable, solution for people tracking challenges. And in the process, customers gain a future proof shared edge infrastructure that will deliver great ROI.” said Marc-Elian Bégin, SixSq CEO and Co-founder. With the ENTERA™ Advanced Video Analytics agent available in the Nuvla Marketplace, companies can now deploy, manage, and update their ENTERA™ agents remotely and securely. The purchasing and deployment process is fast, simple, and robust, with the app deployed at scale in a few clicks via the Nuvla dashboard. The service is available via a pay-as-you-go subscription. You will find C2RO’s ENTERA™ Agent Application on the Nuvla Marketplace here.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://sixsq.com/app-vendor-c2ro.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://sixsq.com/app-vendor-c2ro.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>